<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: white peak software | thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/white-peak-software/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-16T23:29:49+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retiring My CSV Editor]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/18/retiring-my-csv-editor/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-18T15:23:09+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/18/retiring-my-csv-editor</id>
    <tag>white peak software</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Today I did something that I’ve been saying I will do for a long time. I retired my CSV editor, <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/">Killink</a>.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I did something that I’ve been saying I will do for a long time. I retired my CSV editor, <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/">Killink</a>.</p>

<p>The first release of Killink CSV Editor was back on March 22, 2007, and over the years it has done well despite the fact that I haven’t been actively working on the app or marketing it. Killink had great potential, especially if I had followed the business advice from those smarter than me to focus on the enterprise, but I honestly lost interest in the editor after I started writing apps for Mac and iOS.</p>

<p>I did start work on a Mac version of Killink CSV Editor, and I have still have a semi-working version of it on my iPhone. But I struggled to create the user experience that I wanted on those two platforms. Given enough time I could have conquered the UX challenges, but I knew the market for the editor was small and spending the extra time to do what I wanted didn’t make good business sense. So the Mac and iOS versions never shipped.</p>

<p>I always found the customers of Killink CSV Editor fascinating. While we developer types view CSV as antiquated technology, these customers work with CSV files regularly. And most are business users from large, well known companies. We developer types often times forget that people around the world are using old technologies like CSV daily to do their job, and they too would like a better way to work with old tech like CSV files. Killink CSV Editor was a better way for many for a number of years.</p>

<p>It saddens me to retire Killink CSV Editor, but at the same time I feel like a burden has been lifted off my shoulders. The app is rock solid and support is minimum, but I have felt guilty for a long time about selling a software product that I know isn’t actively being worked on. And with the recent Windows 10 release, I finally decided now is the time to retire my CSV editor.</p>

<p>I’ve heard many good things about Windows 10. But if I keep selling Killink to Windows users I will have no choice but to install it some day. And honestly, I don’t want to do that. I have zero interest in Windows these days.</p>

<p>I do plan to continuing supporting licensed users of Killink CSV Editor, which I talk about over at the <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/">company blog site</a>. The support load is minimum, so providing ongoing support isn’t a concern for me. Killink is a native Win32 app built using Delphi. It’s rock solid and hasn’t had a serious issue that I couldn’t resolve in email in years. So I’m happy to continue answering questions about Killink and helping folks if they happen to run into a problem. That said, I’m not looking forward to the emails I’m going to receive when people try to buy a new license.</p>

<p>When I retired SMTP Diagnostics, another Windows app I sold for years, I received emails for nearly a year asking why it was no longer available and why I couldn’t make an exception this one time and sell a new license. Most of the time the people understood, but a few sent angry emails. I fully expect the same will happen with the retirement of Killink, and all I can say to those folks is sorry.</p>

<p>Retiring my CSV editor ends another chapter in my long software career. I’m a bit sad by this, but I’m also excited by no longer having the mental burden that came with having my editor sit untouched for such a long time while people were still buying licenses for it.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maintain Your iOS App With Peak App Care]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/11/maintain-your-ios-app-with-peak-app-care/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-11T11:05:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/11/maintain-your-ios-app-with-peak-app-care</id>
    <tag>white peak software</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Last month I briefly mentioned <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/07/ive-been-doing-it-wrong/">my plan</a> to productize some of the services I offer through White Peak Software. The main idea is to take a consulting service that I already offer to my clients and turn it into a product that my clients and others will hopefully subscribe to thus creating a monthly recurring revenue stream for my company. My goal was to spend no more than 40 hours over the span of a few weeks setting up this new product. And now, after spending 38.75 hours over the last few weeks, I’m ready to share more details.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month I briefly mentioned <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/07/ive-been-doing-it-wrong/">my plan</a> to productize some of the services I offer through White Peak Software. The main idea is to take a consulting service that I already offer to my clients and turn it into a product that my clients and others will hopefully subscribe to thus creating a monthly recurring revenue stream for my company. My goal was to spend no more than 40 hours over the span of a few weeks setting up this new product. And now, after spending 38.75 hours over the last few weeks, I’m ready to share more details.</p>

<p>Today I’m happy to announce <a href="https://www.peakappcare.com">Peak App Care</a>. Peak App Care is a monthly subscription service for maintaining your iOS apps. What do I mean by that? Simply put, I monitor your app for crashes and fix them as quickly as possible. Not only that, I also perform small jobs such as bug fixes and enhancements to your app at your request, and I even manage the App Store for you, from updating screenshots to submitting new builds on your behalf.</p>

<p>What I have found is that many apps available today in the App Store are published by companies with zero iOS developers on staff. Those companies, instead, rely on freelancers and software shops to build their apps for them. The problem, however, is that often times there’s no plans to keep the app up to date after the initial release.</p>

<p>What happens when the app starts crashing or customers start reporting bugs? What happens when Apple releases a new version of iOS or a new device?</p>

<p>Often times these companies must scramble to find an iOS developer to help out. If they are lucky, the original developer is still available but chances are good the developer is currently working on something else and isn’t available for days, weeks, or even months.</p>

<p>With Peak App Care I become your in-house iOS developer responsible for the upkeep of your mobile app. I watch for crashes and fix them as they are reported. But I go beyond that. I will work with you to ensure your app remains up to date with the latest changes coming out of Cupertino. A good example of this is happening right now.</p>

<p>iOS 9 is in beta and every app publisher should be testing their app on this new iOS version. Not only that, the app should be updated to cleanly compile against the iOS 9 SDK. This means replacing deprecated code. But a company with no staffed iOS developer is often times unaware of the need to perform these types of tasks. Or they choose to ignore these tasks. After all, the app is running fine right now, so why wouldn’t it run fine when the new OS comes out.</p>

<p>Sometimes it’s okay to ignore changes coming from Apple, but sometimes the changes are too big to ignore. The iPhone 6 Plus is one example. Customers can quickly tell if an iPhone app doesn’t support the larger display found on the 6 Plus, and the only way to take full advantage of the larger display is to update the app.</p>

<p>This is one area where Peak App Care helps app publishers. Making changes to your app to support the latest iOS release or new device is covered with Peak App Care.</p>

<p>So that’s the new productize service I’m now offering. Check out the new <a href="https://www.peakappcare.com">web site</a>, and tell your friends, family members and anyone else who might be interested. Now let’s chat about how this concept came to be.</p>

<h2 id="giving-credit-where-credit-is-due">Giving Credit Where Credit is Due</h2>

<p>I wish I could take credit for coming up with a totally unique concept, but the truth is a maintenance plan for software isn’t anything new. And providing this type of service for mobile apps isn’t new either. In fact, I got the idea from Einar Vollset.</p>

<p>Einar talks about his app care service in <a href="http://www.freelancetransformation.com/blog/building-a-recurring-revenue-consulting-business-with-einar-vollset">this podcast interview</a> over at <a href="http://www.freelancetransformation.com">Freelance Transformations</a>. This interview blew me away. Here’s a person providing a service that is similar to what I provide, but he came up with a different way to market the service. Brilliant!</p>

<p>But Einar’s <a href="http://www.appaftercare.com">App Aftercare</a> isn’t unique either. There are many other examples of this in different spaces. <a href="http://wpcurve.com">WPCurve</a> provides a similar service for folks running a WordPress site. And I’ve heard of other examples too, companies that will help you maintain your Ruby on Rails app or your Django server. So the concept of app maintenance isn’t new, but I do give credit to Einar Vollset for inspiring me to create <a href="https://www.peakappcare.com">Peak App Care</a>.</p>

<h1 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h1>

<p>So what’s next now that the web site is up and running? Well, it’s time for me to roll up my sleeves and start the real work…marketing Peak App Care.</p>

<p>Like any product I need to market Peak App Care if it is to be a success. My first step is to let my existing clients know about this new offering, which I’ve already done. After that I need to start making others companies within my target audience aware of Peak App Care, and that is where things start to get tougher for me. Just posting a web site isn’t going to bring in customers. I must find ways to reach my target audience, and thankfully I have some ideas on how to make that happen.</p>

<p>As for my company reboot, I feel this is a good first step. I don’t know if Peak App Care will be a success or not. I’m hopeful it will be. But if I fail to bring on new subscribers over the next few months, at least I won’t feel like I have wasted a lot of my time or money. This is a big switch in thinking when I compare it to the months I’ve spent in the past working on other products that either failed or were never even released into the wild.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I've Been Doing It Wrong]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/07/ive-been-doing-it-wrong/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-07T11:22:54+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/07/ive-been-doing-it-wrong</id>
    <tag>white peak software</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A few years back I was making the majority of my income from the products I sold. My apps, my book, they were all doing well. But that changed in 2013. Things came crashing down, and I found myself wondering how I was going to pay the bills.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years back I was making the majority of my income from the products I sold. My apps, my book, they were all doing well. But that changed in 2013. Things came crashing down, and I found myself wondering how I was going to pay the bills.</p>

<p>Luckily I have a marketable skill, so I decided to focus on consulting. This was my attempt to reboot my company. The idea was to do consulting work to raise cash, then when I had enough cash I would take time off to work on my business, which in my case meant building another app or two and improving on the ones I already had.</p>

<p>Unfortunately my attempts to reboot didn’t work. Sure, I released two new apps, but once they were out the door my focus returned to billable work. I wasn’t growing and nurturing the products I had. And I wasn’t taking advantage of the momentum I had built up through the end of 2012. I stopped working on my business (again), and things only got worst.</p>

<p>Today I barely make any money off of the products I have. My average monthly product revenue is around $800 per month now, which is better than nothing but certainly not enough to live on. And my attempts to relieve personal stress on the consulting side of has put me into a situation where my hourly bill rate is much lower than it was a few years back.</p>

<p>To get back on track, I started listening to podcasts and reading articles and books about bootstrapping and being an entrepreneur.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup> From reading posts by <a href="https://unicornfree.com">Amy Hoy</a> to watching videos from the <a href="http://appreneursummit.com">Appreneur Summit</a>, I’ve been consuming as much information as possible to figure out 1) how I got myself into this situation, and 2) how I’m going to get myself out of this situation. I’ve even started attending a mastermind group, which gives me an opportunity to talk through issues with my business and bounce around new ideas. But even after doing all this, I wasn’t feeling any better about my situation. In fact, I’ve been toying with the idea of giving up and taking a job elsewhere. But that changed two weeks ago.</p>

<p>Two weeks ago I woke up early one morning and thought, “I’ve been doing it wrong, and I know what I need to do to correct it.” It was as if all the information I consumed about making products and being an entrepreneur had finally mashed together in a way that made sense to my brain and the light bulb finally turned on.</p>

<p>My cycle of doing full-time consulting work followed by taking time off to work on an app or other product doesn’t work for me. That is now so obvious to me. But how do I get out of this cycle and start building up the momentum on the product side again.</p>

<p>The answer was right in front of my face. It’s a common theme in everything I was reading and listening to. And Justin Jackson says it best in his <a href="http://buildandlaunch.net">Build and Launch podcast</a>, “Start small, start now.”</p>

<p>I was using consulting work to save cash so I can take months off at a time to focus on building something. But what I built doesn’t make money. It’s not that the apps I’ve published suck. It’s that once they hit the App Store, my focus returns to consulting work. I’m not sticking with what I started. I’m not marketing the products I have. I’m not doing what I need to do to let more people know about them.</p>

<p>But at the same time I have a wife and a kid that I must provide for and rent and bills to pay. This is why I keep returning to consulting work.</p>

<p>So how do I break this cycle. It’s simple. I need to start small.</p>

<p>Instead of taking two to three months off to write a new app, I need to start creating small, even tiny, products that only take a short amount of time. Once the momentum is going and I have cash coming in from product sales, I can cut back on the consulting.</p>

<p>But what products can I create now, in a short amount of time, that will get the ball rolling. Here’s what I’m currently thinking:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Productize part of the services I offer.</strong> I’ll share more details on this soon, but in general the goal is to take a consulting service I already offer to my clients and turn it into a product that my clients, and hopefully others, will subscribe to. Now this might seem like a huge gamble. I mean after all, generating monthly recurring income is a tough nut to crack. But it’s a small gamble for me in that I will not spend more than 40 hours over the span of a few of weeks getting this setup. If no one subscribes, I’ve only lost a week’s worth of my time. But if just one company signs up, I’m that much closer to getting back on track.</li>
  <li><strong>Start publishing ebooks.</strong> While I don’t love writing I do enjoy it a lot, and frankly, I miss it. But writing a big book like <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">Learning iPad Programming</a> took too much out of me, so this time I want to do it differently. I want to keep it small. Again, I’ll share details later but the plan is to create highly focused, short ebooks on specific topics.</li>
  <li><strong>Video tutorials.</strong> This is something I’ve explored in the past, and it’s something I want to explore again. But this time I want to do it under my control.</li>
</ol>

<p>I don’t suspect any one of these ideas to make a ton of money, but that’s not the goal. The goal is to start small and start now so I can build momentum. And if any one of the products fail, then I’ve only lost, at most, a few weeks of my time. Besides, pursuing these small product ideas will not be a failure anyways even if they don’t earn a single cent. That’s because I will be learning a lot more about marketing and building a personal brand. And once the momentum does grows I can turn my attention back to my apps with new found knowledge on how to market and grow those apps.</p>

<p>Wish me luck, and stay tuned to see if I succeed or fail in the coming month.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I’m not a fan of calling myself an entrepreneur because I don’t think of myself as one entrepreneur. But I am a business owner, and I have been for nearly 12 years, so I guess that makes me an entrepreneur.&nbsp;<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross Posting to App.net, Facebook, and Twitter]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/14/cross-posting-to-app.net-facebook-and-twitter/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/14/cross-posting-to-app.net-facebook-and-twitter</id>
    <tag>white peak software</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Last year my wife told me more family and friends would “like” my photos on Facebook if I posted the them directly to Facebook. At the time I was using <a href="https://ifttt.com">ifttt</a> to selectively cross post to App.net and Facebook. This meant my photos on Facebook were actually links to the App.net, which is where the photos were being stored, and this required my Facebook followers to tap the link to see the photos. Not the best experience for my followers.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year my wife told me more family and friends would “like” my photos on Facebook if I posted the them directly to Facebook. At the time I was using <a href="https://ifttt.com">ifttt</a> to selectively cross post to App.net and Facebook. This meant my photos on Facebook were actually links to the App.net, which is where the photos were being stored, and this required my Facebook followers to tap the link to see the photos. Not the best experience for my followers.</p>

<p>I decided to test my wife’s theory by posting photos directly to Facebook. Turns out she was right. I started getting more likes. Not only that, I found that family and friends posted more comments when I posted the photos directly. My wife was right. Posting photos directly to the social site is the best experience for followers and the best to become more engaged with your followers.</p>

<p>Now I could have setup an ifttt recipe that cross posted my Facebook photos to App.net, but that means my followers on App.net would have the less than ideal experience reading my posts and viewing my photos. So I started down the path of exploring different options for cross posting between different social networks.</p>

<p>After exploring options for nearly six months, I learned there is no single solution that will cross post to different social networks while giving the followers on each network the best viewing experience. So I set out to write my own app.</p>

<p>I quickly learned why no cross post solution that posts natively to each social network existed. It’s hard, and in the case of Facebook, nearly impossible to make the post look as if it were posted from the official app. But I figured it out and for the past few months I have been making posts using Cross Post.</p>

<p>Cross Post is the app I’ve been working on for the last few months. I’ve also been using it almost daily for months. The app was ready for public release back in August, but I decided to wait until the iOS 8 release. The primary reason for this is to avoid annoying iPhone 4 users. iPhone 4 cannot run iOS 8, and I had planned to drop support for iOS 7 the moment iOS 8 is released. So I decided to delay the release of Cross Post.</p>

<p>The delayed release gave me time to work on adding some new iOS 8 only features. One feature in particular that I’m very excited about is the share extension. This feature makes it possible for a person to cross post to different social networks from other apps running on their iPhone or iPad. This feature alone makes Cross Post much more useful than I ever imagined 6 months ago.</p>

<p>When I started learning the ins and outs of share extensions I thought to myself, “This will be a snap.” But as I got deeper into the code I realized Cross Post has one major issue that makes the Cross Post share extension suck. It takes Cross Post too damn long to post photos to multiple social sites.</p>

<p>Consider the scenario where you want to post 4 photos to App.net, Facebook, and Twitter. Each photo must be uploaded to each network. That means 12 different uploads, which is not speedy. This performance problem is acceptable in the Cross Post app because it performs the uploads even when the app is no longer active. A share extension, on the other hand, should return almost immediately. It should not, or have to, wait for the uploads to complete.</p>

<p>Extensions that need to upload data should do so using a background <code class="highlighter-rouge">NSURLSession</code>. Unfortunately this is not an option for Cross Post because it uses the Facebook SDK to post to Facebook and <code class="highlighter-rouge">SLRequest</code> to post to Twitter. Cross Post does use <code class="highlighter-rouge">NSURLSession</code> to post to App.net, but I want to be able to post to Facebook and Twitter via the share extension as well. So I needed to come up with a better way to post status updates and photos across different social networks.</p>

<p>To solve this problem I decided to create a Cross Post server. I was trying to avoid having a server for Cross Post, but it’s unavoidable if I want to provide the best user experience. With the server in place Cross Post can upload the post and photos once and let the server handle uploading the content to the selected networks. Best of all, the upload from the app can be accomplished using a single <code class="highlighter-rouge">NSURLSession</code> request, and it can be performed in a background session. This means the Cross Post share extension can return almost immediately. It also means that Cross Post now only needs to make one HTTP request whereas previously it had to make numerous requests. For instance, the previous scenario of posting 4 photos to 3 different social sites required 15 HTTP requests. Now Cross Post app accomplishes the same thing using a single HTTP request<sup id="fnref:onerequest"><a href="#fn:onerequest" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, and the Cross Post server handles making all the other requests on behalf of the app.</p>

<p>This performance boost does have some disadvantages. First and foremost, I’m now responsible for keeping the server environment up and running. But thanks to <a href="https://www.openshift.com">OpenShift</a>, I’m not too worried about that.</p>

<p>Another disadvantage is that reporting errors back to the iOS app is going to be more challenging. Cross Post and the share extension sends off the request to the server. Once the server receives the payload the HTTP connection ends. The server, however, continues working by posting the payload to the selected social sites. If there is an error posting to, say, Twitter, there is no way for the server to tell the Cross Post app because that connection no longer exist. I have some ideas on how to solve this problem, but it’s not going to happen in the first release.</p>

<p>Still, the improved user experience outweighs the disadvantages of using a server. And I have to admit, I’m enjoying getting back into server-side programming. So much as changed, for the better, over the years.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:onerequest">
      <p>I was able to reducing the number of calls to the server down to one by packaging the post and photos into a single .zip file, which is sent to the server.&nbsp;<a href="#fnref:onerequest" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Send Camera Video to Your TV]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/20/send-your-camera-video-to-your-tv/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/20/send-your-camera-video-to-your-tv</id>
    <tag>white peak software</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Believe it or not, I finally released a new app for iOS. It’s my first new app for <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">White Peak Software</a> in more than 2 years. Somewhere along the way over the last two years I lost my way, but I’m back.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Believe it or not, I finally released a new app for iOS. It’s my first new app for <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">White Peak Software</a> in more than 2 years. Somewhere along the way over the last two years I lost my way, but I’m back.</p>

<p>So what’s this new app? It’s <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/big-screen">Big Screen</a>.</p>

<p>Big Screen lets you view the video from your iPhone or iPad’s camera on your TV. It requires an AppleTV, or other AirPlay receiver. Sure, you can use the built-in iOS 7 camera app to do the same, but you will see the app’s chrome on the TV. With Big Screen, there is no chrome or any other evidence that the app is being used. This makes Big Screen ideal for presentation, conferences, and other events where large screen TVs are used to let viewers in the room see the action on the stage.</p>

<p>I got the idea to write an <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/main/big-screen/why">app to display the camera’s video on a TV</a> while attending an event at Rowan’s elementary school. It just goes to show you never know when a new app idea will pop up.</p>

<p>Big Screen is a free app available now in the iOS App Store. <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/main/store/buy/big-screen">Grab a copy</a>, and let me know what you think.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>