<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-14T15:04:10-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright (c) 2002-2015 Kirby Turner</rights>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redirect Jekyll Site To HTTPS On Openshift]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/14/redirect-jekyll-site-to-https-on-openshift/"/>
    <published>2015-07-14T14:17:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-14T14:17:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/14/redirect-jekyll-site-to-https-on-openshift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m preparing to roll out a new <a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> website, but unlike with my other Jekyll sites, I want each web page served up on <code>https</code>, not <code>http</code>. This means telling the server to redirect <code>http</code> request to <code>https</code>. </p>

<p>Hosting this new site on <a href="https://pages.github.com">Github Pages</a> isn’t option because Github Pages doesn’t support using a custom SSL certificate for your custom domain name. So I decided to see what it would take to host a Jekyll site on <a href="https://www.openshift.com">OpenShift</a>. </p>

<p>I was thrilled to learn that OpenShift has a <a href="https://hub.openshift.com/quickstarts/41-jekyll">quick start cartridge for installing Jekyll</a> on a new gear. With a click of a button I was able to deploy my new server instance with a boiler plate Jekyll site. I replaced the boiler plate site with the one I’ve been working on, and BAM! My site was up and running. The only step remaining was to force the web server to serve up the pages using <code>https</code>.</p>

<p>Turns out this is simple to do with OpenShift and Jekyll. First, I went over to namecheap.com and purchased a <a href="https://www.namecheap.com/security/ssl-certificates/rapidssl/rapidssl.aspx">RapidSSL certificate</a> with domain validation. Next, I followed the instructions from OpenShift to <a href="https://developers.openshift.com/en/managing-domains-ssl.html#_generating_a_csr_certificate_signing_request">generate my certificate signing request</a>. Using my newly generated CSR I activated my RapidSSL certificate over at namecheap, then I followed the instructions on OpenShift to <a href="https://developers.openshift.com/en/managing-domains-ssl.html#using-a-custom-ssl-certificate">add the certificate to my server instance</a>.</p>

<p>Up to this point everything was easy peasy, and all I had left to do was figure out how to redirect the Jekyll site from <code>http</code> to <code>https</code>. Turns out this isn’t difficult either.</p>

<p>The Jekyll website is actually just a static website hosted by Apache 2 running on an OpenShift gear. To force the redirect all I needed to do was add a <em>.htaccess</em> file to the root of my Jekyll site source code (note: the site source code is in the <em>source/</em> directory when using OpenShift) and put this rewrite rule in the file:</p>

<p><code>
RewriteEngine on 
RewriteCond %{HTTP:X-Forwarded-Proto} !https 
RewriteRule .* https://%{HTTP_HOST}%{REQUEST_URI} [R,L]
</code></p>

<p>After I added the <em>.htaccess</em> file with the rewrite rule, I pushed my changes to the remote git repository running on my OpenShift gear. This launched Jekyll which re-built my static website, this time with each web page being served with <code>https</code> instead of <code>http</code>.</p>

<p>Including the <em>.htaccess</em> file works great when deploying the Jekyll site to OpenShift, but approach isn’t unique to OpenShift. This should work for most Jekyll site hosted with Apache 2. And if for some reason Jekyll isn’t including the <em>.htaccess</em> file when it builds the site, add <code>include: [".htaccess"]</code> to your <em>_config.yaml</em> file.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I've Been Doing It Wrong]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/07/ive-been-doing-it-wrong/"/>
    <published>2015-07-07T07:22:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-07T07:22:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/07/ive-been-doing-it-wrong</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years back I was making the majority of my income from the products I sold. My apps, my book, they were all doing well. But that changed in 2013. Things came crashing down, and I found myself wondering how I was going to pay the bills. </p>

<p>Luckily I have a marketable skill, so I decided to focus on consulting. This was my attempt to reboot my company. The idea was to do consulting work to raise cash, then when I had enough cash I would take time off to work on my business, which in my case meant building another app or two and improving on the ones I already had.</p>

<p>Unfortunately my attempts to reboot didn’t work. Sure, I released two new apps, but once they were out the door my focus returned to billable work. I wasn’t growing and nurturing the products I had. And I wasn’t taking advantage of the momentum I had built up through the end of 2012. I stopped working on my business (again), and things only got worst.</p>

<p>Today I barely make any money off of the products I have. My average monthly product revenue is around $800 per month now, which is better than nothing but certainly not enough to live on. And my attempts to relieve personal stress on the consulting side of has put me into a situation where my hourly bill rate is much lower than it was a few years back.</p>

<p>To get back on track, I started listening to podcasts and reading articles and books about bootstrapping and being an entrepreneur.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup> From reading posts by <a href="https://unicornfree.com">Amy Hoy</a> to watching videos from the <a href="http://appreneursummit.com">Appreneur Summit</a>, I’ve been consuming as much information as possible to figure out 1) how I got myself into this situation, and 2) how I’m going to get myself out of this situation. I’ve even started attending a mastermind group, which gives me an opportunity to talk through issues with my business and bounce around new ideas. But even after doing all this, I wasn’t feeling any better about my situation. In fact, I’ve been toying with the idea of giving up and taking a job elsewhere. But that changed two weeks ago.</p>

<p>Two weeks ago I woke up early one morning and thought, “I’ve been doing it wrong, and I know what I need to do to correct it.” It was as if all the information I consumed about making products and being an entrepreneur had finally mashed together in a way that made sense to my brain and the light bulb finally turned on.</p>

<p>My cycle of doing full-time consulting work followed by taking time off to work on an app or other product doesn’t work for me. That is now so obvious to me. But how do I get out of this cycle and start building up the momentum on the product side again. </p>

<p>The answer was right in front of my face. It’s a common theme in everything I was reading and listening to. And Justin Jackson says it best in his <a href="http://buildandlaunch.net">Build and Launch podcast</a>, “Start small, start now.” </p>

<p>I was using consulting work to save cash so I can take months off at a time to focus on building something. But what I built doesn’t make money. It’s not that the apps I’ve published suck. It’s that once they hit the App Store, my focus returns to consulting work. I’m not sticking with what I started. I’m not marketing the products I have. I’m not doing what I need to do to let more people know about them. </p>

<p>But at the same time I have a wife and a kid that I must provide for and rent and bills to pay. This is why I keep returning to consulting work.</p>

<p>So how do I break this cycle. It’s simple. I need to start small. </p>

<p>Instead of taking two to three months off to write a new app, I need to start creating small, even tiny, products that only take a short amount of time. Once the momentum is going and I have cash coming in from product sales, I can cut back on the consulting. </p>

<p>But what products can I create now, in a short amount of time, that will get the ball rolling. Here’s what I’m currently thinking:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Productize part of the services I offer.</strong> I’ll share more details on this soon, but in general the goal is to take a consulting service I already offer to my clients and turn it into a product that my clients, and hopefully others, will subscribe to. Now this might seem like a huge gamble. I mean after all, generating monthly recurring income is a tough nut to crack. But it’s a small gamble for me in that I will not spend more than 40 hours over the span of a few of weeks getting this setup. If no one subscribes, I’ve only lost a week’s worth of my time. But if just one company signs up, I’m that much closer to getting back on track.</li>
  <li><strong>Start publishing ebooks.</strong> While I don’t love writing I do enjoy it a lot, and frankly, I miss it. But writing a big book like <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">Learning iPad Programming</a> took too much out of me, so this time I want to do it differently. I want to keep it small. Again, I’ll share details later but the plan is to create highly focused, short ebooks on specific topics. </li>
  <li><strong>Video tutorials.</strong> This is something I’ve explored in the past, and it’s something I want to explore again. But this time I want to do it under my control.</li>
</ol>

<p>I don’t suspect any one of these ideas to make a ton of money, but that’s not the goal. The goal is to start small and start now so I can build momentum. And if any one of the products fail, then I’ve only lost, at most, a few weeks of my time. Besides, pursuing these small product ideas will not be a failure anyways even if they don’t earn a single cent. That’s because I will be learning a lot more about marketing and building a personal brand. And once the momentum does grows I can turn my attention back to my apps with new found knowledge on how to market and grow those apps.</p>

<p>Wish me luck, and stay tuned to see if I succeed or fail in the coming month.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I’m not a fan of calling myself an entrepreneur because I don’t think of myself as one entrepreneur. But I am a business owner, and I have been for nearly 12 years, so I guess that makes me an entrepreneur. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fear]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/02/fear/"/>
    <published>2015-07-02T06:48:32-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-02T06:48:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/02/fear</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I’ve been struggling to release new things out to the public, things such as blog posts, open source code, a new website and service I want to offer, even updates to some of my apps. What’s worse is that a number of these things are done and are just sitting on my computer. For instance, I’ve been using an updated version of Cross Post for nearly two months that isn’t available in the App Store. </p>

<p>So why haven’t I pulled the trigger on these things and released them to the public? Fear, that’s my answer. </p>

<p>I’m letting fear get the best me recently. I fear what people might say or think of the work I’m going. I fear that friends will start looking down on me. I fear that I will end up looking like an idiot. The funny part is I don’t have a fear of failing. You learn from failure. But for some odd reason I have developed a fear what others, especially friends, will think. </p>

<h2 id="out-of-character">Out of Character</h2>

<p>This fear of what others will think is completely out of character for me. For most of my life I’ve had a “I don’t give a fuck what other think” attitude (and that’s exactly how I’ve always put it). I was the high school weirdo with dyed hair and strange clothes. I was the nonconformist who would occasionally wear a polo shirt just to throw off my small circle of friends. In college I had a my racquetball racquet strung with bright hot pink strings, which led to some heated confrontations with others<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>. The point here is I didn’t care what others thought.</p>

<p>I remember an evening years ago when my dad refused to go out to dinner with me because of the way I was dressed. He said I embarrassed him. I argued that he was being ridiculous because 1) it wasn’t him that was dressed up like a Boy George reject and if anyone should be embarrassed it should be me (though I wasn’t), and 2) if I don’t care what people think about me, then why should he care. If anything people will feel sorry for him for having to sit with me at a restaurant. My argument didn’t change his mind and our dinner plans were canceled.</p>

<p>So if this fear is out of character for me, then where is it coming from?</p>

<h2 id="where-is-it-coming-from">Where Is It Coming From</h2>

<p>I know my fear is irrational when I think about it. But it’s still there and I can’t seem to shake it. Recently I’ve been putting a lot of thought into where this fear is coming from, and I think I might know. </p>

<p>I’ve been much more isolated since moving to Vermont. I don’t have the social circle of independent software developers and business owners around me like I did when I lived in New York City and the Boston area. Most of my social interactions these days involved talking about snowboarding and hiking, not on product releases, marketing, and growing a business. </p>

<p>Before moving to Vermont I attended a number of social gatherings where I could talk about and share my ideas. These groups were great and always provided excellent feedback. I always listened to what others had to say, but I didn’t always follow their advice. For example, I released a CSV editor for Windows years ago and made a good money from it for a number of years even though all my software dev friends said not to do it. Still, talking about the ideas with other on a regular bases always felt good, but I no longer have a local circle of friends and peers like I did before. And I think that is why I’ve developed this fear inside me.</p>

<p>Even though I didn’t care, for most of my life, what others thoughts, hearing what others had to say, both good or bad, always helped me. But in my recent isolation I rarely, if ever, get feedback from others. Hearing “you suck” motivated me to do better. Hearing “that’s awesome” in encouraged me to do more. But hearing nothing, no feedback at all, for long periods of time has caused this fear to grow inside of me. </p>

<h2 id="get-over-the-fear">Get Over The Fear</h2>

<p>I know my fears are irrational, but I can’t seem to shake them. So I’m trying a few new things in my attempts to get over the fear. </p>

<p>I’m trying to build a small community here in Stowe (though I think about giving up each month). A few folks do join me each month, but the group is not the same as the ones I participated in before coming to Vermont. Like the gatherings I attended before, this new group is made up of mostly software developers. But what is missing for me are the independents, the business owners, the solopreneur that were common in the circles I had when I lived in NYC and Boston.</p>

<p>I’m also participating in a bi-weekly mastermind group. This is going well, and in fact, it was on a recent mastermind call that I realized I’ve developed this irrational fear. My fear came up again last night in an email exchange with a friend who is doing a far better job of shipping than me. Talking about my fear with others as well as what I’m working on and my goals is starting to help me return to my old self, but I need to do more.</p>

<p>Another thing I’m interested in trying but I haven’t started yet is working with an accountability partner. The concept is simple. You and your partner help each other keep weekly commitments. Once a week you and your partner chat about the previous week’s accomplishments and the current week’s goals. When goals are not met, you analyze and talk through what happened. Having someone hold me accountable each week will help get me back into the habit of releasing things, which in turn will help me get over my fears.</p>

<p>One other thing I am doing in my attempts to shake the fear is to leave my quiet “cave” here in Stowe and get back into interacting in person with peers. To get things started, I agreed last week to speak at a small conference in October (more on this later). Just knowing I have this speaking event coming up should help reset my brain back to where it once was, or so I hope.</p>

<p>Are you having or had the similar fears? What sort of things are your doing to get over it? Fire off an email to me or send me a tweet and let me know.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>To this day I still don’t understand why people get so worked up over something so silly such as the string color of a racquetball racquet or the appearance of others. Just because it’s not something you would do, wear, or whatever doesn’t mean you need to hate on the other person. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips To Being More Focused]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/22/tips-to-being-more-focused/"/>
    <published>2015-06-22T11:51:20-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-22T11:51:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/22/tips-to-being-more-focused</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I tweeted the other day that “I have the problem of wanting to do too many things at once, which is distracting. It’s time for me to learn how to scale back and focus.”</p>

<p><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/420/18776596119_d03e98a590_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>It’s true. Right now there are a number of things I’m working on and there are even more things that I want to work on. </p>

<p>Lately I’ve been bouncing back and forth between a number of projects, but I haven’t been very productive. I start work on a task but before I finish I let myself get distracted with another task. For instance, I’ll work on a client project and before I finish the task at hand I’ll jump to another task from another project. </p>

<p>I haven’t always worked this way, and I’m not sure why I now struggle to stay focused. It could be the changing of seasons. I had my daily routine dialed in during the winter months, but something has changed recently and it’s not just the seasons. </p>

<p>Maybe my struggle with focus is a sign of being burnt out, maybe it’s the type of projects I’m working on - I’m certainly less excited about certain projects while much more excited about others. Maybe it’s because the kid is out of school and my work day is broken up into smaller chunks than during school time. Or maybe it’s a combination of all of the above. All I know for sure is that I find it difficult to focus, so last week I set out to find new ways to get focused and stay focused<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>. And here’s what I came up with…</p>

<h2 id="dont-check-email-first-thing-in-the-morning">Don’t Check Email First Thing In The Morning</h2>

<p>I have stopped checking email first thing in the morning. This is probably one of the hardest habit for me to break, but I’ve come to realize that checking email first thing in the morning leads to the biggest distractions for me. So it is a must change habit for me. </p>

<p>On a typical day I start the morning excited about what I’m planning to do during the day only to have that excitement squashed because of emails. The emails will often times change my plans for the day. Emails, in other words, control my day when I should be controlling my day.</p>

<p>Instead of checking email at the start of the day I now check it later in the morning, usually just before I break for lunch. This gives me a chance to really focus on the work at hand and not let my day get off on the wrong foot.</p>

<p>I admit this hasn’t been the easiest change for me to make. I’ve become accustom to checking my email as soon as I wake up…often times while still in bed. But I recognize that checking email first thing each morning typically controls the rest of my day. It causes me to change the priorities I set the evening before, which in turn makes me feel like I didn’t spend nearly as much time on the most important tasks for the week. That’s why I’ve stopped checking email first thing each day and I have replaced that habit with the next tip.</p>

<h2 id="do-whats-most-important-first">Do What’s Most Important First</h2>

<p>Instead of checking email at the start of my day, I begin my work day by working on the task that is most important for the day. It could be bug fixes for a client’s app, work on a new landing page, writing a blog post, or adding a new feature to one of my apps. I decide the night before what is the most important thing to do and that’s the first task I work on the next morning.</p>

<p>I’ve been following this tip for only a few days, and so far I feel more productive. Plus I feel a greater sense of accomplishment at the end of the day because that task that was most important got the love it deserved.</p>

<p>I highly recommend get into the habit of starting your day by doing the most important task first. If you are writing a book, start your day by writing. If you are working on a client project, and have a upcoming deadline, start your day by working on the project. And remember to work on this important task before you check your email.</p>

<p>Those are the biggest changes I’ve made to my daily routine, and I’m seeing immediate results. But I decided to try a couple of more things to see if I can make more improvements to my focus and productivity.</p>

<h2 id="limit-meetings-to-tuesday-and-thursday">Limit Meetings to Tuesday and Thursday</h2>

<p>My next tip is to limit meetings with others to two specific days each week. For me those two days are Tuesday and Thursday. </p>

<p>The main benefit to doing this is to give me more control over the other days of the week. I can use those other days to focus on productive work without the disruption of meetings. Meetings are, after all, disruptive to a productive day. Nothing kills my productivity faster than having to stop what I’m working on to waste time in a meeting. And yes, most meetings are a waste of time. Even the ones that are not a complete waste of time do waste some time. That casual chit chat at the beginning of the meeting, for example, is unproductive time. So I’m limiting those periods of unproductive time to two days a week.</p>

<p>I get that this isn’t something everyone can do. Heck I’m not 100% sure I can make it happen for me. But if you work for yourself and/or have control over your schedule, then you should be able to make this happen. </p>

<p>Also if you are like me, you already have meetings on your calendar. I, for example, have a recurring client meeting every Monday and Thursday mornings, another client meeting on Monday afternoon, one on Wednesday morning, and just recently a client asked to do a daily stand-up meeting each morning<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote">2</a></sup>. This means there will be a transition period for me as I get my meetings re-scheduled for Tuesday and Thursday. But this is something I’m going to make happen come hell or high water.</p>

<h2 id="pomodoro-technique">Pomodoro Technique</h2>

<p>As if not checking email first thing each morning isn’t already a big change to my daily routine, I’ve decided to give the <a href="http://pomodorotechnique.com">Pomodoro Technique</a> a try.</p>

<p>The Pomodoro Technique is simple. You set a timer for 25 minutes and during that time you focus on a particular task. When the 25 minutes are up, you take a 5 minute break. Then you start another pomodoro, setting the timer for 25 minutes; focus, focus, focus; then take another 5 minute break. After four pomodoros you take a longer break (15 to 30 minutes).</p>

<p>I’ve heard about the Pomodoro Technique a number of times over the years. I felt the process was not for me, but since focus has become a recent problem for me I decided to give it a try. So far the small blocks of 25-minute work cycles is working well for me given the amount of distractions that can happen throughout the day especially when my wife and kid are home. With the Pomodoro Technique I focus for 25 minutes, then I can use the 5 minute break answer a question my wife might have or see the latest LEGO creation my son has built.</p>

<p>Time will tell if this technique will work for me long term. And I should mention I’m not following the Pomodoro Technique by the book either. There are times when I reach the end of my 25 minute work cycle and I don’t want to stop. So I don’t. I skip my 5 minute break, and I continue working using a new pomodoro. But I do force myself to take a break after the second pomodoro when I combine two of them.</p>

<h2 id="do-these-tips-really-work">Do These Tips Really Work</h2>

<p>So do these tips really work? It’s hard for me to say with absolutely certainty that they work. I’m seeing some positive results already, but only time will tell what works and doesn’t work for me long term. And obviously not every tip will work for every person. Heck, I’m not sure if all the tips will work for me. But these are the tips I’m trying right now, and after only a few days I’m seeing good results. </p>

<p>I’m getting more done faster, and that feeling of being overwhelmed that I got at the end of each day has been replaced with a greater sense of accomplishment and a feeling of being more productive. But the real test for me will be following these tips for a month and see what happens. Trying these tips for a month is the only way I will know what works and doesn’t work for me.</p>

<p>I’ll post an update on my progress in a few weeks. Meanwhile I encourage you to give one, some or all the tips a try to see what works for you. And let me know how it works out for you. </p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Yes, I see the irony in that my search for ways to become more focused distracted me from the work that I needed to do last week. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>I personally think daily stand up meetings, like most meetings, are a waste of time, and it’s certainly not a productive use of my time. A daily status email is far more productive in my opinion, and you have the report captured for historical purposes.  <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video of Stowe, Vermont]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/video-of-stowe-vermont/"/>
    <published>2015-06-18T22:22:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-18T22:22:58-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/video-of-stowe-vermont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Ashley came across another video of Vermont. This time it’s about Stowe, the town I live in. Enjoy.</p>

<div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9_Wk5j_4Uc4?color=white&amp;theme=light"></iframe></figure></div>

<p>The video is from <a href="http://www.vtscapes.com">VermontScapes</a>. Go checkout the site if you want to see more beautiful photos of Vermont and the Stowe area.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Essence Of Vermont]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/essence-of-vermont/"/>
    <published>2015-06-18T06:16:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-18T06:16:26-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/essence-of-vermont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s no surprise I love living in Vermont in part because it’s different from other places I have lived. And this video from Skyworks really captures parts of why I love it here.</p>

<div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UBwqn9BRWhA?color=white&amp;theme=light"></iframe></figure></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do I Need Another Twitter Account]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account/"/>
    <published>2015-06-14T23:09:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-14T23:09:24-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier tonight I setup a new Twitter account that tweets a link each time I publish a new post here at thecave.com. The new Twitter account is <a href="https://twitter.com/thecave_com/">@thecave_com</a>. Of course now that this is setup, I’m wondering…Do I really need a separate Twitter account, or should I just tweet the links from my <a href="https://twitter.com/kiryt/">@kirbyt</a> account?</p>

<p>I guess I will keep the two separate accounts, and I’ll retweet via @kirbyt any links that I feel might be of greater interest, which is basically what I’ve always done. So if you want to know each time a new post is published, follow @thecave_com. Otherwise just keep doing what you’ve been doing.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[thecave On Twitter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter/"/>
    <published>2015-06-14T22:31:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-14T22:31:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Uli <a href="https://twitter.com/uliwitness/status/600656348272001024">asked</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Do you have a Twitter feed that lets me know when you post something new?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It only took me a month, but I finally have a Twitter account for thecave. Follow <a href="https://twitter.com/thecave_com/">@thecave_com</a> on Twitter if you want to know when I post something new to this blog. And as always you can subscribe to the <a href="http://www.thecave.com/feed.xml">RSS feed</a> if you prefer feed readers over Twitter.</p>

<h2 id="the-technical-how-to">The Technical How To</h2>

<p>There are a few different ways to automate the process of posting a link on Twitter when you publish a new blog post. <a href="http://twitterfeed.com">Twitter Feed</a> is one service I tried. It is fast and easy to setup, and it includes options such as including the title, description, or title and description in the tweet. Even though Twitter Feed is a cinch to setup, I decided to go with <a href="https://ifttt.com/">If This Then That (IFTTT)</a> instead.</p>

<p>Using IFTTT create a new recipe. Select <em>Feed</em> for the trigger and <em>Twitter</em> for the action. Be sure to connect your Twitter account to the IFTTT if you have not already done so. And that’s it. Next time you make a blog post, IFTTT will update your Twitter account with the title and link to the post.</p>

<p>And thanks <a href="https://twitter.com/uliwitness">@uliwitness</a> for suggesting I do this.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building An App From Start To Finish]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish/"/>
    <published>2015-06-08T09:09:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-08T09:09:35-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amy Hoy wrote the first version of her book <a href="https://unicornfree.com/just-fucking-ship">Just Fucking Ship</a> in 24 hours, which is awesome. Along those same lines, <a href="https://twitter.com/_davidsmith">David Smith</a> built an app from start to finish in about 6 hours - also awesome, and he posted this video that shows the entire process.</p>

<div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rEkuRFO6xTw?color=white&amp;theme=light"></iframe></figure></div>

<p>Both of these, the book and the app, are motivating me to do more faster. I just need to stop letting excuses and fear of not being perfect get in my way.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Better To Try An Idea]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/its-better-to-try-an-idea/"/>
    <published>2015-06-08T08:54:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-08T08:54:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/its-better-to-try-an-idea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of my favorite quotes about shipping:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s better to try an idea and see if it works than worry too much about its potential and never ship. - <a href="https://twitter.com/_davidsmith">@_davidsmith</a></p>
</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stuck Working For Others]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/04/stuck-working-for-others/"/>
    <published>2015-06-04T16:31:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-04T16:31:38-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/04/stuck-working-for-others</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love this quote from Amy Hoy:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you only do what pays immediately, you will be stuck working for other people. Or you will be stuck doing what other people want you to do…forever.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The quote come from her talk about <a href="https://unicornfree.com/2015/be-your-own-angel-a-revenue-model-for-slow-startups?inf_contact_key=33d23f3cc326dbb9432ca21551e5c05960ba9e460978b642f3bc69a5e6171317">being your own angel investor</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where I Blog These Days]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days/"/>
    <published>2015-05-19T09:40:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-19T09:40:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve recently, and “recently” as in the last couple of years, cut back on the number of blog sites I have. I’m down to three sites now, and that seems manageable. The sites are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/">thecave.com</a><br />
  That’s this site. It’s my personal blog, and it’s where I post most often. I talk about everything from what’s going on with me personally to snowboarding to programming. The site is broken down into categories, and I have plans to publish an RSS feed for each category so readers can filter out topics they might consider noise.</li>
  <li><a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/">blog.whitepeaksoftware.com</a><br />
  This is my company blog site. The focus of this site is to talk about the company and the products I sell. Granted I’m doing a horrible job at keeping up with the posts. That’s probably one of the many reasons my stuff doesn’t sell as well as it did a few years back.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.rowanturner.net/">rowanturner.net</a><br />
  Yep, my son has his own website. But he has no interest in making posts here, so I do it for him. I usually post pictures and videos of Rowan and his friends off having fun. My mom might be the only person reading this site regularly, but that’s fine. I’ll keep posting because I like looking back on past articles and reliving fun moments with my kid.</li>
</ul>

<p>These sites each have RSS feeds, so you don’t have to remember to visit. And some day I’ll do a better job of mentioning when new posts are available on the various social networks for those who don’t want to subscribe to the feeds. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snow River At Stowe]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe/"/>
    <published>2015-05-09T11:24:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-09T11:24:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This looks like it was a lot of fun. Wish I had known about it when it happened last year. </p>

<div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wfWUHKUt-Q0?color=white&amp;theme=light"></iframe></figure></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Views Created In Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/15/views-created-in-code/"/>
    <published>2015-04-15T12:58:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-15T12:58:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/15/views-created-in-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year I posted an article that talks about why <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout/">I stopped using Interface Builder</a> in favor of writing code to create views. There are some who disagree with me, and to them I say, “To each his own.” And there are some who agree with me, but choose not to publicize it. No matter. Every programmer has tricks that make them more productive, and creating views in code just happens to be one trick that works well for me. </p>

<p>What works for me doesn’t necessarily work for others. But I have to say, I had a brief “HA!” moment when I read this comment from Peter Steinberger’s post about <a href="http://petersteinberger.com/blog/2015/researching-researchkit/">researching Apple’s research kit</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>All views are created in code. Apple uses a Storyboard for the example catalog, but that’s it. Apple uses the standard pattern of overriding <code>viewDidLoad</code> to build UI in combination with Auto Layout and the visual format language, whenever possible.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Great minds think alike.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Though I don’t override <code>viewDidLoad</code> to create my views. I usually create a view class, and I add an instance of the class to the view controller’s view in <code>loadView</code>. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No WWDC Or SF Trip]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip/"/>
    <published>2015-04-14T09:20:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-14T09:20:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple announced the dates for this year’s WWDC, and once again a lottery is being used to decide who gets to buy a ticket. I have no interesting is attending WWDC other than to attend the labs since I do have questions I would love to ask an Apple engineer. But it’s not worth spending $1599 on a ticket just for that. </p>

<p>Likewise, I’m struggling to justify spending the money to stay in San Francisco the week of WWDC just to hang out with friends and drink beer. Certainly reconnecting with friends and making news ones is very enjoyable, but there are cheaper ways for me to do that. So I’ve decided I’m not going to SF for this year’s WWDC. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Should Feel Guilty But I Don't]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/13/i-should-feel-guilty-but-i-dont/"/>
    <published>2015-04-13T20:15:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-13T20:15:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/13/i-should-feel-guilty-but-i-dont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played hooky from work afternoon. I should feel guilty but I don’t. </p>

<p>I picked up Rowan from school this afternoon, and we headed to the mountain. Unfortunately I forgot his skis boots, so we had to stop by the house. Then as we tried to get on the lift I realized I left our passes in our jackets. The temperature was in the 60, so we weren’t wearing our jackets. They were still at the house. The afternoon was off to a bad start, but our luck changed. </p>

<p>We were able to get two runs in before the lifts closed thanks to the nice lifties that let us through without our passes. Also we ran into some friends in our first run, including a class mate of Rowan’s. After the lifts shut down for the day we hung out in the parking lot for a bit of après ski with friends. Then we headed to Rimrocks where we ran into more friends. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8776/16952950809_f0103c0255_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>It was a great father son afternoon with wonderful friends, and when I’m 85 years old I’ll remember how much fun Rowan and I had today. I won’t remember the work I should have done today, and that’s why I don’t feel guilty about how I spent my time this afternoon.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8722/16951598160_95cb6df7cc_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Argh! Thanks A Lot Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/10/argh-thanks-a-lot-apple/"/>
    <published>2015-04-10T03:13:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-10T03:13:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/10/argh-thanks-a-lot-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I woke up at 2:45 am this morning to buy a new Apple Watch. I ordered the 42mm space gray with black sport band Apple Watch Sport, but I’m still annoyed. I got a delivery date of May 13 to May 27, and that annoys me because I was ready to order at 3 am.</p>

<p>I was at my computer trying to load store.apple.com at 3 am, but the site was down. I foolishly kept refreshing the web page for 6 minutes before deciding to try the Apple Store app on my iPhone. The app worked perfectly, and thanks to Apple Pay, the order process was fast. But it was too late to get the watch I wanted in the first set of shipments, and all because I wasted my time trying to use the damn website.</p>

<p>I know, “first world problems.” All I can say is I’m grumpy when I have to use an alarm clock to wake up, and I become more grumpy when my time is wasted because of a website outage after waking up so freakin’ early.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Watch Will Make iPhone 6 Plus Size Less Annoying]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying/"/>
    <published>2015-04-06T21:42:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-06T21:42:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things that annoys me most about the size of my iPhone 6 Plus is pulling it out of my pocket while at a bar or restaurant just to see why my phone buzzed. The majority of the time my phone buzzes because of an incoming text message. I have notifications turned off for almost all other apps, and I rarely. if ever, get phone calls these days, which is why I know the buzz is most likely a text message. And if I’m at the bar without my wife, then the person trying to reach me is most likely my wife. </p>

<p>So when the text message comes in, I have to pull out this big honkin’ device out of my pocket and light up the room just to see the message. I may reply, and if I do, it’s a short reply because, after all, I’m busy at the bar. Then I put the phone back into my pocket only to repeat all of this a few minutes later. </p>

<p>Receiving text messages doesn’t annoy me, but having to pull out and put away this big device every few minutes does annoy me. </p>

<p>It occurred to me that one of the possible reasons why Apple decided to release the larger iPhones was because they knew, thanks to the Apple Watch, that there would be no reason to pull out these larger devices from pockets and purses just to check notifications and send simple text messages and replies.</p>

<p>The Apple Watch will make the iPhone 6 Plus size less annoying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best April Fools' Joke Ever]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/03/best-april-fools-joke-ever/"/>
    <published>2015-04-03T01:32:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-03T01:32:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/03/best-april-fools-joke-ever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I met a guy tonight at the bar. He was the victim of the best April Fools’ Joke ever.</p>

<p>He broke up with his girlfriend 5 weeks ago. At 8 am on April 1 she sent him a text message with a picture of a at-home pregnancy test that was positive. Yep, she was telling my new friend he was going to be a dad. 16 hours later, at midnight and after he consumed countless shots and another drinks, she sent him the text “Happy April Fools.”</p>

<p>She really got him, and he really appreciated the joke. The fact that she let him think he was going to be a new dad for 16 hours is what makes the joke really great. Had she reply “April Fools” five minutes after the first text message, the joke wouldn’t be as funny. But the fact that she made him sweat it out all day makes this the best April Fools’ joke ever. I’m just glad the joke wasn’t played on me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2600 Miles In 4 Minutes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/28/2600-miles-in-4-minutes/"/>
    <published>2015-03-28T02:36:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-28T02:36:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/28/2600-miles-in-4-minutes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here’s a very cool video of a guy who did a time-lapse of his Pacific Crest Trail thru hike. Enjoy. </p>

<div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xyo8OIp7aHM?color=white&amp;theme=light"></iframe></figure></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>