<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[thecave | Ramblings from a crotchety old man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-17T10:26:06-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright (c) 2003-2014 White Peak Software Inc</rights>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Send Camera Video to Your TV]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/20/send-your-camera-video-to-your-tv/"/>
    <published>2013-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/20/send-your-camera-video-to-your-tv</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Believe it or not, I finally released a new app for iOS. It&#8217;s my first new app for <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/'>White Peak Software</a> in more than 2 years. Somewhere along the way over the last two years I lost my way, but I&#8217;m back.</p>

<p>So what&#8217;s this new app? It&#8217;s <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/big-screen'>Big Screen</a>.</p>

<p>Big Screen lets you view the video from your iPhone or iPad&#8217;s camera on your TV. It requires an AppleTV, or other AirPlay receiver. Sure, you can use the built-in iOS 7 camera app to do the same, but you will see the app&#8217;s chrome on the TV. With Big Screen, there is no chrome or any other evidence that the app is being used. This makes Big Screen ideal for presentation, conferences, and other events where large screen TVs are used to let viewers in the room see the action on the stage.</p>

<p>I got the idea to write an <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/main/big-screen/why'>app to display the camera&#8217;s video on a TV</a> while attending an event at Rowan&#8217;s elementary school. It just goes to show you never know when a new app idea will pop up.</p>

<p>Big Screen is a free app available now in the iOS App Store. <a href='http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/main/store/buy/big-screen'>Grab a copy</a>, and let me know what you think.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rowan on the Balance Board]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/11/rowan-on-the-balance-board/"/>
    <published>2013-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/11/rowan-on-the-balance-board</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='/images/blog/2013-11-11rowan-balanceboard.gif'><img alt='Rowan on the balance board' border='0' class='alignleft' src='/images/blog/2013-11-11rowan-balanceboard.gif' width='150' /></a> I wanted to play with a GIF animator, so I used a few photos I took yesterday of Rowan playing on the balance board. That kid is going to be so much better than me at just about everything.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whale Watching Tour]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/whale-watching-tour/"/>
    <published>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/whale-watching-tour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Around-Town/Salem-Mass/Whale-Watching-Tour'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Around-Town/Salem-Mass/Whale-Watching-Tour/i-JBK3hfx/0/Th/IMG_4272-Th.jpg' /></a> Here are some <a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Around-Town/Salem-Mass/Whale-Watching-Tour'>pictures</a> from our recent whale watching tour out of Gloucester, MA.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pawleys Island with the Davis Clan]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/pawleys-island/"/>
    <published>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/pawleys-island</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Davis-Clan/Pawleys-Island-Summer-2013'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Davis-Clan/Pawleys-Island-Summer-2013/i-694tRP6/0/Th/IMG_4230-Th.jpg' /></a> Here are <a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Davis-Clan/Pawleys-Island-Summer-2013'>pictures</a> from our visit to Pawleys Island. The whole Davis Clan was there for this trip.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Camp Murphy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/camp-murphy/"/>
    <published>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/camp-murphy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Camp-Murphy/Camp-Murphy-2013'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Camp-Murphy/Camp-Murphy-2013/i-XH5KmC9/0/Th/IMG_1664-Th.jpg' /></a> <a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Camp-Murphy/Camp-Murphy-2013'>Pictures</a> from this year&#8217;s Camp Murphy. Great time as always.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andy's Wedding]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/andys-wedding/"/>
    <published>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/andys-wedding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Weddings/Andys-Wedding'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Weddings/Andys-Wedding/i-G9jR27x/0/Th/IMG_1642-Th.jpg' /></a> Here are <a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Weddings/Andys-Wedding'>pictures</a> from my brother Andy&#8217;s wedding.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Knew a Drug Dealer in Memphis]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/19/i-knew-a-drug-dealer-in-memphis/"/>
    <published>2013-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/19/i-knew-a-drug-dealer-in-memphis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just received a spam email saying, &#8220;A well-established company wants to offer you a telecommuting opportunity in the business of mail management.The position requires no professional skills besides basic computer literacy. The key responsibilities are to receive correspondence at your home address, repack and resend it to our customers.&#8221;</p>

<p>I knew a drug dealer in Memphis who made me a similar offer back in the 80s, but the offer included me staying for free at an apartment on the south bluff.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations to the Kid]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/20/congrats-to-the-kid/"/>
    <published>2013-06-20T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/20/congrats-to-the-kid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Rowan/Pre-school-Graduation/30095717_rX5mHW'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Rowan/Pre-school-Graduation/i-mVqV5r9/0/Th/IMG_1350%20-%20Version%202-Th.jpg' /></a> A big congratulations to Rowan, aka the kid, for graduating from pre-school. He&#8217;s been at Run-a-Muck for three and a half years. Seems strange that he&#8217;s done - though officially his last day is tomorrow. I&#8217;m very proud of the kid.</p>

<p>Here are the <a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Rowan/Pre-school-Graduation/30095717_rX5mHW'>graduation pictures</a> for your viewing pleasure.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm an Idiot]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/18/im-an-idiot/"/>
    <published>2013-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/18/im-an-idiot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am, what I like to call certain individuals, an idiot. Yep. I too am an idiot.</p>

<p>Last week we bought a used Subaru Outback from a private seller. As with buying any car, used or new, there is a period of discovery as you learn more about your purchase. This is especially true when you buy a high mileage car. Our &#8220;new&#8221; Subaru came with 161,702 miles on it so I knew we would make all sorts of interesting, but hopefully not expensive, discoveries. I knew before buying the car it needs new tires, despite the seller insisting that the tires are in good condition. (Side note: I showed the seller what good condition tires look like by showing him the tires on our other Outback. This was a plus for us because it helped drive down the price of the car.)</p>

<p>I also knew the car needs new rear brakes, not immediately but soon. And I knew we would need to have the interior detailed to get rid of most of the dog hair and smell. No offense to dog lovers, but I can&#8217;t stand a car that smells like a dog. So de-dogifying the car was a top priority for me and another point that I raised to help drive down the price.</p>

<p>We&#8217;ve had the car for almost a week, and so far no surprises. But that changed yesterday.</p>

<p>I had our local mechanic take a look at the car yesterday to let me know what discoveries he finds. I also had the car inspected. The car passed state inspection as expected, and the mechanic didn&#8217;t find anything problems with the car that I didn&#8217;t already know about. Life is good, and I felt like we got a good deal on the car. But then, shortly after leaving the car shop the car started acting up.</p>

<p>As I was driving the car lost power. It was still running, but it wouldn&#8217;t go when I gave it gas. Then the car would take off as the transmission made hard gear shifts. My first thought was, &#8220;Oh no. There goes the transmission.&#8221; Then the check engine light came on. I continued driving the car in a stop and go pattern hoping to make it back to the car shop, which was only a couple of miles away. Next the check oil temperature light came on and started flashing. &#8220;Great!&#8221; I thought. &#8220;This car is about to totally crap out on me.&#8221; Then the car died. Luckily it cranked right up and I was able to continue my crazy drive to the car shop.</p>

<p>I made it back to the car shop, and they ran a diagnosis. The throttle sensor was acting up. Apparently there is some dirt or corrosion in or around the sensor, which is not uncommon with higher mileage Subarus. Apparently in poking around the car, the mechanic giggled a wire or something that caused the sensor to fail. It&#8217;s an easy fix and is something that doesn&#8217;t have to be addressed right away.</p>

<p>I started feeling good about the car purchase again despite this new discovery. But this morning we made another new discovery. The car battery was completely dead. &#8220;Oh great. The car has some type of electrical problem,&#8221; was my first thought. I called the mechanic and he too thought the sensor problem and the battery problem might be related. He suggested that the battery might be the source of the problem, so I replaced it with a new battery. This was something we needed to do anyways because the other battery looked old, and I wasn&#8217;t sure how much cranking power it would have this winter once we&#8217;re in chilly Vermont. (Another side note: We have had battery problems in the past in Vermont when the temperature drops below zero, so replacing the battery was already on my to do list. I was just hoping to wait a couple of months before spending the money.)</p>

<p>Because I wasn&#8217;t convinced the problem was related to the battery, I had the guy at the auto parts store check the old battery. The diagnostics showed that the battery was fine but it needed a charged. Still, I opted to buy a new battery because I knew I would be buying one soon enough, and I wanted to make sure the battery was eliminated in this guessing game of why the old battery was completely drained this morning.</p>

<p>I installed the new battery and my wife immediately pointed out that the parking lights were on. Bingo! Now I knew why the battery was dead this morning. But what I didn&#8217;t know was why the parking lights were on. Between the throttle sensor problem yesterday and the always on parking lights, I was starting to believe more and more that the car has some type of electrical problem. I drove the car to car shop to have the mechanic look at the problem. He too was baffled by this latest discovery.</p>

<p>This is our third time purchasing a high mileage Subaru. We don&#8217;t drive much, so we don&#8217;t have a need for a newer, nicer car (though my wife wouldn&#8217;t mind having a newer, nicer car). We pay cash for the older cars and drive them until they die. Our first Subaru had 193,000 miles on it when we purchased it for $1500. Our second had around 165,000 miles and we paid $3300. And our latest ride had just under 162,000 miles on it and cost us $3200. We know going into each purchase that we&#8217;ll put about a thousand dollars into the car, but after that it&#8217;s been our experience that we don&#8217;t have any major, unexpected issues with the cars as long as we follow the manufacturer&#8217;s recommended maintenance schedule. When our first Subaru started to finally have major issues, at around 215,000 miles, we sold it. And knock on wood, our second Subaru hasn&#8217;t had any major issues with it yet. But there is one thing different I did with our first two Subaru purchases that I didn&#8217;t do with our latest. I didn&#8217;t have the dealer check out the car for us.</p>

<p>This time around I had our local mechanic check out our newest Subaru. We trust our mechanic and he performs the scheduled maintenance on our other Subaru Outback. But our newest Subaru started having trouble after he looked it over. And even worse, he wasn&#8217;t sure why the parking lights were on and wouldn&#8217;t turn off. So I decided that&#8217;s is. I&#8217;m taking the car to the dealer that serviced our first Subaru and our second one up until about a year and a half ago.</p>

<p>In case you are wondering, the only reason I stopped going to the dealer was that the local shop is cheaper for regular maintenance work such as oil changes.</p>

<p>I walked into the Subaru Service Center and explained that the parking lights would not turn off and as a result I had a dead battery this morning. The gentleman behind the counter said he knew exactly what the problem is and it&#8217;s a really simple fix. He asked me to show him the car, so we walked outside to the car. He then said, &#8220;Watch this,&#8221; and proceeded to flip a switch on top of the steering column. He said, &#8220;Parking lights are off.&#8221; Switch. &#8220;Packing lights are on.&#8221;</p>

<p>Boy, I am an idiot!</p>

<p>It turns out that our local mechanic accidentally hit the parking light switch yesterday, and idiot me didn&#8217;t think to check the obvious this morning after I discovered the parking lights would not turn off. But idiot me is in good company because our local mechanic didn&#8217;t think about the switch either. Instead, we both were looking at the problem from the wrong point of view. We both were thinking the throttle sensor problem, dead battery, and parking light issue were all related when in fact they were not. It took having a third person with a fresh perspective to point out the obvious. And he was nice enough to not point out how I&#8217;m obviously an idiot.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We're Moving to a Ski Town...Finally]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/05/moving-to-a-ski-town/"/>
    <published>2013-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/05/moving-to-a-ski-town</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s official. It&#8217;s really going to happen. We&#8217;re moving to a ski town! We&#8217;re moving to <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stowe,_Vermont'>Stowe, Vermont</a>, in August.</p>

<p>While this isn&#8217;t really new news for most, it&#8217;s now official with the signing on a lease for a condo in Stowe and the signing of a property management agreement for our house in Salem. I&#8217;ve been talking about this move for many months, but it almost didn&#8217;t happen despite being part of a longer term plan since we left NYC.</p>

<p>Melanie and I love NYC, and living in Manhattan was definitely one of the best things either of us have ever done. But skiing - for Melanie - and snowboarding - for me - was becoming a bigger part of our lives. It may sounds strange, but I got into snowboarding while living in New York. People think of New York as a big city with tall buildings, great food, wonder entertainment, and people everywhere. But New York has something to offer everyone including snowboarding. The closest slope is Mountain Creek in New Jersey, and there are buses that run from Grand Central to Hunter and Windham mountains in the Catskills. During the winter of 2000/2001 I spent many a Saturday and or Sunday at one of these &#8220;local&#8221; mountains snowboarding. I may have never become obsessed with snowboarding if not for living in New York City.</p>

<p>Fast forward a few years, Melanie and I bought a &#8220;city car.&#8221; It was a Subaru Impreza that we paid $1500 cash for. I call it a city car because it sat in a parking lot most of the time and the body would get dinged up from other cars. But we didn&#8217;t care. The car served one purpose and one purpose only - to get us to and from <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Killington,_Vermont'>Killington, Vermont</a>.</p>

<p>Like many living in Manhattan, we would leave the city on the weekend during the winter. Our weekend journeys took us up to Killington, Vermont, where Melanie&#8217;s parents have a condo. We would spend the weekend snowboarding with the crowds. At the time I wasn&#8217;t bothered by the crowds like I am today. I was just happy to be out on the slopes. The problem, however, was the drive. Depending on traffic it could take us up to 7 hours to drive from the West Village to Killington.</p>

<p>Melanie and I realized priorities for us had changed since getting married, and living closer to the slopes was one of those changes. Plus the drive was starting to drive us crazy. We decided to explore for places to live in New England. Because Melanie would be working out of New York City, we knew we needed to live near an airport. And we weren&#8217;t sure how Melanie&#8217;s commute each week to JFK would be, so we settled on <a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salem,_Massachusetts'>Salem, Massachusetts</a>, as a &#8220;temporary&#8221; place to live while she tried out life as a commuting flight attendant. The plan was: If the commute sucked we would move back to NYC, but if the commute was okay then we would start looking for a more permanent New England town closer to the slopes to call home.</p>

<p>But something distracted us from this plan. Melanie got knocked up. It was a planned knock up, but it caused more changes in our priorities. Instead of finding a new town to call home, we found a house in Salem to buy. Nesting, gotta love it.</p>

<p>Despite becoming more settled in Salem we keep snowboarding (and skiing) a priority for our family of three. Rowan has made numerous trips to the slopes over the last five years of his life, and he has become quite the good little skier. And now he is learning to snowboard.</p>

<p>Having Rowan in our lives hasn&#8217;t limited our time skiing and snowboarding. Sure, there were seasons early on were we didn&#8217;t get to hit the slopes as much as we would have liked, and we had to make compromises such as me snowboarding in the morning and Melanie skiing in the afternoon so one of us could watch the kid. But we tried hard to make sure having a kid wouldn&#8217;t distract us from our love of being on the mountain. We were also not limited to riding only the hills of New England. Rowan has joined us on trips to places such as Breckenridge, Colorado, and Ogden, Utah. But now we face another distraction that would limit our ability to play on the snow as much as we would like.</p>

<p>Rowan starts kindergarten in September.</p>

<p>Having Rowan in school five days a week will be a change for us, but not being able to pull him out of school regularly is an even bigger change. Rowan has been signed up for pre-school and daycare three days a week for years, but he doesn&#8217;t always go three days a week. Instead we take him on fun trips. While pulling him out of pre-school is okay, in fact probably better for him than being in pre-school five days week, pulling him out of kindergarten, first grade, second grade, and so on on a regular basis isn&#8217;t going to fly with school officials. And we ain&#8217;t no teachers so home skooling the kid ain&#8217;t ah option fur us. But having Rowan in school five days a week does not mean we have to cut back on our time riding magic powder, as Rowan likes to call it.</p>

<p>Knowing that Rowan is starting &#8220;real&#8221; school soon reminded Melanie and me of why we left NYC - to live closer to the slopes. Salem was supposed to be a temporary stop, but it has become more permanent especially with the purchase of our house. The fact that we might have to drive 3 hours to Killington to ride with weekend crowds (we tend to be on the mountains week days only to avoid crowds) wasn&#8217;t something I was happy about. So last year Melanie and I started talking about our original plan to move closer to the slopes and possibly live in a ski town.</p>

<p>Planning this move has been an emotional roller coaster ride. We would get excited about the possibility of living the dream only to hit rock bottom when it looked like it wasn&#8217;t going to happen. One of the biggest challenges has been finding a suitable place to live. Finding an apartment in Manhattan is a cut-throat process but at least new apartments become available daily. The same isn&#8217;t true for Stowe. There are not as many places available, and making matters worse is that many of the available rental properties, especially houses, are seasonal rentals where the owner can earn a lot of money renting out the place weekly during the winter months.</p>

<p>We were able to find apartments and condos available for long-term rental (6 to 12+ months), but most came furnished. This also bothered us. Living in a place for a year with someone else&#8217;s furniture doesn&#8217;t feel like home. The other problem was the size of most places. Unless we were willing to pay three grand or more a month in rent, we would have the settle on a 2-bedroom place. For someone who works from home this is a problem. Before we bought our house we lived in 2-bedroom apartments while I worked from home, so I can make it work. However the difference this time around is the kid. We didn&#8217;t have the kid before, but now we do. Still, it should work out since the kid will be in school five days a week.</p>

<p>So over the course of the last four months finding a place in Stowe to live has looked grim. We&#8217;re were close to giving up.</p>

<p>You are probably wondering right now why we didn&#8217;t just look for a place in one of the surround towns. There are certainly many more affordable options including houses. But we want Rowan in the Stowe public school system, which means we must be a resident of Stowe. There is an option to pay a crap load of money to get your kid into the Stowe school system, but that&#8217;s not something we can afford to do. So finding a place to live in Stowe was a must for us.</p>

<p>As I said, we were close to giving up. In fact, in my head I had already given up. I started making plans to be in Salem for at least one more year. I decided I would be in San Francisco for WWDC. I even volunteered to help with labs at AltWWDC. But as luck would have it, a large 2-bedroom condo that we liked became available in Stowe. It didn&#8217;t really become available as much as we helped it become available by sparking an idea in the condo owner&#8217;s mind.</p>

<p>In May, we placed a wanted ad in the local Stowe newspaper. The ad was simple.</p>

<p>&#8220;Family of 3, no pets, looking for a long-term (12+ months), unfurnished house for rent in the Stowe public school district. Prefer July or August move in date.&#8221;</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t remember who gave us the idea to post an ad in the local paper. I think it was my sister-in-law Brooke, so that&#8217;s who I will credit for the idea. Thanks Brooke.</p>

<p>We received only one reply from the ad. It was from a retired couple living in Stowe. The couple did not have plans to leave Stowe anytime soon, but the ad got them thinking. They knew they would leave Stowe within the next couple of years to live closer to family. They called us to chat and explore the idea of leaving Stowe sooner. Long story short, they liked us, we liked them, and their family liked the idea of them moving closer sooner than later. So last week we made it official.</p>

<p>Just two weeks ago I was resolved to the fact that we would be in Salem for at least one more year, then few days later it looked like the move was back on. Melanie even said me excitedly, &#8220;This is really going to happen.&#8221; And yes, indeed it looked like it was going to finally happen. Melanie asked me not to say anything publicly last week, which is why I couldn&#8217;t share the details of why I canceled my trip to San Fran. But now that the lease is signed and we have a move-in date, I can tell the world.</p>

<p>We move in August. For the moment we take possession of the Stowe condo on August 15. However we&#8217;re hoping we can move up the date to August 1.</p>

<p>As for our house in Salem, we&#8217;re not selling it. Instead we&#8217;re going to try our hand at being landlords. But we will be silent landlords. We&#8217;ve hired a property management company to manage the house for us. Renting our house is part of the reason we hope we can move into the Stowe condo as early as August 1. We want to make our house available for tenants looking to move in before the school year starts in Salem.</p>

<p>And as for canceling my trip to San Francisco, as well as a visit to Memphis, I decided we need to hold on to as much cash as possible. The next few months are going to be expensive, and how expensive will depend on how quickly we can rent out our house. It&#8217;s great that I work for myself, but the indie income is itself a roller coaster ride. And while I&#8217;m bummed that I will not be in SF for WWDC, I&#8217;m not bummed about getting to snowboard almost daily this upcoming winter season.</p>

<p>So that&#8217;s my big announcement and the reason plans for this summer have changed. We&#8217;re moving to a ski town to make living the dream even better.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kayaking the Ipswich River]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/02/kayaking-the-ipswitch-river/"/>
    <published>2013-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/02/kayaking-the-ipswitch-river</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Sports/Ipswich-River/29760430_PwD6W4'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Sports/Ipswitch-River/i-BBjM2Nm/0/Th/IMG_1313-Th.jpg' /></a> Yesterday I did a 16 mile paddle on the Ipswich River with my buddy Shawn. It was the perfect way to spend a Saturday morning. We put in at Thunder Bridge, made our way east through the Ipswich Wildlife Sanctuary, and finally stopped in the town of Ipswich.</p>

<p>We keep a fast pace so I didn&#8217;t get a chance to take a lot of pictures, but I need sneak in a few <a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Sports/Ipswich-River/29760430_PwD6W4'>shots</a>.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Visit to the Eiffel Tower]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/05/24/our-visit-to-the-eiffel-tower/"/>
    <published>2013-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/05/24/our-visit-to-the-eiffel-tower</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Europe/Eiffel-Tower-May-2013/'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Europe/Eiffel-Tower-May-2013/i-xsrGKH2/0/Th/IMG_1293-Th.jpg' /></a> Melanie was working a flight to Paris this week, and as luck would have it there were seats available on the flight. So Rowan and I decided to join her. Rowan has wanted to visit the Eiffel Tower for as long as I can remember, so that&#8217;s what we did on this trip. We flew to Paris, went to the Eiffel Tower, then flew back home. Pictures from our short trip are available <a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Europe/Eiffel-Tower-May-2013/'>here</a>.</p>

<p>Rowan was a real trooper during this trip. He handled the long plane ride, time zone changes, and lack of sleep like a seasoned traveler.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Bank, My Kind of Banking]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/05/12/simple-banking-my-kind-of-banking/"/>
    <published>2013-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/05/12/simple-banking-my-kind-of-banking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier today I <a href='https://alpha.app.net/kirbyt/post/5586671'>posted</a> on ADN that I love banking with Simple. My friend <a href='https://alpha.app.net/danielpunkass'>Daniel</a> asked if I could summarize in 250 or less what sets Simple apart from other banks. I did my best to summarize what I thought was different/better about Simple, but I still felt a blog post would be better.</p>

<p>At the end of 2012, my wife and I decided to return to separate checking accounts. We&#8217;ve had a joint account for years, but it wasn&#8217;t working for us. We do better managing our money separately. Going back to separate accounts meant I needed to setup a new personal checking account for myself. I had heard of <a href='https://www.simple.com'>Simple</a>, so I decided to give it a try.</p>

<p>Before trying Simple, I asked if any of my friends use Simple. I was surprised to find that of my friends with a Simple account, not one of them really liked it. And none are using it as their primary bank. But as I read more about Simple, the more I liked the concepts behind Simple. Despite the lack of rave reviews from friends, I decided to give Simple a try. A friend sent me an invite, and within 24 hours I had my own Simple account.</p>

<p>I should point out that I approach banking differently than most. I&#8217;ve been using online banking for as long as I cam remember, at least since 1992, possibly longer. And I&#8217;ve not lived in a city where my bank had a local branch or ATM in over 10 years. This means I&#8217;ve done all my banking online and done mail-in check deposits for the last decade. This already makes me well suited for banking with Simple.</p>

<p>After five months of using Simple, and I have to say I love it. It&#8217;s almost as if Simple was designed specifically for me. Simple not only provides the banking services I need, but it&#8217;s &#8220;goals&#8221; feature makes it easier for me to manage and save my money. Goals is the single most feature that makes Simple standout from all the other online banking experiences I have had over the years. Of course the beautiful, easy to use web interface and iPhone app also set Simple apart from other banks, but it&#8217;s goals that have changed my expectations for online banking.</p>

<p>Goals help you save money in an automated fashion. Say you want to save a $1,000 in six months for a trip. You define a goal and optionally give it a starting balance, say $50. Each day Simple will move a few dollars from your &#8220;safe to spend&#8221; to the goal until your goal is reached. The dollar amount varies based on when you want to archive the goal. A goal of saving $1,000 in three months will move more money daily than a goal of the same amount that spans six months. You can also pause the goal and manually move money in and out of a goal any time you like.</p>

<p>I use goals to set aside money for paying big bills such as our quarterly property tax payment as well as for stashing money away in an emergency fund goal and savings for Rowan. I also use goals for monthly automatic debit payments like our gas and electric bills. These goals are not tied to a time period. Instead, when I get the statement for a bill I create a goal for the payment amount. This sets aside the money that will be automatically debited from my account. Once a transaction has clear, such as paying the gas bill, I mark the payment as spent from my gas bill goal. This means my &#8220;safe to spend&#8221; balance remains unaffected.</p>

<p>And what of this &#8220;safe to spend&#8221; that I keep mentioning? The &#8220;safe to spend&#8221; is a different way of looking at your available balance. The &#8220;safe to spend&#8221; balance is the dollar amount you have in your account that has not been set aside for a scheduled payment or goal. In other words, &#8220;safe to spend&#8221; tells you how much money you have in your account that is not allocated to some other purpose, making it&#8230;safe to spend.</p>

<p>Your account still has an account balance, and the Simple website and iPhone app easily shows this information. But knowing how much I actually have to spend helps me not overspend. That&#8217;s the problem I&#8217;ve had in the past with online banking. I see I have $1,500 in the available balance, but I might forget that I need a $1,000 of that $1,500 to pay my estimated quarterly taxes. With a goal I don&#8217;t have to think about setting aside the $1,000. Simple goal does it for me.</p>

<p>I know third party banking apps have, for years, had features to hide money in an account and some even have goal-like features, but that&#8217;s another reason I really like banking with Simple. I don&#8217;t need a third party app. Simple provides the features I need to manage my money without needing a third party app, and that is another point that sets Simple apart from other online banks. Other online banking experiences are so basic that you need a third party app to help manage your money.</p>

<p>As much as I enjoy banking with Simple, it&#8217;s not all perfect (yet). There are some things I don&#8217;t like. I cannot view my goals in the iPhone app. I found a word around for this by opening the details of a past transaction and tapping &#8220;Spend from goal&#8221;. This shows me each of my goals and how much money is in each goal. I just have to remember not to actually select a goal since I don&#8217;t want to transaction to use money from the goal.</p>

<p>Another thing I don&#8217;t like about Simple is that I cannot assign a category to a scheduled payment until after the payment has cleared. The good news is once I do set the category for the cleared payment, if I ever send another payment to the same payee, Simple will automatically assign the category for me based on the previously selected category. Still, I think it&#8217;s silly that I cannot set the category at the time I initially setup the scheduled payment.</p>

<p>Also, Simple does not yet have support for joint checking accounts. Granted I don&#8217;t need joint checking, but for some this is a deal breaker. What I do need is a business checking account, which is another service not yet provided by Simple. So I must continue using a traditional bank for my business. The online experience with my traditional bank is okay, in fact better than with many other banks, but the experience is still not as good as with Simple.</p>

<p>And as for my friends who have tried Simple, their reasons for not using Simple as their primary bank varies from preferring to have a local branch to having a local ATM for cash deposits. I admit there are times when I wish I could do a cash deposit, but those times are rare and are usually only after I sell something on Craig&#8217;s List.</p>

<p>As for check deposits, taking a picture of the check and doing a mobile deposit using the Simple iPhone app is far faster for me than depositing a check through an ATM. And remember, I&#8217;ve not made check deposit, or cash for that matter, via an ATM for a decade so not having a local branch or ATM doesn&#8217;t effect me like it might effect others.</p>

<p>Simple is not a primary bank for everyone, but for me there is no better online bank than Simple.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What the Hell]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/04/27/what-the-hell/"/>
    <published>2013-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/04/27/what-the-hell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s right. What the hell?</p>

<p>I&#8217;m in Seattle stressing out about a talk I have to do in a few hours, and all I can think is what the hell?</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NSSnow 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/02/12/nssnow-2013/"/>
    <published>2013-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/02/12/nssnow-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Ski-and-Snowboard-Trips/NSSnow-2013/i-dq5gQjT/0/Th/IMG_1069-Th.jpg' />
<p>Last week Melanie and I had the pleasure to join 13 others in <a href='http://www.courchevel.com'>Courchevel, France</a>, for NSSnow 2013. NSSnow is a gathering of mostly Mac and iOS developers who love to ski and snowboard, well, mostly snowboard but skiers were welcome - Melanie was the token skier at this year&#8217;s NSSnow.</p>

<p>This year was the first NSSnow and it was simply amazing. Rob Elkin did an outstanding job organizing the week long event, and Mother Nature smiled on us with new snow almost daily. I rode the most powder and deepest powder I&#8217;ve ever ridden, and it was AWESOME! Combine that with meeting great new friends and it was the perfect snowboard vacation getaway.</p>

<p>For those who didn&#8217;t make it to NSSnow, and for those who did and want to re-live the moments, here are photos from the incredible week.</p>

<p><strong>Photos by:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/sets/72157632749826895/'>Kirby and Melanie</a></li>

<li><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/robelkin/sets/72157632745757578/'>Rob Elkin</a></li>

<li><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/clodagh/sets/72157632742930989/'>Clodagh Kelly</a></li>

<li><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/ctr/sets/72157632740072345/'>Chris Ross</a></li>

<li><a href='http://flickr.com/gp/44634982@N06/5r1giE/'>Paul Darcey</a></li>

<li><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/26409938@N00/sets/72157632744849656/'>Greg Raiz</a></li>

<li><a href='https://www.icloud.com/photostream/#A4GY8gBYGmFJfr'>Nigel Barber</a></li>

<li><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/stuffmc/sets/72157632691830865/'>Stuff MC</a></li>

<li><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/paulofierro/sets/72157632781226252'>Paulo Fierro</a></li>

<li><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/niquimerret/sets/72157632800614896/'>Niqui Merret</a></li>

<li><a href='http://www.flickr.com/search/?q=nssnow&amp;m=tags&amp;ss=2&amp;s=int'>NSSnow tag on Flickr</a></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Videos:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href='http://vimeo.com/paulofierro/nsbeerrun'>NSBeerRun video</a> starring Rob and Paulo. Filmed by Paulo.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Long Day with the Kid]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/01/19/super-long-day-with-the-kid/"/>
    <published>2013-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/01/19/super-long-day-with-the-kid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Melanie&#8217;s out of town enjoying some quality vacation time with one of her girlfriends leaving Rowan and me in Salem to enjoy some quality father son time. We made the most of it today, which has turned into a super long day.</p>

<p>Rowan woke me up at 4 AM looking for his blanket and Blue Doggie. Naturally, I couldn&#8217;t go back to sleep so I did some work starting at 4:30 AM. Rowan woke up at 8 AM, so I put the laptop away and started entertaining the kid. We had breakfast and played during the morning. At lunch time, we ate lunch while watching a Star Wars movie. Then we headed to the Boston Children&#8217;s Museum. We stayed until closing time, then headed to Rowan&#8217;s favorite restaurant, Acapulcos, for dinner. Then we had more play time, and had &#8220;movie night,&#8221; which was another Star Wars movie. Finally, the kid hit the sack at 10:30 PM and I jumped back on the laptop to do a bit of work.</p>

<p>Needless to say, it&#8217;s been a super long, and exhausting, day for both of us.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Christmas 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/12/25/christmas-2012/"/>
    <published>2012-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/12/25/christmas-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Christmas/Christmas-2012/27252258_tNP4bM'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Christmas/Christmas-2012/i-cxCnk8n/0/Th/IMG_0911-Th.jpg' /></a> We spent Christmas in Salem this year. Mother Nature was kind and gave us a little snow this morning, but it melted by mid-afternoon. I repeated the tradition I started a few years back by smoking a turkey for dinner. It&#8217;s was delicious, but not has favor packed as it was 2 years ago. I blame it on the lack of thyme. The grocery store was all out when I went shopping.</p>

<p>Rowan got lots of toys. It&#8217;s hard to tell which ones are his favorite since he has played with them all. Melanie got a set of stemless wine glasses, which is something she has wanted for a long time. And they&#8217;re the perfect companion to the wine chiller she got last Christmas. I got a new solar powered keyboard for my Mac, which I&#8217;m using right now to type this postings. And Rowan made me a coffee cup, which will be perfect for my hot cocoa fix.</p>

<p>Overall, it&#8217;s been a good, low key Christmas, just the way we like it.</p>

<p>(Photos from our Christmas holiday are available <a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Christmas/Christmas-2012/27252258_tNP4bM'>here</a>.)</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back from the Long Trail Hike]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/09/25/back-from-the-long-trail-hike/"/>
    <published>2012-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/09/25/back-from-the-long-trail-hike</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Hikes/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-2012/25322189_WRGQQ7'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Hikes/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-2012/i-2xkDqK9/0/Th/IMG0208-Th.jpg' /></a> My southbound hike of the Long Trail didn&#8217;t go as planned. I had to stop after 13 days due to a knee injury. As I said in a tweet, “Th-Th-Th-Th-Th…That’s all, folks. I’m not continuing the hike due to constant pain that has zapped all the fun out of the journey.” I’m disappointed that I wasn’t able to hike the trail end to end, but I’m glad I at least tried it. And I will be back next year to complete the remaining 182 miles.</p>

<h2 id='an_amazing_experience'>An Amazing Experience</h2>

<p>Despite not finishing and having to deal with knee pain for weeks that followed leaving the trail, I still look back to my days on the trail and think to myself, “What an amazing experience.” Leaving the trail was a hard thing to do. I struggled with mixed emotions. My heart was into the hike and I wanted to continue. But my brain, and the pain, said it was time to stop. Even after I decided I would not continue the hike, I would stare out at the mountains and daydream about being on the trail. Even now, weeks later, when I see a tree covered mountain I think to myself how great it would be hiking up and over the summit. But a thru hike wasn’t meant to be for me this year.</p>

<h2 id='whats_next'>What’s Next</h2>

<p>This is not it for me and the Long Trail though. I’m planning to complete my hike next year, and I hope to re-attempt a thru hike again the following year. Also, I want to write up a blog post about my experience hiking the first 90 miles of the Long Trail from the Canadian border to Jonesville, Vermont. I hope to do this within the next week or so, but I also need to finish writing the second edition of my iPad book. Time will tell if I actually write the blog post. Meanwhile, enjoy the <a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Hikes/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-2012/25322189_WRGQQ7'>pictures</a> I took during my journey.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weighing In]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/21/weighing-in/"/>
    <published>2012-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/21/weighing-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to weigh every item going with me on my end-to-end hike of the Long Trail. I&#8217;m unfortunately carrying about 5 pounds more than I was hoping, but I remind myself this is a month long hike, not a 3 to 5 day trip. I can do without some gear, such as the Solio charger, on shorter trips.</p>

<p>Here are the final weigh-in numbers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Base pack weight: 24.45 pounds</li>
<li>Fuel: 1.62 pounds</li>
<li>Food: 11.44 pounds</li>
<li>Water: 5.71 pounds</li>
</ul>
<p>Total pack weight: 43.22 pounds</p>

<p>For the more curious, I posted my <a href='https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ai_IwjXXrirWdEZrSWh6c3YtR0Q2SmtMaUZRSWQ5cWc#gid=0'>gear list</a> and <a href='https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ai_IwjXXrirWdDVCYWozak50SV9DTzdMTGxSenpUbHc#gid=0'>food list</a> on Google Docs.</p>

<p>What would I do differently if I could? Update some gear, specifically my backpack and sleeping bag. Updating these two items could shave off as much as 2 pounds from the base pack weight.</p>

<p>I could also go without the fitbit, Solio charger, iPhone, and cables, but I really want to track my steps, have a way to call someone if an emergency happens, and keep charged up while on the trail. Still, a little weight could be saved by leaving these items at home.</p>

<p>I could also leave the Long Trail Guide book behind, but it might prove useful while out on the trail.</p>

<p>Well, it is what it is, and a base pack weight of 24.45 isn&#8217;t too bad. It&#8217;s not great, but it will do. It is, after all, a month long hike.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pack Unpack Repeat]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/18/pack-unpack-repeat/"/>
    <published>2012-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/18/pack-unpack-repeat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Random/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-Prep-2012/Packing-Practice/24840367_jkVX9C'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Random/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-Prep-2012/Packing-Practice/i-9cwLz2t/0/Th/IMG0180-Th.jpg' /></a> With only 5 days left before I start my hike, I spent the day packing and unpacking my backpack. To my surprise, every thing fit. But also to my surprise, the unofficial total weight is 45 pounds. This includes food and water. I was hoping my total weight would be 5 to 10 pounds less.</p>

<p>Not much I can do about it now other than to leave some gear behind. I&#8217;m planning to weigh each item on Monday, and will decide what absolutely needs to go and what can stay behind. I doubt, though, I will see much reduction of in weight. Some of my gear, such as my sleeping bag, are in desperate need of an upgrade.</p>

<p>My sleeping bag is 15 years year, and is much heavier than what I would buy today. But a new sleeping bag is not in my future anytime soon. With luck, and a change in our finical situation, I might be able to buy a lighter, better sleeping bag.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>