<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-18T22:29:24-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright (c) 2002-2015 Kirby Turner</rights>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video of Stowe, Vermont]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/video-of-stowe-vermont/"/>
    <published>2015-06-18T22:22:58-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-18T22:22:58-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/video-of-stowe-vermont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Ashley came across another video of Vermont, but this time it’s about Stowe, the town I live in. Enjoy.</p>

<div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9_Wk5j_4Uc4?color=white&amp;theme=light"></iframe></figure></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Essence Of Vermont]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/essence-of-vermont/"/>
    <published>2015-06-18T06:16:26-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-18T06:16:26-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/essence-of-vermont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s no surprise I love living in Vermont in part because it’s different from other places I have lived. And this video from Skyworks really captures parts of why I love it here.</p>

<div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UBwqn9BRWhA?color=white&amp;theme=light"></iframe></figure></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do I Need Another Twitter Account]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account/"/>
    <published>2015-06-14T23:09:24-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-14T23:09:24-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier tonight I setup a new Twitter account that tweets a link each time I publish a new post here at thecave.com. The new Twitter account is <a href="https://twitter.com/thecave_com/">@thecave_com</a>. Of course now that this is setup, I’m wondering…Do I really need a separate Twitter account, or should I just tweet the links from my <a href="https://twitter.com/kiryt/">@kirbyt</a> account?</p>

<p>I guess I will keep the two separate accounts, and I’ll retweet via @kirbyt any links that I feel might be of greater interest, which is basically what I’ve always done. So if you want to know each time a new post is published, follow @thecave_com. Otherwise just keep doing what you’ve been doing.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[thecave On Twitter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter/"/>
    <published>2015-06-14T22:31:52-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-14T22:31:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Uli <a href="https://twitter.com/uliwitness/status/600656348272001024">asked</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Do you have a Twitter feed that lets me know when you post something new?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It only took me a month, but I finally have a Twitter account for thecave. Follow <a href="https://twitter.com/thecave_com/">@thecave_com</a> on Twitter if you want to know when I post something new to this blog. And as always you can subscribe to the <a href="http://www.thecave.com/feed.xml">RSS feed</a> if you prefer feed readers over Twitter.</p>

<h2 id="the-technical-how-to">The Technical How To</h2>

<p>There are a few different ways to automate the process of posting a link on Twitter when you publish a new blog post. <a href="http://twitterfeed.com">Twitter Feed</a> is one service I tried. It is fast and easy to setup, and it includes options such as including the title, description, or title and description in the tweet. Even though Twitter Feed is a cinch to setup, I decided to go with <a href="https://ifttt.com/">If This Then That (IFTTT)</a> instead.</p>

<p>Using IFTTT create a new recipe. Select <em>Feed</em> for the trigger and <em>Twitter</em> for the action. Be sure to connect your Twitter account to the IFTTT if you have not already done so. And that’s it. Next time you make a blog post, IFTTT will update your Twitter account with the title and link to the post.</p>

<p>And thanks <a href="https://twitter.com/uliwitness">@uliwitness</a> for suggesting I do this.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building An App From Start To Finish]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish/"/>
    <published>2015-06-08T09:09:35-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-08T09:09:35-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amy Hoy wrote the first version of her book <a href="https://unicornfree.com/just-fucking-ship">Just Fucking Ship</a> in 24 hours, which is awesome. Along those same lines, <a href="https://twitter.com/_davidsmith">David Smith</a> built an app from start to finish in about 6 hours - also awesome, and he posted this video that shows the entire process.</p>

<div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rEkuRFO6xTw?color=white&amp;theme=light"></iframe></figure></div>

<p>Both of these, the book and the app, are motivating me to do more faster. I just need to stop letting excuses and fear of not being perfect get in my way.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Better To Try An Idea]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/its-better-to-try-an-idea/"/>
    <published>2015-06-08T08:54:23-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-08T08:54:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/its-better-to-try-an-idea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of my favorite quotes about shipping:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s better to try an idea and see if it works than worry too much about its potential and never ship. - <a href="https://twitter.com/_davidsmith">@_davidsmith</a></p>
</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stuck Working For Others]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/04/stuck-working-for-others/"/>
    <published>2015-06-04T16:31:38-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-06-04T16:31:38-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/04/stuck-working-for-others</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love this quote from Amy Hoy:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you only do what pays immediately, you will be stuck working for other people. Or you will be stuck doing what other people want you to do…forever.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The quote come from her talk about <a href="https://unicornfree.com/2015/be-your-own-angel-a-revenue-model-for-slow-startups?inf_contact_key=33d23f3cc326dbb9432ca21551e5c05960ba9e460978b642f3bc69a5e6171317">being your own angel investor</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where I Blog These Days]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days/"/>
    <published>2015-05-19T09:40:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-19T09:40:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve recently, and “recently” as in the last couple of years, cut back on the number of blog sites I have. I’m down to three sites now, and that seems manageable. The sites are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/">thecave.com</a><br />
  That’s this site. It’s my personal blog, and it’s where I post most often. I talk about everything from what’s going on with me personally to snowboarding to programming. The site is broken down into categories, and I have plans to publish an RSS feed for each category so readers can filter out topics they might consider noise.</li>
  <li><a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/">blog.whitepeaksoftware.com</a><br />
  This is my company blog site. The focus of this site is to talk about the company and the products I sell. Granted I’m doing a horrible job at keeping up with the posts. That’s probably one of the many reasons my stuff doesn’t sell as well as it did a few years back.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.rowanturner.net/">rowanturner.net</a><br />
  Yep, my son has his own website. But he has no interest in making posts here, so I do it for him. I usually post pictures and videos of Rowan and his friends off having fun. My mom might be the only person reading this site regularly, but that’s fine. I’ll keep posting because I like looking back on past articles and reliving fun moments with my kid.</li>
</ul>

<p>These sites each have RSS feeds, so you don’t have to remember to visit. And some day I’ll do a better job of mentioning when new posts are available on the various social networks for those who don’t want to subscribe to the feeds. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snow River At Stowe]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe/"/>
    <published>2015-05-09T11:24:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-09T11:24:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This looks like it was a lot of fun. Wish I had known about it when it happened last year. </p>

<div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wfWUHKUt-Q0?color=white&amp;theme=light"></iframe></figure></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Views Created In Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/15/views-created-in-code/"/>
    <published>2015-04-15T12:58:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-15T12:58:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/15/views-created-in-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year I posted an article that talks about why <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout/">I stopped using Interface Builder</a> in favor of writing code to create views. There are some who disagree with me, and to them I say, “To each his own.” And there are some who agree with me, but choose not to publicize it. No matter. Every programmer has tricks that make them more productive, and creating views in code just happens to be one trick that works well for me. </p>

<p>What works for me doesn’t necessarily work for others. But I have to say, I had a brief “HA!” moment when I read this comment from Peter Steinberger’s post about <a href="http://petersteinberger.com/blog/2015/researching-researchkit/">researching Apple’s research kit</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>All views are created in code. Apple uses a Storyboard for the example catalog, but that’s it. Apple uses the standard pattern of overriding <code>viewDidLoad</code> to build UI in combination with Auto Layout and the visual format language, whenever possible.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Great minds think alike.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Though I don’t override <code>viewDidLoad</code> to create my views. I usually create a view class, and I add an instance of the class to the view controller’s view in <code>loadView</code>. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No WWDC Or SF Trip]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip/"/>
    <published>2015-04-14T09:20:56-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-14T09:20:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple announced the dates for this year’s WWDC, and once again a lottery is being used to decide who gets to buy a ticket. I have no interesting is attending WWDC other than to attend the labs since I do have questions I would love to ask an Apple engineer. But it’s not worth spending $1599 on a ticket just for that. </p>

<p>Likewise, I’m struggling to justify spending the money to stay in San Francisco the week of WWDC just to hang out with friends and drink beer. Certainly reconnecting with friends and making news ones is very enjoyable, but there are cheaper ways for me to do that. So I’ve decided I’m not going to SF for this year’s WWDC. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Should Feel Guilty But I Don't]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/13/i-should-feel-guilty-but-i-dont/"/>
    <published>2015-04-13T20:15:11-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-13T20:15:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/13/i-should-feel-guilty-but-i-dont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played hooky from work afternoon. I should feel guilty but I don’t. </p>

<p>I picked up Rowan from school this afternoon, and we headed to the mountain. Unfortunately I forgot his skis boots, so we had to stop by the house. Then as we tried to get on the lift I realized I left our passes in our jackets. The temperature was in the 60, so we weren’t wearing our jackets. They were still at the house. The afternoon was off to a bad start, but our luck changed. </p>

<p>We were able to get two runs in before the lifts closed thanks to the nice lifties that let us through without our passes. Also we ran into some friends in our first run, including a class mate of Rowan’s. After the lifts shut down for the day we hung out in the parking lot for a bit of après ski with friends. Then we headed to Rimrocks where we ran into more friends. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8776/16952950809_f0103c0255_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>It was a great father son afternoon with wonderful friends, and when I’m 85 years old I’ll remember how much fun Rowan and I had today. I won’t remember the work I should have done today, and that’s why I don’t feel guilty about how I spent my time this afternoon.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8722/16951598160_95cb6df7cc_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Argh! Thanks A Lot Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/10/argh-thanks-a-lot-apple/"/>
    <published>2015-04-10T03:13:14-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-10T03:13:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/10/argh-thanks-a-lot-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I woke up at 2:45 am this morning to buy a new Apple Watch. I ordered the 42mm space gray with black sport band Apple Watch Sport, but I’m still annoyed. I got a delivery date of May 13 to May 27, and that annoys me because I was ready to order at 3 am.</p>

<p>I was at my computer trying to load store.apple.com at 3 am, but the site was down. I foolishly kept refreshing the web page for 6 minutes before deciding to try the Apple Store app on my iPhone. The app worked perfectly, and thanks to Apple Pay, the order process was fast. But it was too late to get the watch I wanted in the first set of shipments, and all because I wasted my time trying to use the damn website.</p>

<p>I know, “first world problems.” All I can say is I’m grumpy when I have to use an alarm clock to wake up, and I become more grumpy when my time is wasted because of a website outage after waking up so freakin’ early.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Watch Will Make iPhone 6 Plus Size Less Annoying]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying/"/>
    <published>2015-04-06T21:42:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-06T21:42:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things that annoys me most about the size of my iPhone 6 Plus is pulling it out of my pocket while at a bar or restaurant just to see why my phone buzzed. The majority of the time my phone buzzes because of an incoming text message. I have notifications turned off for almost all other apps, and I rarely. if ever, get phone calls these days, which is why I know the buzz is most likely a text message. And if I’m at the bar without my wife, then the person trying to reach me is most likely my wife. </p>

<p>So when the text message comes in, I have to pull out this big honkin’ device out of my pocket and light up the room just to see the message. I may reply, and if I do, it’s a short reply because, after all, I’m busy at the bar. Then I put the phone back into my pocket only to repeat all of this a few minutes later. </p>

<p>Receiving text messages doesn’t annoy me, but having to pull out and put away this big device every few minutes does annoy me. </p>

<p>It occurred to me that one of the possible reasons why Apple decided to release the larger iPhones was because they knew, thanks to the Apple Watch, that there would be no reason to pull out these larger devices from pockets and purses just to check notifications and send simple text messages and replies.</p>

<p>The Apple Watch will make the iPhone 6 Plus size less annoying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best April Fools' Joke Ever]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/03/best-april-fools-joke-ever/"/>
    <published>2015-04-03T01:32:47-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-04-03T01:32:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/03/best-april-fools-joke-ever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I met a guy tonight at the bar. He was the victim of the best April Fools’ Joke ever.</p>

<p>He broke up with his girlfriend 5 weeks ago. At 8 am on April 1 she sent him a text message with a picture of a at-home pregnancy test that was positive. Yep, she was telling my new friend he was going to be a dad. 16 hours later, at midnight and after he consumed countless shots and another drinks, she sent him the text “Happy April Fools.”</p>

<p>She really got him, and he really appreciated the joke. The fact that she let him think he was going to be a new dad for 16 hours is what makes the joke really great. Had she reply “April Fools” five minutes after the first text message, the joke wouldn’t be as funny. But the fact that she made him sweat it out all day makes this the best April Fools’ joke ever. I’m just glad the joke wasn’t played on me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2600 Miles In 4 Minutes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/28/2600-miles-in-4-minutes/"/>
    <published>2015-03-28T02:36:16-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-28T02:36:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/28/2600-miles-in-4-minutes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here’s a very cool video of a guy who did a time-lapse of his Pacific Crest Trail thru hike. Enjoy. </p>

<div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xyo8OIp7aHM?color=white&amp;theme=light"></iframe></figure></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Affordable Cloud Storage With Amazon Cloud Drive]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/27/affordable-cloud-storage-with-amazon-cloud-drive/"/>
    <published>2015-03-27T06:52:45-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-27T06:52:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/27/affordable-cloud-storage-with-amazon-cloud-drive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday Amazon announced new <a href="https://www.amazon.com/clouddrive/pricing">pricing plans</a> for their cloud storage offering named <a href="https://www.amazon.com/clouddrive/home">Cloud Drive</a>. You can store unlimited number of photos for $11.99 per year, or you can store unlimited number of files for $59.99. The later is a no-brainer for me as I have been looking for an affordable cloud storage solution like this.</p>

<p>Currently I use a number of different services for cloud storage. I use <a href="https://db.tt/Y2NovyiG">Dropbox</a> to sync files between computers and devices. The files I keep on Dropbox are ones I need immediate access to. In other words, these are the files I need to have on my laptop while also having access from other computers and devices such as my iPhone. </p>

<p>I use <a href="https://secure.backblaze.com/r/00ytw8">Backblaze</a> to backup all the files on my laptop to the cloud. It’s my lifeline should something unexpected happen to my laptop. For photos I use <a href="https://secure.smugmug.com/signup?Coupon=8ZK2smzZYAS1I">SmugMug</a>, but more recently I’ve been using <a href="http://www.flickr.com">Flickr</a> more than SmugMug. And I use Rackspace Cloud File for my CDN. That’s content delivery network for my non-geeky friends reading this.</p>

<p>The problem with these different cloud storage providers is that I still had no easy way to upload and store files that I don’t need frequent access to. I don’t like to throw away data, but I also don’t need documents I wrote back in 2003 wasting space on my laptop. Dropbox has a way to not sync selected folders, but I don’t trust it. Plus, it’s not as straight forward as uploading and storing selected files.</p>

<p>Rackspace Cloud File works well for archiving my old data, but it can become costly if I have multi-terabytes of data to store. Same is true for Amazon S3, which I considered using in the past. In fact, when Amazon announced S3 Glacier I thought I had found the perfect cloud storage solution for me, but it’s not easy to use.</p>

<p>Flickr and SmugMug are great for storing photos and videos, and they both make it easy to upload new ones. Heck, Flickr will even automatically upload new photos taken on my iPhone for me. It doesn’t get much easier than that. But these two only support photos and videos, and I have other file types I want to store in the cloud.</p>

<p>So when I first heard about Amazon’s new pricing for Cloud Drive I thought, “Finally, an affordable cloud storage solution that fixes my needs for archiving old data.” At $60 per year for unlimited storage, I would be a fool not to try it out. But I don’t even need to spend the $60 right now. Amazon is offering a 3-month free trial.</p>

<p>Cloud Drive has desktop software for your Mac (and I’m guessing Windows too) to upload files, but I’m not a fan of the desktop software. It doesn’t let me pick where I want to store the files I’m uploading, and I like to use a very specific directory structure for my files. </p>

<p>While the Cloud Drive desktop software doesn’t suite my needs, the Cloud Drive web interface does. I can organize my storage area to my liking, create new folders and upload files to specific folders within the file system. And that’s just what I’ve been doing…uploading and organizing files - a few gigs so far to test out the service.</p>

<p>I do, however, have one complaint about Cloud Drive. The Cloud Drive app for iOS only shows photos and videos. I want access to all the files stored on my Cloud Drive. Hopefully Amazon will change this soon, or maybe it’s an opportunity for me to write a new app. There is, after all, an API for Cloud Drive.</p>

<p>Amazon Cloud Drive is the solution I’ve been looking for to archive my old data to the cloud. I’ll continue using external hard drives, Dropbox, Backblaze and such for backups, but my days with SmugMugs might be numbered. Still, I’m excited to finally have an affordable cloud storage solution for my old data.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dress Code For Remote Job]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/21/dress-code-for-remote-job/"/>
    <published>2015-03-21T08:27:07-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-21T08:27:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/21/dress-code-for-remote-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came across one of the silliest benefits I’ve seen for a remote developer job: casual dress code. From the job <a href="https://weworkremotely.com/jobs/1323">posting</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>What’s In It For You</p>

  <ul>
    <li>Medical and dental benefits</li>
    <li>Paid vacation and holidays</li>
    <li>Remote work environment … work where you work best</li>
    <li>Dynamic and dedicated team</li>
    <li>Data/Cell (internet) stipend</li>
    <li>Casual dress code</li>
    <li>Most of all smart and driven team members that love to collaborate, seek feedback, and improve</li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>

<p>I’m not sure I would want to work for a remote company that has a dress code even if it’s a casual dress code. I like coding in my pjs on many days, which means I would be in violation of the casual dress code. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Driver X]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/09/driver-x/"/>
    <published>2015-03-09T16:11:50-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-09T16:11:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/09/driver-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I received my new pair of Burton Driver X snowboard boots this afternoon. Damn, these puppies are stiff, but that’s a good thing. I can’t wait to hit the hill with them in the morning. It’s going to be a whole new riding experience after wearing boots that I probably should’ve replaced a couple of seasons ago.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7634/16766864701_a383cbd8cc_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Feel Guilty But]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/09/i-feel-guilty-but/"/>
    <published>2015-03-09T11:21:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-09T11:21:39-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/09/i-feel-guilty-but</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our local hill received a surprised 6-7 inches of new snow overnight. I feel a little guilty for not letting Rowan skip the first half of school this morning so he could ride the fresh powder, but at the time, he didn’t ask to skip school so he’s loss.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>