<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[thecave | Ramblings from a crotchety old man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-08T20:03:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright (c) 2003-2014 White Peak Software Inc</rights>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still Enjoying the Snow]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/08/still-enjoying-the-snow/"/>
    <published>2014-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/08/still-enjoying-the-snow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/sets/72157644571329602"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7347/14161061213_f44bfb7073_m.jpg" alt="Top of Nosedive" border="0" width="150" class="alignleft" /></a> I refuse to accept that winter is over. For instance, today I hiked up Mt. Mansfields to do a snowboard run on Nosedive. And based on the crowd, I wasn’t the only one who thought today was a good day for a hike.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/sets/72157644571329602">Here are some pictures</a> from today’s hike.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Stopped Using NIBs Thanks to Auto Layout]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout/"/>
    <published>2014-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The subject to this post might suggest I don’t like Auto Layout, but on the contrary I really like Auto Layout. I didn’t always like Auto Layout. For the longest time Auto Layout was a major pain in my ass, but it turns out it was Interface Builder that was causing me the majority of headaches when I used Auto Layout. So I stopped using Auto Layout in IB and I started using it in code only.</p>

<p>It took me a while to get comfortable with Auto Layout in code, but once things clicked, I found it easy to get the layout I wanted. In fact, I have found Auto Layout saves me time when laying out a UI, and I’ve become so comfortable with Auto Layout that now I become annoyed if I have to work on a project that does not use Auto Layout.</p>

<p>Because I use Auto Layout in code I realized overtime I was using Interface Builder only to define the UI elements that made up the view. I would define all the Auto Layout constraints in code. This got me thinking, why do I need to define the UI elements in IB? So I did a small project with no NIBs or storyboards, and I loved it. I felt more productive, and I was banging my head against the wall a hell of a lot less.</p>

<p>(Credit also goes to <a href="https://twitter.com/mattie">Matt Massicotte</a> for encouraging me to try a project with no NIB or storboard files.)</p>

<p>I’ve now done a number of iOS projects where I don’t use a single NIB or storyboard, and I’m convinced this is the right approach for me. I see everything regarding a view and its subviews explicitly defined in source code, which makes it easier to see what’s going on and to make changes. No more bouncing between inspectors to figure out what is causing a problem or to understand how a view is rendered. I see it all in the source code defined in a single <em>.m</em> file.</p>

<p>So how do I construct my views using only source code? I have a base class that I call <a href="https://github.com/kirbyt/WPSKit/blob/master/WPSKit/UIKit/WPSCompositeView.h"><code>WPSCompositeView</code></a> in my <a href="https://github.com/kirbyt/WPSKit">WPSKit</a>, a set of classes and categories I use to build apps. <code>WPSCompositeView</code> has a class method named <code>+addToSuperview:</code> that creates the instance of the view, which must be a subclass of <code>WPSCompositeView</code>, then calls <code>-loadView</code> on the instance of the view. I place all the code needed to create the subviews of the view in the <code>-loadView</code> implementation. The constraints for the view are implemented in the <code>-updateConstraints</code> that is called by iOS when needed. That’s it.</p>

<p>Here’s an example of a composer view for a new app I’m working on:</p>

<p><a href="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7204/13920896030_4c53fbfe1c_o.jpg"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7204/13920896030_e0da352daf_m.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>And the code for creating this view is as follows:</p>

<pre><code>- (void)loadView
{
  UIView *containerView = self;

  WPSTextView *textView = [[WPSTextView alloc] init];
  [textView setTranslatesAutoresizingMaskIntoConstraints:NO];
  [textView setAlwaysBounceVertical:YES];
  [textView setInputAccessoryView:[self toolbar]];
  [textView setFont:[UIFont systemFontOfSize:17.0]];
  [textView setPlaceholderText:NSLocalizedString(@"What's up?", @"Placeholder text.")];
  [self setTextView:textView];

  UIButton *locationButton = [UIButton buttonWithType:UIButtonTypeCustom];
  [locationButton setTranslatesAutoresizingMaskIntoConstraints:NO];
  [locationButton setImage:[UIImage wps_imageNamed:@"location" withMaskColor:[UIColor lightGrayColor]] forState:UIControlStateNormal];
  [locationButton setImage:[UIImage wps_imageNamed:@"location" withMaskColor:[UIColor wps_iOSDefaultBlue]] forState:UIControlStateSelected];
  [locationButton setSelected:NO];
  [locationButton addTarget:self action:@selector(_locationButtonTapped:) forControlEvents:UIControlEventTouchUpInside];
  [self setLocationButton:locationButton];

  UILabel *locationLabel = [[UILabel alloc] init];
  [locationLabel setTranslatesAutoresizingMaskIntoConstraints:NO];
  [locationLabel setTextColor:[UIColor lightGrayColor]];
  [locationLabel setTextAlignment:NSTextAlignmentLeft];
  [locationLabel setText:NSLocalizedString(@"Location Disabled", @"Location text.")];
  [self setLocationLabel:locationLabel];

  UILabel *characterCountLabel = [[UILabel alloc] init];
  [characterCountLabel setTranslatesAutoresizingMaskIntoConstraints:NO];
  [characterCountLabel setTextColor:[UIColor lightGrayColor]];
  [characterCountLabel setTextAlignment:NSTextAlignmentRight];
  [self setCharacterCountLabel:characterCountLabel];

  [containerView addSubview:textView];
  [containerView addSubview:locationButton];
  [containerView addSubview:locationLabel];
  [containerView addSubview:characterCountLabel];

  [textView wps_setDidChange:^(UITextView *aTextView) {
    NSString *countString = nil;
    NSUInteger length = [[aTextView text] length];
    if (length &gt; 0) {
      countString = [NSString stringWithFormat:@"%lu", (unsigned long)length];
    }
    [characterCountLabel setText:countString];
  }];
}

- (void)updateConstraints
{
  WPSTextView *textView = [self textView];
  UILabel *characterCountLabel = [self characterCountLabel];
  UIButton *locationButton = [self locationButton];
  UILabel *locationLabel = [self locationLabel];

  [locationButton wps_constrainToHeight:38.0f];
  [locationButton wps_constrainToWidth:38.0f];

  NSDictionary *bindings = NSDictionaryOfVariableBindings(textView, characterCountLabel, locationButton, locationLabel);
  [self addConstraints:[NSLayoutConstraint constraintsWithVisualFormat:@"V:|-0-[textView]-4-[characterCountLabel]-0-|" options:0 metrics:nil views:bindings]];
  [self addConstraints:[NSLayoutConstraint constraintsWithVisualFormat:@"H:|-0-[textView]-0-|" options:0 metrics:nil views:bindings]];
  [self addConstraints:[NSLayoutConstraint constraintsWithVisualFormat:@"H:|-8-[locationButton]-[locationLabel]-[characterCountLabel]-8-|" options:0 metrics:nil views:bindings]];
  [self addConstraint:[NSLayoutConstraint constraintWithItem:locationLabel attribute:NSLayoutAttributeBaseline relatedBy:NSLayoutRelationEqual toItem:characterCountLabel attribute:NSLayoutAttributeBaseline multiplier:1.0 constant:0.0]];
  [self addConstraint:[NSLayoutConstraint constraintWithItem:locationButton attribute:NSLayoutAttributeCenterY relatedBy:NSLayoutRelationEqual toItem:locationLabel attribute:NSLayoutAttributeCenterY multiplier:1.0 constant:0.0]];

  [super updateConstraints];
}

- (UIToolbar *)toolbar
{
  if (_toolbar == nil) {
    CGRect screenBounds = [[UIScreen mainScreen] bounds];
    UIToolbar *toolbar = [[UIToolbar alloc] initWithFrame:CGRectMake(0, 0, screenBounds.size.width, 44)];
    [toolbar setTintAdjustmentMode:UIViewTintAdjustmentModeNormal];


    NSUserDefaults *defaults = [NSUserDefaults standardUserDefaults];
    BOOL adnOn = [defaults cp_isAdnOn];
    BOOL facebookOn = [defaults cp_isFacebookOn];
    BOOL twitterOn = [defaults cp_isTwitterOn];

    UIColor *offColor = [UIColor lightGrayColor];
    UIColor *adnColor = adnOn ? [UIColor blackColor] : offColor;
    UIColor *facebookColor = facebookOn ? [UIColor wps_facebookBlue] : offColor;
    UIColor *twitterColor = twitterOn ? [UIColor wps_twitterBlue] : offColor;

    UIBarButtonItem *cameraButton = [self buttonWithImageName:@"camera" color:[UIColor wps_iOSDefaultBlue] action:@selector(_cameraButtonTapped:)];
    [self setCameraButton:cameraButton];

    UIBarButtonItem *adnButton = [self buttonWithImageName:@"adn" color:adnColor action:@selector(_adnButtonTapped:)];
    [adnButton setTag:adnOn];
    [self setAdnOn:adnOn];
    [self setAdnButton:adnButton];

    UIBarButtonItem *facebookButton = [self buttonWithImageName:@"facebook" color:facebookColor action:@selector(_facebookButtonTapped:)];
    [facebookButton setTag:facebookOn];
    [self setFacebookOn:facebookOn];
    [self setFacebookButton:facebookButton];

    UIBarButtonItem *twitterButton = [self buttonWithImageName:@"twitter" color:twitterColor action:@selector(_twitterButtonTapped:)];
    [twitterButton setTag:twitterOn];
    [self setTwitterOn:twitterOn];
    [self setTwitterButton:twitterButton];

    UIBarButtonItem *draftsButton = [self buttonWithImageName:@"drafts" color:[UIColor wps_iOSDefaultBlue] action:@selector(_draftsButtonTapped:)];
    [self setDraftsButton:draftsButton];

    UIBarButtonItem *flexibleButton = [[UIBarButtonItem alloc] initWithBarButtonSystemItem:UIBarButtonSystemItemFlexibleSpace target:nil action:nil];
    [toolbar setItems:@[adnButton, facebookButton, twitterButton, flexibleButton, draftsButton, cameraButton] animated:NO];

    _toolbar = toolbar;
  }
  return  _toolbar;
}
</code></pre>

<p>The only things not created or managed but this view are the navigation bar and collection view of photos. The navigation bar is provided by the <code>UINavigationController</code> used by the view controller that created this composer view. Also, the view controller uses controller containment to include the collection view of photos, which is actually managed by another view controller and custom view class.</p>

<p>Oh, I almost forgot to mention…I create the composite view in the <code>loadView</code> method implemented in the view controller. For example:</p>

<pre><code>- (void)loadView
{
  [super loadView];
  UIView *contentView = [self view];

  CPComposeView *composeView = [CPComposeView addToSuperview:contentView];
  [self setComposeView:composeView];
}
</code></pre>

<p>After I create the view I might add more layout constraints to position and size the subview as needed within the main content view. I do that in the view controller’s <code>-loadView</code> when needed.</p>

<p>So that’s it. That’s why I have stopped using NIB and storyboard files in my iOS projects. This approach might not work for others, but it certainly works for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WTF Ruby Gems]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/24/wtf-ruby-gems/"/>
    <published>2014-04-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/24/wtf-ruby-gems</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m working with a client to update one of their iOS apps. The Xcode project uses CocoaPods for dependency management. I’m not a fan of CocoaPods, but I grin and bear it when working with existing client projects.</p>

<p>Yesterday I needed to update a class, one .h file and one .m, from an open source project, so I ran <code>pod update</code> on the project. This told me I needed to update my install of CocoaPods, so I did. This in turn updated a ton of other Ruby Gems on my system. It was annoying having to go through the update process when all I needed was two files that I could have copied from github in less time, but no harm done, right? WRONG!!!</p>

<p>Today I go to publish a new blog post. I use Jekyll to convert my site to static HTML. Guess what? Yesterday’s CocoaPods update has now broken my Jekyll install, and I cannot publish the blog post I just finished writing. WTF!?</p>

<p>ALL I WANTED TO DO WAS GET THE LATEST FREAKIN’ VERSION OF TWO FILES, A .h AND .m, AND NOW I HAVE TO WASTE TIME TRYING TO FIX WHAT WAS NOT BROKEN UNTIL YESTERDAY JUST SO I CAN PUBLISH A BLOG POST.</p>

<p>This is why I don’t like using things like CocoaPods, plug-ins, and other simular widgets.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family Influence]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/24/family-influence/"/>
    <published>2014-04-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/24/family-influence</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over on ADN, Manton Reece <a href="https://alpha.app.net/manton/post/29056754">posted</a> a link to <a href="https://thedistance.com">The Distance</a>, a new online magazine about “long lasting businesses and the people behind them”. Manton’s post included this quote:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Starting a business is the easy part. Staying in business for a while is harder.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This got me thinking about <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">my own business</a>, which has been around for more than ten years. More importantly it got me thinking about the family influences in my life that unbeknownst to me, until recently, led to me working for myself. I have often shared the story about how the <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/27/woohoo-white-peak-software-is-10-years-old/">idea to start White Peak Software</a> came about, at a swim-up bar during my honeymoon, but I’ve never really talked about the family influences that helped lead me down the path of becoming a business owner. The reason for this is simple. It never occurred to me until recently.</p>

<p>My grandfather (my dad’s dad) was a successful business owner running his own lumber company for many years. My dad owned a general maintenance company. My aunt’s husband (my dad’s sister’s husband) opened <a href="http://www.jamesmiddletonjewelers.com">James Middleton Jewelers</a> back in 1955, and the store is still in business today run by my cousin Vickie.</p>

<p>Entrepreneurship was, and still is, common on my mom’s side of the family as well. My mom and her sisters opened and ran their own hair salon for a short period of time. My mom’s oldest sister’s husband ran his own accounting firm that is still in business today and still run by family members. My mom’s youngest sister, Beth and her husband Jay, owned Gary’s Ice Cream and Deli, the place of my very first “real” job, and later Mikey’s. My sister Renay’s husband has his own pressure washing company, and my grandmother, Dot, made and sold crafts.</p>

<p>I grew up surrounded by family members pursuing their own dreams and making their own destiny. Some were, and still are, successful in their business endeavors while others were not so lucky. But even the unlucky ones tried. They took the chance at running their own business. And all of this has had a huge impact on me even though I did not realized it until recently.</p>

<p>Thank you to all my family members who have influenced me directly and indirectly with their entrepreneur spirit. <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">White Peak Software</a> would not be here, and I would be living the life I live today if not for your influence.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still No Regrets]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/08/still-no-regrets/"/>
    <published>2014-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/08/still-no-regrets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I pierced my ear when I was 16 or 17 years old. I did it myself on the way to school. I stopped by my mom’s place to pick up my little sister. While my mom was busy getting my sister ready, I grabbed two ice cubes from the frig, and I used them to numb my ear lobe. Then I took a piercing ear ring, the kind with a pointy end, and shoved it through my ear lobe. It made a pop sound as it pushed through the backside of my ear lobe. I felt nothing. It was easy peasy.</p>

<p>I don’t remember if it was later than day or the next when my dad found out. Needless to say, he was not happy. In fact he was very angry with me. As he shared his disappointment with me, he told me having my ear pierced was just a fad and that I would soon regret it. Well, 30 plus years later I’m still wearing earrings and I still have no regrets.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Organizing Events]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/06/not-organizing-events/"/>
    <published>2014-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/06/not-organizing-events</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I lived in NYC I organized and ran events for computer geeks like me. It was a lot of fun, and a great way to meet new people. Then I moved to Salem, Mass, a suburb of Boston, and again I organized and ran events in Salem and Boston. And again it was a lot of fun and a great way to meet new people.</p>

<p>I now live in Stowe, Vermont, and as of right now I have zero desire to organize and run events for like-minded computer nerds. After being so involved organizing meetups and such for over 10 years, it’s nice to take a break. That said, I sometimes wish someone had a tech-focused garthering in Stowe. I wonder how long before I end up organizing something.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross Posting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/03/14/cross-posting/"/>
    <published>2014-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/03/14/cross-posting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to go back to cross posting between ADN, Twitter, and Facebook. I’m not as active as I once was on any one of these social networks, so I figured cross posting won’t cause too much noise in the streams of followers. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm Having a Bad Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/02/05/i-m-having-a-bad-day/"/>
    <published>2014-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/02/05/i-m-having-a-bad-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m having a really bad day today. First, I had to rush to get Rowan to school. He was being his normal slow self, but thankfully we made it there before the bell rang. Then I get to the hill to ride the new snow when I realized I left my snowboard gear at home. So back home I go. But I had to drive behind a plow the entire way home turning a 15 minute drive into a 25 minute drive. And now I have to drive with the stream of traffic back up the hill. </p>

<p>Don’t you just hate days like today.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 25]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/01/17/day-25/"/>
    <published>2014-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/01/17/day-25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks my 25th day snowboarding this season. While this might sound awesome, it’s fewer days than I was hoping to have by mid-January. I snowboarded 21 days up through Christmas. That means I have only snowboarded 4 days since Christmas, which is why I thought I would have more days by now.</p>

<p>There are a couple of reasons I’ve only gotten in 4 days over the last 3 weeks:</p>

<ol>
  <li>My season pass has blackout dated between December 26 and December 31. </li>
  <li>Warm temperatures and rain last week left the hill in less than ideal conditions, so I didn’t go out.</li>
</ol>

<p>Thankfully winter has returned to Stowe, and I’ve been able to hit the slopes again. And with more snow in the forecast I’m hoping to see my day count increase more rapidly in the coming weeks.</p>

<p>Oh, and just to be clear my days on the hill are not full days like you would do when on vacation. I still have a <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">job</a> and I have to work. So when I go out for a day in Stowe it’s usually only for an hour and a half to two hours. I might do longer days when snowboarding with Rowan and Melanie, but in general my days on the slope are the equivalent to someone else going to the gym or running or doing some other form of regular exercise.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Send Camera Video to Your TV]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/20/send-your-camera-video-to-your-tv/"/>
    <published>2013-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/20/send-your-camera-video-to-your-tv</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Believe it or not, I finally released a new app for iOS. It’s my first new app for <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">White Peak Software</a> in more than 2 years. Somewhere along the way over the last two years I lost my way, but I’m back. </p>

<p>So what’s this new app? It’s <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/big-screen">Big Screen</a>.</p>

<p>Big Screen lets you view the video from your iPhone or iPad’s camera on your TV. It requires an AppleTV, or other AirPlay receiver. Sure, you can use the built-in iOS 7 camera app to do the same, but you will see the app’s chrome on the TV. With Big Screen, there is no chrome or any other evidence that the app is being used. This makes Big Screen ideal for presentation, conferences, and other events where large screen TVs are used to let viewers in the room see the action on the stage.</p>

<p>I got the idea to write an <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/main/big-screen/why">app to display the camera’s video on a TV</a> while attending an event at Rowan’s elementary school. It just goes to show you never know when a new app idea will pop up.</p>

<p>Big Screen is a free app available now in the iOS App Store. <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/main/store/buy/big-screen">Grab a copy</a>, and let me know what you think.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rowan on the Balance Board]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/11/rowan-on-the-balance-board/"/>
    <published>2013-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/11/rowan-on-the-balance-board</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/blog/2013-11-11rowan-balanceboard.gif"><img src="/images/blog/2013-11-11rowan-balanceboard.gif" alt="Rowan on the balance board" border="0" width="150" class="alignleft" /></a> I wanted to play with a GIF animator, so I used a few photos I took yesterday of Rowan playing on the balance board. That kid is going to be so much better than me at just about everything.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whale Watching Tour]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/whale-watching-tour/"/>
    <published>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/whale-watching-tour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Around-Town/Salem-Mass/Whale-Watching-Tour"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Around-Town/Salem-Mass/Whale-Watching-Tour/i-JBK3hfx/0/Th/IMG_4272-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> Here are some <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Around-Town/Salem-Mass/Whale-Watching-Tour">pictures</a> from our recent whale watching tour out of Gloucester, MA.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pawleys Island with the Davis Clan]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/pawleys-island/"/>
    <published>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/pawleys-island</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Davis-Clan/Pawleys-Island-Summer-2013"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Davis-Clan/Pawleys-Island-Summer-2013/i-694tRP6/0/Th/IMG_4230-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> Here are <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Davis-Clan/Pawleys-Island-Summer-2013">pictures</a> from our visit to Pawleys Island. The whole Davis Clan was there for this trip.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Camp Murphy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/camp-murphy/"/>
    <published>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/camp-murphy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Camp-Murphy/Camp-Murphy-2013"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Camp-Murphy/Camp-Murphy-2013/i-XH5KmC9/0/Th/IMG_1664-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Camp-Murphy/Camp-Murphy-2013">Pictures</a> from this year’s Camp Murphy. Great time as always.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andy's Wedding]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/andys-wedding/"/>
    <published>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/26/andys-wedding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Weddings/Andys-Wedding"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Weddings/Andys-Wedding/i-G9jR27x/0/Th/IMG_1642-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> Here are <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Weddings/Andys-Wedding">pictures</a> from my brother Andy’s wedding. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Knew a Drug Dealer in Memphis]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/19/i-knew-a-drug-dealer-in-memphis/"/>
    <published>2013-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/08/19/i-knew-a-drug-dealer-in-memphis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just received a spam email saying, “A well-established company wants to offer you a telecommuting opportunity in the business of mail management.The position requires no professional skills besides basic computer literacy. The key responsibilities are to receive correspondence at your home address, repack and resend it to our customers.”</p>

<p>I knew a drug dealer in Memphis who made me a similar offer back in the 80s, but the offer included me staying for free at an apartment on the south bluff.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations to the Kid]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/20/congrats-to-the-kid/"/>
    <published>2013-06-20T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/20/congrats-to-the-kid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Rowan/Pre-school-Graduation/30095717_rX5mHW"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Rowan/Pre-school-Graduation/i-mVqV5r9/0/Th/IMG_1350%20-%20Version%202-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> A big congratulations to Rowan, aka the kid, for graduating from pre-school. He’s been at Run-a-Muck for three and a half years. Seems strange that he’s done - though officially his last day is tomorrow. I’m very proud of the kid.</p>

<p>Here are the <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Rowan/Pre-school-Graduation/30095717_rX5mHW">graduation pictures</a> for your viewing pleasure.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm an Idiot]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/18/im-an-idiot/"/>
    <published>2013-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/18/im-an-idiot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am, what I like to call certain individuals, an idiot. Yep. I too am an idiot. </p>

<p>Last week we bought a used Subaru Outback from a private seller. As with buying any car, used or new, there is a period of discovery as you learn more about your purchase. This is especially true when you buy a high mileage car. Our “new” Subaru came with 161,702 miles on it so I knew we would make all sorts of interesting, but hopefully not expensive, discoveries. I knew before buying the car it needs new tires, despite the seller insisting that the tires are in good condition. (Side note: I showed the seller what good condition tires look like by showing him the tires on our other Outback. This was a plus for us because it helped drive down the price of the car.)</p>

<p>I also knew the car needs new rear brakes, not immediately but soon. And I knew we would need to have the interior detailed to get rid of most of the dog hair and smell. No offense to dog lovers, but I can’t stand a car that smells like a dog. So de-dogifying the car was a top priority for me and another point that I raised to help drive down the price. </p>

<p>We’ve had the car for almost a week, and so far no surprises. But that changed yesterday. </p>

<p>I had our local mechanic take a look at the car yesterday to let me know what discoveries he finds. I also had the car inspected. The car passed state inspection as expected, and the mechanic didn’t find anything problems with the car that I didn’t already know about. Life is good, and I felt like we got a good deal on the car. But then, shortly after leaving the car shop the car started acting up.</p>

<p>As I was driving the car lost power. It was still running, but it wouldn’t go when I gave it gas. Then the car would take off as the transmission made hard gear shifts. My first thought was, “Oh no. There goes the transmission.” Then the check engine light came on. I continued driving the car in a stop and go pattern hoping to make it back to the car shop, which was only a couple of miles away. Next the check oil temperature light came on and started flashing. “Great!” I thought. “This car is about to totally crap out on me.” Then the car died. Luckily it cranked right up and I was able to continue my crazy drive to the car shop.</p>

<p>I made it back to the car shop, and they ran a diagnosis. The throttle sensor was acting up. Apparently there is some dirt or corrosion in or around the sensor, which is not uncommon with higher mileage Subarus. Apparently in poking around the car, the mechanic giggled a wire or something that caused the sensor to fail. It’s an easy fix and is something that doesn’t have to be addressed right away. </p>

<p>I started feeling good about the car purchase again despite this new discovery. But this morning we made another new discovery. The car battery was completely dead. “Oh great. The car has some type of electrical problem,” was my first thought. I called the mechanic and he too thought the sensor problem and the battery problem might be related. He suggested that the battery might be the source of the problem, so I replaced it with a new battery. This was something we needed to do anyways because the other battery looked old, and I wasn’t sure how much cranking power it would have this winter once we’re in chilly Vermont. (Another side note: We have had battery problems in the past in Vermont when the temperature drops below zero, so replacing the battery was already on my to do list. I was just hoping to wait a couple of months before spending the money.)</p>

<p>Because I wasn’t convinced the problem was related to the battery, I had the guy at the auto parts store check the old battery. The diagnostics showed that the battery was fine but it needed a charged. Still, I opted to buy a new battery because I knew I would be buying one soon enough, and I wanted to make sure the battery was eliminated in this guessing game of why the old battery was completely drained this morning.</p>

<p>I installed the new battery and my wife immediately pointed out that the parking lights were on. Bingo! Now I knew why the battery was dead this morning. But what I didn’t know was why the parking lights were on. Between the throttle sensor problem yesterday and the always on parking lights, I was starting to believe more and more that the car has some type of electrical problem. I drove the car to car shop to have the mechanic look at the problem. He too was baffled by this latest discovery. </p>

<p>This is our third time purchasing a high mileage Subaru. We don’t drive much, so we don’t have a need for a newer, nicer car (though my wife wouldn’t mind having a newer, nicer car). We pay cash for the older cars and drive them until they die. Our first Subaru had 193,000 miles on it when we purchased it for $1500. Our second had around 165,000 miles and we paid $3300. And our latest ride had just under 162,000 miles on it and cost us $3200. We know going into each purchase that we’ll put about a thousand dollars into the car, but after that it’s been our experience that we don’t have any major, unexpected issues with the cars as long as we follow the manufacturer’s recommended maintenance schedule. When our first Subaru started to finally have major issues, at around 215,000 miles, we sold it. And knock on wood, our second Subaru hasn’t had any major issues with it yet. But there is one thing different I did with our first two Subaru purchases that I didn’t do with our latest. I didn’t have the dealer check out the car for us.</p>

<p>This time around I had our local mechanic check out our newest Subaru. We trust our mechanic and he performs the scheduled maintenance on our other Subaru Outback. But our newest Subaru started having trouble after he looked it over. And even worse, he wasn’t sure why the parking lights were on and wouldn’t turn off. So I decided that’s is. I’m taking the car to the dealer that serviced our first Subaru and our second one up until about a year and a half ago. </p>

<p>In case you are wondering, the only reason I stopped going to the dealer was that the local shop is cheaper for regular maintenance work such as oil changes. </p>

<p>I walked into the Subaru Service Center and explained that the parking lights would not turn off and as a result I had a dead battery this morning. The gentleman behind the counter said he knew exactly what the problem is and it’s a really simple fix. He asked me to show him the car, so we walked outside to the car. He then said, “Watch this,” and proceeded to flip a switch on top of the steering column. He said, “Parking lights are off.” Switch. “Packing lights are on.” </p>

<p>Boy, I am an idiot!</p>

<p>It turns out that our local mechanic accidentally hit the parking light switch yesterday, and idiot me didn’t think to check the obvious this morning after I discovered the parking lights would not turn off. But idiot me is in good company because our local mechanic didn’t think about the switch either. Instead, we both were looking at the problem from the wrong point of view. We both were thinking the throttle sensor problem, dead battery, and parking light issue were all related when in fact they were not. It took having a third person with a fresh perspective to point out the obvious. And he was nice enough to not point out how I’m obviously an idiot.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We're Moving to a Ski Town...Finally]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/05/moving-to-a-ski-town/"/>
    <published>2013-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/05/moving-to-a-ski-town</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s official. It’s really going to happen. We’re moving to a ski town! We’re moving to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stowe,_Vermont">Stowe, Vermont</a>, in August. </p>

<p>While this isn’t really new news for most, it’s now official with the signing on a lease for a condo in Stowe and the signing of a property management agreement for our house in Salem. I’ve been talking about this move for many months, but it almost didn’t happen despite being part of a longer term plan since we left NYC.</p>

<p>Melanie and I love NYC, and living in Manhattan was definitely one of the best things either of us have ever done. But skiing - for Melanie - and snowboarding - for me - was becoming a bigger part of our lives. It may sounds strange, but I got into snowboarding while living in New York. People think of New York as a big city with tall buildings, great food, wonder entertainment, and people everywhere. But New York has something to offer everyone including snowboarding. The closest slope is Mountain Creek in New Jersey, and there are buses that run from Grand Central to Hunter and Windham mountains in the Catskills. During the winter of 2000/2001 I spent many a Saturday and or Sunday at one of these “local” mountains snowboarding. I may have never become obsessed with snowboarding if not for living in New York City.</p>

<p>Fast forward a few years, Melanie and I bought a “city car.” It was a Subaru Impreza that we paid $1500 cash for. I call it a city car because it sat in a parking lot most of the time and the body would get dinged up from other cars. But we didn’t care. The car served one purpose and one purpose only - to get us to and from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Killington,_Vermont">Killington, Vermont</a>. </p>

<p>Like many living in Manhattan, we would leave the city on the weekend during the winter. Our weekend journeys took us up to Killington, Vermont, where Melanie’s parents have a condo. We would spend the weekend snowboarding with the crowds. At the time I wasn’t bothered by the crowds like I am today. I was just happy to be out on the slopes. The problem, however, was the drive. Depending on traffic it could take us up to 7 hours to drive from the West Village to Killington. </p>

<p>Melanie and I realized priorities for us had changed since getting married, and living closer to the slopes was one of those changes. Plus the drive was starting to drive us crazy. We decided to explore for places to live in New England. Because Melanie would be working out of New York City, we knew we needed to live near an airport. And we weren’t sure how Melanie’s commute each week to JFK would be, so we settled on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salem,_Massachusetts">Salem, Massachusetts</a>, as a “temporary” place to live while she tried out life as a commuting flight attendant. The plan was: If the commute sucked we would move back to NYC, but if the commute was okay then we would start looking for a more permanent New England town closer to the slopes to call home. </p>

<p>But something distracted us from this plan. Melanie got knocked up. It was a planned knock up, but it caused more changes in our priorities. Instead of finding a new town to call home, we found a house in Salem to buy. Nesting, gotta love it.</p>

<p>Despite becoming more settled in Salem we keep snowboarding (and skiing) a priority for our family of three. Rowan has made numerous trips to the slopes over the last five years of his life, and he has become quite the good little skier. And now he is learning to snowboard. </p>

<p>Having Rowan in our lives hasn’t limited our time skiing and snowboarding. Sure, there were seasons early on were we didn’t get to hit the slopes as much as we would have liked, and we had to make compromises such as me snowboarding in the morning and Melanie skiing in the afternoon so one of us could watch the kid. But we tried hard to make sure having a kid wouldn’t distract us from our love of being on the mountain. We were also not limited to riding only the hills of New England. Rowan has joined us on trips to places such as Breckenridge, Colorado, and Ogden, Utah. But now we face another distraction that would limit our ability to play on the snow as much as we would like. </p>

<p>Rowan starts kindergarten in September.</p>

<p>Having Rowan in school five days a week will be a change for us, but not being able to pull him out of school regularly is an even bigger change. Rowan has been signed up for pre-school and daycare three days a week for years, but he doesn’t always go three days a week. Instead we take him on fun trips. While pulling him out of pre-school is okay, in fact probably better for him than being in pre-school five days week, pulling him out of kindergarten, first grade, second grade, and so on on a regular basis isn’t going to fly with school officials. And we ain’t no teachers so home skooling the kid ain’t ah option fur us. But having Rowan in school five days a week does not mean we have to cut back on our time riding magic powder, as Rowan likes to call it.</p>

<p>Knowing that Rowan is starting “real” school soon reminded Melanie and me of why we left NYC - to live closer to the slopes. Salem was supposed to be a temporary stop, but it has become more permanent especially with the purchase of our house. The fact that we might have to drive 3 hours to Killington to ride with weekend crowds (we tend to be on the mountains week days only to avoid crowds) wasn’t something I was happy about. So last year Melanie and I started talking about our original plan to move closer to the slopes and possibly live in a ski town.</p>

<p>Planning this move has been an emotional roller coaster ride. We would get excited about the possibility of living the dream only to hit rock bottom when it looked like it wasn’t going to happen. One of the biggest challenges has been finding a suitable place to live. Finding an apartment in Manhattan is a cut-throat process but at least new apartments become available daily. The same isn’t true for Stowe. There are not as many places available, and making matters worse is that many of the available rental properties, especially houses, are seasonal rentals where the owner can earn a lot of money renting out the place weekly during the winter months. </p>

<p>We were able to find apartments and condos available for long-term rental (6 to 12+ months), but most came furnished. This also bothered us. Living in a place for a year with someone else’s furniture doesn’t feel like home. The other problem was the size of most places. Unless we were willing to pay three grand or more a month in rent, we would have the settle on a 2-bedroom place. For someone who works from home this is a problem. Before we bought our house we lived in 2-bedroom apartments while I worked from home, so I can make it work. However the difference this time around is the kid. We didn’t have the kid before, but now we do. Still, it should work out since the kid will be in school five days a week.</p>

<p>So over the course of the last four months finding a place in Stowe to live has looked grim. We’re were close to giving up.</p>

<p>You are probably wondering right now why we didn’t just look for a place in one of the surround towns. There are certainly many more affordable options including houses. But we want Rowan in the Stowe public school system, which means we must be a resident of Stowe. There is an option to pay a crap load of money to get your kid into the Stowe school system, but that’s not something we can afford to do. So finding a place to live in Stowe was a must for us.</p>

<p>As I said, we were close to giving up. In fact, in my head I had already given up. I started making plans to be in Salem for at least one more year. I decided I would be in San Francisco for WWDC. I even volunteered to help with labs at AltWWDC. But as luck would have it, a large 2-bedroom condo that we liked became available in Stowe. It didn’t really become available as much as we helped it become available by sparking an idea in the condo owner’s mind.</p>

<p>In May, we placed a wanted ad in the local Stowe newspaper. The ad was simple. </p>

<p>“Family of 3, no pets, looking for a long-term (12+ months), unfurnished house for rent in the Stowe public school district. Prefer July or August move in date.”</p>

<p>I don’t remember who gave us the idea to post an ad in the local paper. I think it was my sister-in-law Brooke, so that’s who I will credit for the idea. Thanks Brooke.</p>

<p>We received only one reply from the ad. It was from a retired couple living in Stowe. The couple did not have plans to leave Stowe anytime soon, but the ad got them thinking. They knew they would leave Stowe within the next couple of years to live closer to family. They called us to chat and explore the idea of leaving Stowe sooner. Long story short, they liked us, we liked them, and their family liked the idea of them moving closer sooner than later. So last week we made it official. </p>

<p>Just two weeks ago I was resolved to the fact that we would be in Salem for at least one more year, then few days later it looked like the move was back on. Melanie even said me excitedly, “This is really going to happen.” And yes, indeed it looked like it was going to finally happen. Melanie asked me not to say anything publicly last week, which is why I couldn’t share the details of why I canceled my trip to San Fran. But now that the lease is signed and we have a move-in date, I can tell the world. </p>

<p>We move in August. For the moment we take possession of the Stowe condo on August 15. However we’re hoping we can move up the date to August 1. </p>

<p>As for our house in Salem, we’re not selling it. Instead we’re going to try our hand at being landlords. But we will be silent landlords. We’ve hired a property management company to manage the house for us. Renting our house is part of the reason we hope we can move into the Stowe condo as early as August 1. We want to make our house available for tenants looking to move in before the school year starts in Salem.</p>

<p>And as for canceling my trip to San Francisco, as well as a visit to Memphis, I decided we need to hold on to as much cash as possible. The next few months are going to be expensive, and how expensive will depend on how quickly we can rent out our house. It’s great that I work for myself, but the indie income is itself a roller coaster ride. And while I’m bummed that I will not be in SF for WWDC, I’m not bummed about getting to snowboard almost daily this upcoming winter season.</p>

<p>So that’s my big announcement and the reason plans for this summer have changed. We’re moving to a ski town to make living the dream even better.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kayaking the Ipswich River]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/02/kayaking-the-ipswitch-river/"/>
    <published>2013-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-06-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/02/kayaking-the-ipswitch-river</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Sports/Ipswich-River/29760430_PwD6W4"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Sports/Ipswitch-River/i-BBjM2Nm/0/Th/IMG_1313-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> Yesterday I did a 16 mile paddle on the Ipswich River with my buddy Shawn. It was the perfect way to spend a Saturday morning. We put in at Thunder Bridge, made our way east through the Ipswich Wildlife Sanctuary, and finally stopped in the town of Ipswich. </p>

<p>We keep a fast pace so I didn’t get a chance to take a lot of pictures, but I need sneak in a few <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Sports/Ipswich-River/29760430_PwD6W4">shots</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>