<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-03T21:42:26-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright (c) 2002-2015 Kirby Turner</rights>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Return To Whistler Blackcomb]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/03/our-return-to-whistler-blackcomb/"/>
    <published>2015-03-03T20:50:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-03T20:50:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/03/our-return-to-whistler-blackcomb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Years ago I, with help from a couple of friends, organized an annual snowboarding trip to Whistler Blackcomb. Even after the annual trips were no more, Melanie and I continued visiting Whistler once every year or two. Our last Whistler trip was in 2007, and we’ve been wanting to return for many years. But it just hasn’t worked out for us. That is until this year when we finally made our return to Whistler, and we brought Rowan with us. </p>

<p>In the same spirit as those past Whistler trips<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, I decided to write a daily blog post about our trip. But because I didn’t have a reliable Internet connection at the condo, I wasn’t able to publish the posts at the end of each day. So I combined the postings from each day into a single post that I have published them here. Enjoy.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-01-feb-23-2015">Day 0.1 (Feb 23, 2015)</h1>

<p>We started our trek to Whistler today. It’s the first time back to Whistler for Melanie and me since 2007. For those who might not know, Whistler was like a second home mountain for me for a while. I even had a season pass there one year. But we haven’t been back since Rowan was born. </p>

<p>Our day began with a 4 hour car drive to Boston. The Delta flights out of Burlington were full, so we had to fly out of Logan. We flew to Minneapolis St. Paul for our first leg of the trek. We stayed overnight before continuing on to Vancouver the next morning. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8618/16710139785_725dfcca0f_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="weather">Weather</h2>

<p>Recently I’ve been joking that our vacation in Whistler will feel more like a spring vacation than a winter one. As I type this the current temperature in Stowe is -27°F and 36°F in Whistler. That’s a 63°F temperature difference. Makes me think I should have packed a pair of shorts. </p>

<p>The weather in Whistler has been less than ideal. They haven’t received much new snow in recent weeks. And we’ve received more total snow in Stowe this season so far, 225 inches compared to the 186 inches in Whistler. On the plus side, there’s been plenty of sunshine in Whistler, which means lots of great views of the mountains. </p>

<p>Despite the lack of fresh snow and powder - 3 to 4 inches is in the forecast for tomorrow (woohoo!) - I’m sure we are going to have a great time. And Rowan is going to be amazed at the sheer size of the mountains. </p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-02-feb-24-2015">Day 0.2 (Feb 24, 2015)</h1>

<p>Our second and final leg to Whistler went smoothly. We even arrived earlier than expected giving us time to walk around the village. Rowan was tired by this point so he became a bit grouchy, but in general he was a real trooper the entire day. </p>

<p>Rowan was very excited to see how close to the gondolas we’re staying. We’re at the Executive Inn, and it’s the closest to the gondolas Melanie and I have ever stayed. We are literally a one to two minute walk to the lifts. </p>

<h2 id="a-first-for-me">A First For Me</h2>

<p>When we arrived in Vancouver we were starving. It was way past our normal lunch time thanks to the time change. The only food option for us was Tim Hortons, so we grabbed sandwiches from there. After visiting Canada for all these years - my first visit to Canada was in 1992 - it’s hard to believe this is the first time I’ve eaten at Tim Hortons. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8599/16502851387_470ba232a9_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="wheres-the-snow">Where’s The Snow</h2>

<p>The drive up the up the Sea to Sky highway was beautiful. Nothing but sunshine, which meant awesome views. But at the same time it was a bit depressing. There was no snow. Even as we arrived into Whistler, the lack of snow was obvious and not just from the sides of the road. Many trails on the lower parts of the mountains were bare, and many trails were already closed for the season. It felt more like late spring than late February. </p>

<p>I’m really curious what the upper part of the mountains will be like.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8601/16024150634_c8f88975bc_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-1-feb-25-2015">Day 1 (Feb 25, 2015)</h1>

<p>We finally hit the slopes today. After hearing about days and days of sunshine in Whistler, we get a cloudy day on the hill. And it was a bit colder than recent days. The snow was so so, about on par with the conditions during the second WASTED trip. And there was a lot more ice than I expected. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8654/16458871298_255f10c5a8_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="the-runaway-snowboard">The Runaway Snowboard</h2>

<p>The funniest part of the day happened before the first run. Outside the Roundhouse, Melanie asked me to take a picture of Rowan and her. For some reason Rowan let go of his snowboard while I took the picture. Next thing we know is his snowboard is heading down the mountain by itself. </p>

<p>I strapped on my board in hopes of catching it, but his board was heading down the hill too fast. We saw it go into a small section of woods, so I started my search for the run away board there. Thankfully I found his board jammed up between two trees. Had the board been six inches to rider’s left it would have exited the tree patch, and it might have been lost forever. We got lucky. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8629/16459039930_cef7a9d0ba_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="so-so-conditions">So So Conditions</h2>

<p>Rowan wasn’t into the conditions today. I don’t blame him. It wasn’t the best. The spring conditions from the previous day turned to hard pack when the colder temps rolled in. So we did 5 runs then called it a day.</p>

<h2 id="peak-2-peak">Peak 2 Peak</h2>

<p>The Peak 2 Peak gondola is a nice addition to the resort. We did a few runs on Whistler then jumped over the Blackcomb, something I wouldn’t consider doing before the Peak 2 Peak lift was installed.</p>

<h2 id="new-snow">New Snow</h2>

<p>Snow was falling when we left the top of the mountain. I hope it continues through the night, but I doubt it will. Still, looking forward to hitting the hill again tomorrow. </p>

<h2 id="another-disappointment">Another Disappointment</h2>

<p>The snow conditions weren’t the only disappointment today. We stopped by Longhorn Saloon for après ski and was told that kids until 21 are not allowed in after 2 pm. So no poutine for us today.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-2-feb-26-2015">Day 2 (Feb 26, 2015)</h1>

<p>Today was a bit better than yesterday. Moods were better too, which helped. </p>

<p>We rode Blackcomb in the morning, then took the Peak 2 Peak over to Whistler at lunchtime, which is where we stayed for the rest of the day. Visibility was good this morning, but very poor this afternoon after the clouds moved in. </p>

<p>We decided to wait for the glass bottom gondola on the Peak 2 Peak. Rowan and I enjoyed looking down below us. Melanie didn’t seem to care for it much. </p>

<p>While on the Whistler side, we went to the Tree Fort. Rowan had a lot of fun climbing up the fort and sliding back down. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8677/16633355726_02fd491174_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="swim-time">Swim Time</h2>

<p>Turns out the condo we rented has a heated swimming pool and hot tub, so we took Rowan swimming this afternoon, which he loved. </p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-3-feb-27-2015">Day 3 (Feb 27, 2015)</h1>

<p>I went out for a few runs before meeting up with Rowan and Melanie. Snow conditions were the same, but it was partly cloudy so we had some great views. </p>

<p>We had lunch at Longhorn since we can’t go there for après ski. The poutine there are soooo dang good. And we did a run from the top of Harmony Express to the bottom. </p>

<p>Rowan is finally over his jet lag, so we walked around the village. The new ice skating rink is nice, and Rowan wants to hit it tomorrow. The playground is all new too. Well, new since my last visit. </p>

<p>Rowan was excited to “discover” the ice rink and playground. Guess we’ll be visiting North Village more over the next couple of days. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8671/16682625426_c24c8e63fc_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-4-feb-28-2015">Day 4 (Feb 28, 2015)</h1>

<p>On Day 4 we took our time getting out to the mountain. Put quite frankly, riding hard pack day after day gets rather boring. Melanie and Rowan did a bit of shopping in the morning. When we did finally hit the hill, we did one long run down to Merlins for lunch. And of course we had to order the Nacho Daddy even though it was way to big for the three of us. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8605/16521165420_9761b71774_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After lunch we headed back up Blackcomb and did a few more runs. There wasn’t a cloud in the sky so we had plenty of incredible views. We rode 7th Heaven at the end of the day, and got last chair there twice - we were prepared to hike out but the lifties let us back on for one more ride up. We rode from the top of 7th Heaven down to Whistler Village to finish up our day on the mountain. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8582/16501194227_eac6f20595_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Afterwards we went to the swimming pool and hot tub. I stayed out of both opting to throw a ball from the side of the pool to Rowan who was playing in the pool. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8626/16501199847_3520680d7f_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Later in the evening we went ice skating, which I suck at, Rowan’s getting better at skating, and Melanie was the best of us three. The ice rink in the village is really nice. It’s outdoors and has a small hockey play area in the center. It’s also free to skate if you have your own skates, or $5 to rent a pair. Melanie wasn’t overly excited at first about ice skating, but when it was over she said she’s glad we did it and that she had a lot of fun skating. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8665/16708483725_ef98a3f1a3_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-5-mar-1-2015">Day 5 (Mar 1, 2015)</h1>

<p>Today was our final day on the hill. We took it easy today since the snow conditions were unchanged - still hard packed. We slept in this morning. When we did finally hit the slopes we did a warm up run then we headed straight for the Peak Chair and the top of Whistler. We rode back down to the village where we had lunch at Dubh Linn Gate. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8593/16088539943_c88384e301_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After lunch we headed back up to the Roundhouse so Melanie could shop for a shirt. Then we took the Peak 2 Peak gondola over to Blackcomb. Rowan wanted to play at the castle one last time. Unfortunately it was closed by the time we got there, so we made our way back down to the village. </p>

<p>When we got back to the condo, Rowan said he soooo tired. Melanie suggested relaxing at the condo for a bit, but he would have none of that. He wanted to go swimming, and he said the swimming pool would wake him up. So off Melanie and Rowan went while I stayed behind to shower.</p>

<p>We ended our final night in Whistler watching the Fire and Ice show. Three snowboarders and three skiers doing tricks off of a big kicker and through a ring of fire. Rowan was most excited to see the back flips. He had been wanting to see someone do a back flip since the start of the trip, and he got to see a number of them at the show including a one legged back flip on a snowboard (the rider’s back foot was unstrapped).</p>

<p>It’s been a great week in Whistler despite the lack of fresh snow. We all had a great time, and more importantly Rowan wants to come back. In fact, he says he doesn’t want to leave. So we’ll be back in a couple of years hopefully when the snow conditions are better. </p>

<hr />

<h1 id="the-trek-home-mar-2-2015">The Trek Home (Mar 2, 2015)</h1>

<p>The trek home was a long one. We packed up and left Whistler around 9 am Pacific time, and arrive back home in Vermont at 3:30 am Eastern. It was a long trek home, but all three of us were glad to be home. And it was nice to see a fresh 3 inches of snow on the ground. </p>

<p>For more photos from our trip, take a look at the <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/sets/72157650745528988/">complete photo album</a>.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Here are links to the daily postings I did for WASTED II, which was held in February 2003. The snow conditions that year were very similar to the conditions this year.</p>

      <ul>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/01/day-0-the-commute-begins/">Day 0</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/02/day-1-the-arrival/">Day 1</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/03/day-2-a-hundred-and-ten-percent/">Day 2</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/04/day-3-birthday-fondue/">Day 3</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/05/wasted-ii-day-4-bowl-of-sweetness/">Day 4</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/06/wasted-ii-day-5-park-fun/">Day 5</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/07/wasted-ii-day-6-return-to-blackcomb/">Day 6</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/08/wasted-ii-day-7-the-brotherhood/">Day 7</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/09/wasted-ii-day-8-beer-xbox-and-more-beer/">Day 8</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/13/wasted-ii-day-9-10-11-and-12-catch-up/">Day 9, 10, 11 and 12</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/16/wasted-ii-final-days-no-snow-but-still-a-great-time/">Final Days</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/16/wasted-ii-im-so-glad-we-had-this-time-together/">Conclusion</a></li>
      </ul>
      <p><a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raw Denim]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/raw-denim/"/>
    <published>2015-02-21T23:13:25-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-21T23:13:25-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/raw-denim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>16 months ago I bought my first pair of raw denim, a pair of Levi’s 501 Shrink to Fit, and I’m lovin’ the look.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8610/16578344836_a0c09db97c_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Startup Is Not For Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/this-startup-is-not-for-me/"/>
    <published>2015-02-21T08:27:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-21T08:27:44-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/this-startup-is-not-for-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While writing my previous post on how <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer/">working 80+ hours is not the answer</a>, I was reminded of a Wall Street startup I interviewed for back in December 1999. The startup was staffed with many brilliant programmers, and I certainly would learn a lot from them. The startup was well funded, and they offered me more money than any other company had offer me. But in the end I turned down their offer.</p>

<p>While walking around the their office, I noticed most of the programmers had sleeping bags under their desks. And every one was sitting in cubes with no natural light. No one had toys on their desks, no pictures of loved ones, and no smiles on their faces. It seemed no one was having fun. </p>

<p>I turned down their offer, and in the end I accepted another offer that paid $45,000 per year less. Why? Because the company I did join had passion, and the people working there shared that passion. We were going to work hard and play hard, and in the end build something great. And we did. </p>

<p>Looking back, I know I made the right decision. Sure, an extra $45,000 would have been nice, but it’s wasn’t worth spending a year in hell.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working 80+ Hours Isn't The Answer]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer/"/>
    <published>2015-02-21T07:41:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-21T07:41:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A founder, or maybe the person is a manager type, asked on Quora, “<a href="http://www.quora.com/How-do-you-make-programmers-work-60-80-hours-per-week">How do you make programmers work 60-80 hours per week?</a>” While the question is a pathetic one, the answers that follow, especially the first one, are worth a read. And you should certainly read the answers if you happen to be one of those sad founders/manager types who wants their of programmers to work long hours. In short, if you are trying to force your programmers to work 60, 80 or more hours per week, then you are doing it wrong. </p>

<h2 id="personal-experience">Personal Experience</h2>

<p>I have first hand experience working 80+ hours per week. Heck, there were times I worked more than 100 hours in a single week at one particular startup. There were times when I would go days without going home, choosing instead to sleep in the office for an hour here and an hour there. And if I needed a change of clothes for an important meeting, I would go to the Banana Republic that was below my office to buy a change of clothes instead of going home.</p>

<p>The difference with this experience, however, was that I was never forced to put in those insane hours. No one ever asked me to work 80+ hours. I did it because I truly believed in what we were building. But I also knew what it took to be productive, and that’s why I often times made sure my team did not follow my lead. </p>

<p>I encouraged my team to work no more than 40 hours, and if I noticed someone reaching 50 hours I usually asked that person to take a break, go home, and enjoy life a bit. The work can wait. Sometimes the team member would take my suggestion and leave, other times they would not. But the choice was theirs. I never asked for more than 40 hours per week and in the end we created some amazing things in a short amount of time.</p>

<h2 id="get-to-the-point">Get To The Point</h2>

<p>So what’s my point here? My point is that you can’t force a programmer to work long hours. That person has to want to do it. There has to be a love or passion for what they are doing, otherwise it’s just work. And people max out, especially creative types, after about 32 to 40 hours of work in a single week.</p>

<h2 id="and-now">And Now</h2>

<p>I worked at a few startups putting in 60 or more hours per week, but those days are behind me. Those were fun times with lots of good memories, but I now find it’s more important to break up work with other interest. Today I’m a proponent of what I like to call underworking, or as I more often times jokingly call “being a slacker.”<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>Life’s too short to overwork yourself today in hopes you will have the time later in life for the fun things. Who knows what will happen in the future. You could be hit by a beer truck tomorrow and die. That’s why I believe you should make a point to spend more time <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing what you love</a> now. The work can wait. </p>

<h2 id="the-long-trail-and-me">The Long Trail And Me</h2>

<p>A couple of years back I did a talk on the topic of underworking at the first <a href="http://www.360intersect.com/">360intersect</a>. In it I talk about my time hiking the Long Trail and the effect it has had on me and the amount of time I spend working each week. Here’s the video for those interested in watching it and learning more about the benefits of working less.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<div class="vimeo-video"><figure><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/65740037" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure></div>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Funny how working only 32 to 40 hours a week is thought to be slacking.  <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>Sorry the first couple of minutes of the talk are missing. Someone forgot to push the record button. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For-In Loop vs Using Block]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/20/for-in-loop-vs-using-block/"/>
    <published>2015-02-20T13:17:18-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-20T13:17:18-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/20/for-in-loop-vs-using-block</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Brent Simmons talks about <a href="http://inessential.com/2015/02/19/looping_through_objects_in_an_array">for-in loops</a> in a recent post. In it he says:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>most of the time the for-in enumeration is the straightforward and less clever approach. (“Less clever” is a good thing.)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I agree with Brent. I’m a fan of the for-in syntax. It’s straightforward and easy to read. But I have to admit in recent years I’ve been using <code>enumerateObjects​UsingBlock:</code> more often than for-in loops. I’ve been favoring the block syntax because something bbum <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/25646/bbum">said on Stack Overflow</a> a while back.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><code>enumerateObjectsUsingBlock:</code> will be as fast or faster than fast enumeration (<code>for(... in ...</code>) uses the <code>NSFastEnumeration</code> support to implement enumeration). Fast enumeration requires translation from an internal representation to the representation for fast enumeration. There is overhead therein. Block-based enumeration allows the collection class to enumerate contents as quickly as the fastest traversal of the native storage format. Likely irrelevant for arrays, but it can be a huge difference for dictionaries.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>For those who don’t know who <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/25646/bbum">bbum</a> is, he’s Bill Bumgarner. He works at Apple and knows a thing or two about Cocoa. So I believe him when he says “<code>enumerateObjectsUsingBlock:</code> will be as fast or faster than fast enumeration.”</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Temperature Inversion]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/temperature-inversion/"/>
    <published>2015-02-17T11:24:30-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-17T11:24:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/temperature-inversion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seeing “temperature inversion” in the Stowe snow report this morning is music to my ears. It’s -20°F in town but a balmy 2°F at the summit. Time to ride. </p>

<p>Speaking of odd temperatures…Whistler Village is 50°F warmer than the Village of Stowe this morning. I’m starting to think our Whistler winter vacation next week will feel more like a spring break vacation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reliving The Past]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/reliving-the-past/"/>
    <published>2015-02-17T01:38:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-17T01:38:50-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/reliving-the-past</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just spent the last two hours looking through past posts here at thecave. I was writing a lot for the four or five years, and some of those old posts are actually good. But more importantly reading through those old posts gave me a chance to relive my past. </p>

<p>This makes me realize I need to post here more even if the post is short like this one. All too often I’ll post something short to Twitter or Facebook, but I need to start posting it here too. It will be great to re-read my old posts five years from now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Site Theme]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/16/new-site-theme/"/>
    <published>2015-02-16T22:53:03-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-16T22:53:03-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/16/new-site-theme</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been on a website redesign kick lately updating sites such as <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">kirbyturner.com</a> and <a href="http://www.rowanturner.net">rowanturner.net</a>. The recent update to my <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">vanity website</a> gives it a more modern look, and <a href="http://www.rowanturner.net">Rowan’s website</a> now has a clean, fresh look that focuses on the content.</p>

<p>I especially like Rowan’s new site design. It uses a responsive design site theme so it looks good on the desktop as well as on mobile devices. I also like how it has custom header images for posts, and the clean and simply layout for posts makes it easy to focus on the content in each post. I like the site design for Rowan’s website so much that I decided to use the same site theme here at thecave.</p>

<p>I couldn’t, however, use the site theme as is. thecave is a bit more involved given that it uses categories. Plus, I want to provide a complete <a href="http://www.thecave.com/archive.html">archive</a> of every post available. These are things not found on Rowan’s site, so I’ve spent the last couple of evenings tweaking the site theme to be more appropriate for thecave.com.</p>

<p>Other changes I made include adding a footer to each page that shows recent articles and a link list to other sites that I run, and adding an <a href="http://www.thecave.com/archive.html">archive</a> link to the top that gives you access to every post made here since 2002. There is also a <a href="http://www.thecave.com/categories.html">categories</a> link in the top bar for those who would rather find an article based on a category. But the change that I like the most is the rotating header images for each post. </p>

<p>The original site theme lets me pick a header image for a new post, and if I do not specify a header image then the default header image is used. This works but it felt a bit boring to me. I want to see other header images when reading through old posts, not the same one over and over. So I tweaked the theme to pick the header image, when not specified, by performing a modulus operation on the day of the month. It’s not random, but it’s also not boring. Now as you page through posts you will see different header images<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>I have more work I want to do to this site such as adding an RSS feed for each category. Actually the site has had a feed file for each category for years. I just haven’t made the URL to the category feed files obvious. But that should be easier to do now that there is a page dedicated to listing all the <a href="http://www.thecave.com/categories.html">categories</a>.</p>

<p>So there you have it…the new site theme for thecave.com. Let me know what you think<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote">2</a></sup>.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I made the same change to the theme on Rowan’s website. Now you can see more fun pictures of Rowan as you read through the posts. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>You will find links to me on various social networks such as App.net and Twitter below in the page footer. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bad Case Of Buyer's Remorse]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/13/bad-case-of-buyers-remorse/"/>
    <published>2015-02-13T07:48:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-13T07:48:47-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/13/bad-case-of-buyers-remorse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve very disappointed in my new snowboard purchase. It’s fair to say I have a bad case of buyer’s remorse. I thought I was saving a few dollars by buying online, but at the same time I felt rushed. My gut was telling me not to do it. It told me to wait. But I didn’t listen. I’ll know better next time. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7291/16512353495_71314188f0_n.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>My new board arrived yesterday, but I still cannot ride it. It’s missing the M6 hardware needed for my old bindings. Burton will send the hardware to me for free but it means going a few more days without riding the board. And if I were to buy the board today from AJ’s I would get a 25% discount and they would likely throw in the necessary hardware for my bindings for free. That said, I stopped by AJ’s to buy a pair of new bindings. </p>

<p>Why new bindings? I need something to feel good about with regards to this snowboard purchase. </p>

<p>Why feel bad? It’s not just the money. Turns out the board I bought is a Burton 2nd. This is a pre-production board. This means it has visual defects with the graphics. The board is just as good as a production board. It’s just that the graphic may or may not have blemishes. And my new board certainly has noticeable blemishes. </p>

<p>I feel a bit cheated because the site I bought the board from did not make it clear I was buying a 2nd. The product title had “Blem” at the end, but I had no idea that meant blemish. I certainly would not have bought the board had I known. </p>

<p>I thought about returning the board, but then I decided it was more trouble than it was worth. Plus it was my mistake for buying it, so I owned up to the mistake and decided to keep the board. But that’s also why I decided to buy the new bindings. I wanted something to feel good about with this entire messed up purchasing experience. And I have to say, I really like the new bindings. </p>

<p>I like the ride of the board too. I’m still getting use to it. I finally took it out for 3 run, wish I had had more time. The board feels like a craving machine. The board is a little longer than I’m use to, and I’m using a wider stance than before, but I’m sure I’m going to love this board as much if not more than my Malolo. </p>

<p>Also I learned something from the experience. Buy locally even if the price is slightly higher. Always check in-store locally for the best deals, don’t trust the website. And wait until February, or later, to buy new snowboard gear. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consider The Environmental Cost]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/06/consider-the-environmental-cost/"/>
    <published>2015-02-06T07:56:46-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-06T07:56:46-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/06/consider-the-environmental-cost</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two days ago I wrote a <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website/">post</a> about how I bought a new snowboard online because it was cheaper than buying locally, or so I thought. Turns out a local shop in Stowe was offering a 20% discount on the board I bought, but I didn’t know this at the time since that shop didn’t advertise the sale on their website. So in the end I paid a little more to buy a new snowboard from another local shop located on the other side of the country. </p>

<p>Today I read an article written by Hana Beaman about how we might want it all but we don’t need it all, see the picture below, when it hit me I was totally missed the point in my earlier post. I should have bought locally even if the price was slightly higher. I forgot about the cost on the environment.</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/B8uV-gMCcAAYfXp.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<p>Sure, I thought I was saving a few dollars by buying online, but now that snowboard must travel across the United States by truck, airplane or some sort of and combination of fuel sucking transport. Regardless the means of transport the snowboard takes to get from Oregon to Vermont, it will have a negative impact on the environment. The environmental impact would have been much lower if I had bought locally since I live only a mile or so away from the store, a store that ultimately had the better price. </p>

<p>The lesson here for me is that I need to buy locally more than I already do<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, and I need to consider more than just how much an item will cost me. I need to also consider the cost to the environment. </p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>My spending habits have changed a lot since moving to Stowe. I buy a lot more things locally, from eggs to gear. Even my Amazon purchases have dropped to a third of what they were 3 years ago. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Local Retail Stores, Update Your Website]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website/"/>
    <published>2015-02-04T13:08:21-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-04T13:08:21-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought a new Burton snowboard the other day. I ordered it online from a mom and pop shop in the Oregon. I wanted to buy locally here in Stowe but the price I paid was 10% cheaper than the price listed on the websites of local shops. Combined with the fact that I didn’t have to pay sales tax and shipping was free, I felt I was getting a great deal. Still, I would have preferred to support a local shop here in Vermont, but at least I supported a local shop in Oregon. </p>

<p>All good, right? Well…</p>

<p>My wife stopped by one of the local Stowe shops today to buy a pair of new skis. Turns out the shop has a sale going on…20% off all Burton boards! Turns out if I had bought my new board locally I would have saved more money than buying online. Plus I would have my board now instead of waiting until next week. </p>

<p>So why didn’t I buy locally given that the sale is going on? It’s because I didn’t know about the sale. Being the type of person I am, I check online before going into brick and mortar stores, and I checked the websites of the local Stowe shops before looking elsewhere. But the shop having the awesome sale did not advise the sale on their website. And because they didn’t advise the sale I ended up taking my business elsewhere.</p>

<p>What could this store have done to win my business? They could have shown the sale price on their website. And if they didn’t want to offer the sale price for online orders, then they could have advised the sale on the front page of their website. Something as simple as “20% Off All Snowboards” for in-store purchases only would have brought me into the store two days ago. And since they have the snowboard I want in stock, it would have been an easy sell. I would have been in and out of the store in under 10 minutes, and they would have a few hundred more dollars in the cash register.</p>

<p>Still, I’m happy with my purchase. With my online purchase I was able to support a locally owned, small business…granted in Oregon instead of Vermont, but that’s still better than buying from a big corporate retail chain. And while I spent more money with my online order, it was only $32 more than I would have paid locally when you add sales tax. So I didn’t lose out too much. The Stowe shop, and the state of Vermont for that matter, lost out more than I did and all because the shop didn’t update their website.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/27/finally/"/>
    <published>2015-01-27T13:54:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-27T13:54:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/27/finally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Northeast has been getting slammed with a major snow storm, but unfortunately Stowe, Vermont, is too far northwest to get the full force of the storm. I had hoped for a bit of new snow overnight, but it didn’t happen. So I waited before hitting the slopes this morning in hopes the edge of the storm would inch its way into the Stowe, but it didn’t happen. So Melanie and I hit the slopes anyways, braving the -26 degrees Fahrenheit wind chill. We got in two runs before deciding today would be a good day for a lunch date. So we left the hill, and headed for lunch in town. And then the snow finally came…guess I’ll be hitting the hill first thing tomorrow morning. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eliminating Distractions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/18/eliminating-distractions/"/>
    <published>2015-01-18T13:49:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-18T13:49:47-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/18/eliminating-distractions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dan Counsell wrote an excellent post about <a href="http://dancounsell.com/articles/removing-distractions">removing distractions</a>. In the post he talks about how he removed distractions by removing social media apps such as Twitter and Facebook from his iPhone. He’s done other things too such as reading a book instead of checking Twitter, and he started a “No Technology Day” on Saturdays, which is something I think I might start doing as well.</p>

<p>Over the last year I too have been eliminating distractions in my life by spending more of my time <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing what I love</a> and changing the way I use social networks. Changing the way I use social networks is one of the reasons I wrote my app <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>. With Cross Post I can share pictures, thoughts, and comments on Facebook, Twitter, and App.net without the worry of being distracted by those sites. Cross Post sends updates to social media sites, but it does not read the time lines or streams from those sites. Cross Post is a tool for making, not reading, micro-blog posts, hence it’s ability to help eliminate distractions. </p>

<p>I did one other thing to help me eliminate distractions. I turned off notifications on all but the most important apps on my iPhone<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>. Unlike Dan I did not remove the social media apps from my phone. I still want to be able to reply to mentions via my iPhone, which is why I left the apps installed. And in the case of Facebook, it’s the easiest way for me to get news about my family via my sister down in Mississippi, so I still check Facebook once or twice a day. But I do not receive notifications from any of the social media apps on my phone.</p>

<p>So how can you start eliminating distractions in your life. I suggest starting with Dan’s new website, <a href="http://thegreatdisconnect.info">The Great Disconnect</a>. It contains articles, videos and information about how to remove distractions by living a less connected life. Check it out because we all can benefit from being a bit less connected these days.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Examples of app that are important to me and which I still have notifications turned on are ones for my bank and credit cards. I want to make sure I’m alerted if a fraudulent charge is ever made against one of my accounts. Slack is another app that I use with notifications turned on since I use this for work purposes. Beyond that, I have notifications turned off. Oh, and in case you were wondering, I let sites like Twitter notify me of mentions via email, and I only check email a few times a day. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New kirbyturner.com Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/new-kirbyturnercom-site/"/>
    <published>2015-01-15T16:20:35-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-15T16:20:35-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/new-kirbyturnercom-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have owned the vanity domain name <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">kirbyturner.com</a> for a long time, but I didn’t anything with it after buying it. That changed back when I was writing <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">Learning iPad Programming</a>. My publisher asked that I setup a website that talks about me, so I finally put kirbyturner.com to use. Unfortunately I never liked the look of the site. I used a bland template to create the website quickly. The site was ugly, but it served its purpose. Then Justin Williams created a new “professional web site” for <a href="http://www.justinw.me">himself</a>.</p>

<p>My first thought after seeing Justin’s new site was, “Wow! That looks really nice.” My second thought was, “Man my site sucks donkey balls.” So I spent the last couple of days working on a new look for <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">kirbyturner.com</a>. I just finished the site, and I can say with 100% certainty that the new site looks much, much better than my <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/16288802435/">old site</a>. Thanks for the inspiration, Justin.</p>

<p>Take a look at the new and improved <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">kirbyturner.com</a>, and let me know what you think.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snow is White, Not Brown and Green]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/snow-is-white-not-brown-and-green/"/>
    <published>2015-01-15T13:22:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-15T13:22:07-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/snow-is-white-not-brown-and-green</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This screen shot says it all.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/16286890482"><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8571/16286890482_5fc6e96929_n.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goodbye Fitbit Ultra, Hello Fitbit One]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/14/goodbye-fitbit-ultra-hello-fitbit-one/"/>
    <published>2015-01-14T19:42:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-14T19:42:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/14/goodbye-fitbit-ultra-hello-fitbit-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On November 15, 2011, I started using my Fitbit Ultra, and after only 1157 days I have finally switched to the Fitbit One.</p>

<p>The Ultra has been an outstanding device, and it’s darn tough too. Mine has bits of plastic missing and the casing has separated on one side. And yet the thing continues working. The only problem is the button, which stopped working two days ago. That’s why I decided to upgrade. Still, the Ultra has been one of the best little devices I’ve ever owned.</p>

<p>Together the Ultra and I have taken 7,625,047 steps, climbed the equivalent of 22,711 floors, walked 3,401.97 miles, and burned 5,035,126. My Ultra was with me on my Long Trail thru hike as well as countless other hikes. It’s been with me to New York, San Francisco, Paris, Amsterdam, Montreal, and many other places. It’s the last thing I pull out of my pocket each night before bed, and the first thing I put back in my pocket after waking up. In all that time I’ve left my Ultra behind for fewer than 5 days. But as of this afternoon I’m no longer using my Ultra. I’m now using my new Fitbit One.</p>

<p>I’m excited to use the One. It certainly has features not available on the Ultra, most notably the ability to sync wirelessly over Bluetooth. The Ultra requires plugging in to sync, and often times I would go 6 or 7 days without syncing because it wasn’t convenient for me to plug in. But with the One and the option to sync via my iPhone, I will be syncing more frequently. </p>

<p>The One is smaller than the Ultra, and I have to say I’m really digging the smaller size. The display on the One is better than the Ultra too, but then again the display on my Ultra looked good when it was new. My Ultra has been through a lot and the wear and tear is showing on it. That might be why the One’s display looks much better to me right now.</p>

<p>I do have a couple of minor issues with the One. First, the wireless sync might mean I forget to charge my One as frequently as I did the Ultra. Time will tell if this is a valid concern or not for me. The other issue is that I rarely clipped my Ultra onto myself, but I did do it from time to time…mostly in the morning if I walked around the house in my boxers. I would clip the Ultra to my boxers until I put on pjs, shorts, or pants. The One comes with a clip, but since I rarely need the clip I’m not planning to use it. But there will still be those rare early mornings when I wish I could clip my One to my boxers. Maybe I’ll keep the clip on my nightstand next to my bed so it’s easy to grab when I do need it.</p>

<p>Hmmm, so it seems I don’t really have any issues with the One…at least not yet. And based on my experience with the Ultra, I don’t expect to have any issues with the One either. I’m hoping the One is as good, if not better, than the Ultra. Time will tell. I’ll try to remember to write a follow up about my One in, say, 1157 days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Plans For A Third Edition]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/08/no-plans-for-a-third-edition/"/>
    <published>2015-01-08T08:18:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-08T08:18:28-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/08/no-plans-for-a-third-edition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A number of people have recently asked if there will be a third edition of <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/">Learning iPad Programming</a>. The short answer is no, there are no plans. There are many reasons why I decided to not update the book, but a few key reasons stand out more than others.</p>

<h2 id="i-enjoy-writing-but-i-dont-love-it">I Enjoy Writing, But I Don’t Love It</h2>

<p>Writing a tech book was on my bucket list for many years, and writing has long been an interest of mine. But writing a book like Learning iPad Programming takes a lot of time. The first two editions of the book consumed most of my time and life for nearly two and a half years, and this left me feeling stressed and depressed. That’s when I came to the conclusion that my time is better spent <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing things I love</a> and cutting back on doing things that I only enjoy. </p>

<p>If I had all the time in the world, then I certainly would consider updating the book each year or two. But my time is limited, and writing apps, snowboarding, spending time with my family, and going on outdoor adventures are all things I love doing. And those things leave me with little extra time to do things I only enjoy.</p>

<h2 id="no-financial-motivation">No Financial Motivation</h2>

<p>My <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">company</a> was booming just before I started work on the first edition of Learning iPad Programming. I saw a steady increase in product revenue year after year for five straight years, and I was becoming less dependent on consulting and contract work. In other words, I was on track for making a living selling my own products. In fact, that’s partly why I agreed to write a book in the first place. In my mind the book was another product in my expanding line of diversified products. But it turns out writing a book is hard. And writing the first edition was probably one of the hardest things I’ve ever done.</p>

<p>I had never written a book before, so I ended up spending a lot of time learning how to write a book. I also tried a number of different systems to get me into the habit of writing. All of this extra time spent on learning to write, how to get pass mental blocks, how to stay motivated, how to make daily progress, even the smallest bit, took my focus away from my company. And at one point I knew the only way I would finish the book was to devote 100% of my time to it, so that’s exactly what I did. I stopped working for a few months so I could work on the book full time.</p>

<p>All the time spent away from my company resulted in lost revenue as my product sales started a downward trend and I had zero time to offset the drop in product revenue with consulting. That meant I had to start living off of borrowed money. By the time the book was done I had well over $50K in credit card debt. And while sales of the book were great<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, the royalty payments I received were not enough to pay down the debt, debt that I’m still working on paying off today. </p>

<h2 id="mistakes-and-mishandling">Mistakes and Mishandling</h2>

<p>The third and possibly the number one reason there are no plans for a third edition were the mistakes and mishandling of both editions of the book by the publisher. The publisher’s decision to release the second edition two weeks before WWDC 2013 was the final straw for me. Apple announced iOS 7 with its new look at that WWDC making the second edition obsolete only two weeks after hitting the bookstores.</p>

<p>There were other mistakes made throughout my time working with the publisher, from production problems to not completing planned projects. But it was the handling, or as I call it, the mishandling of the second edition that led to my decision to not continue updating the book. </p>

<p>If the book were self-published, then things might be different. But as it stands Learning iPad Programming is owned by the publisher, and everything other than the final manuscript is controlled by the publisher. I certainly have some say and can provide input, but I don’t really have any control once the manuscript is turned over to them. And given the past mistakes and mishandling of projects, I cannot see myself working with the same group for a third edition (my editor and her assistant excluded - they were outstanding to work with).</p>

<h1 id="there-you-have-it">There You Have It</h1>

<p>So there you have it, the main reasons there are no plans for a third edition of Learning iPad Programming. I admit it makes me rather sad when I think about it not doing new editions of the book. I poured my heart and soul into the first two editions, and I had high hopes that there would be many more editions for years to come. But at the end of the day it just not worth struggle, stress, and toll that the first two editions took on me, my family, and our financial wellbeing.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Of the millions of books available on Amazon, my book was in the top 1100 for a few months. This is an outstanding and rare achievement for a tech book, and one of my proudest moments during my career. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Checkout The New Rowan T Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/checkout-the-new-rowan-t-site/"/>
    <published>2015-01-07T13:49:49-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-07T13:49:49-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/checkout-the-new-rowan-t-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you haven’t seen it yet, be sure to checkout the new <a href="http://www.rowanturner.net">Rowan T</a> website. I moved it to Jekyll, updated it with a new site template, and I’ve starting sharing more about what’s going on with Rowan…after a two and a half year hiatus. So pop over to <a href="http://www.rowanturner.net">www.rowanturner.net</a> and see what the kid has been up to lately.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Minutes Of Writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/15-minutes-of-writing/"/>
    <published>2015-01-07T13:19:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-07T13:19:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/15-minutes-of-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend, Greg Raiz, talks about <a href="http://www.raizlabs.com/graiz/2015/01/05/better-goals-via-better-systems/">using a system to achieve goals</a>. The particular goal he wants to achieve is writing more.</p>

<p>I’ve tried using a system similar to what Greg describes, but I fail each time I try. My system, or goal as I still often call it, has been to write an hour each day. Writing an hour day, often times more, was easy when I was writing my books, but I can’t seem to get into the routine now that I’m done with book writing (for now). I realized after reading Greg’s post that I’ve been doing it wrong. </p>

<p>Greg’s plan is to write about 100 words a day, or for about 15 minutes a day, which is about the amount of time he needs to write 100 words. And that sounds like a much more reasonable system than writing for an hour a day.</p>

<p>I wish I could write for at least an hour a day, but it’s just not in me to do that right now. Sure, if I were focused on writing a book then I would have no problem writing an hour a day. In fact, I would write more. But writing a book not my focus. Writing apps is my focus. And 15 minutes a day sounds like a perfect way for me to get back into writing.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Made Some Fixes To The Blog Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/28/made-some-fixes-to-the-blog-site/"/>
    <published>2014-12-28T19:01:32-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-12-28T19:01:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/28/made-some-fixes-to-the-blog-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before doing some work today I decided to make some improvements to my blog site. I thought I would be playing with the site for only an hour or so, but instead it took most of the day. Typical when dealing with programming issues in an unfamiliar environment. </p>

<p>This site, as well as <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com">my company blog site</a>, uses <a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> to generate a static HTML version of the site that is in turned hosted on a server for your viewing pleasure. I noticed a while back that categories with embedded spaces, such as <em>cross post</em>, weren’t accessible from the categories list. The embedded space was being replaced with a dash. Also, the RSS feed was not including the time of the post, only the date. So I set out to fix these problems.</p>

<p>I started with the time problem first. I learned that Jekyll does not include the time of the post unless you include the <code>date</code> parameter in the front matter. Adding the parameter is easy enough to do, but I decided I wanted to make it even easier for me. So I created a Rakefile that has a <code>new_post</code> task. I could have used an existing Rakefile, maybe even the one from Octopress, but I decided it would be more fun to write my own. Turns out writing a Rakefile is pretty simple, and I had my <code>new_post</code> task working quickly. </p>

<p>The <code>new_post</code> task I wrote create a new markdown file for the post. The task also generates the YAML front matter for the post including the <code>date</code> parameter with the current local time. This solves my time problem in the RSS feed for new post. I thought about making a fix for older post, but I decided it wasn’t worth the effort.</p>

<p>Using the Rakefile to create a new post makes so much sense that I decided to add a <code>deploy</code> task the Rakefile. I’ve been using a shell script I wrote a few years ago to generate the Jekyll site then commit it to the <em>gh-pages</em> branch of the site’s git <a href="https://github.com/kirbyt/site-www-thecave-com">repo</a>. I thought it would be a fun exercise to re-implement this in the Rakefile. At the same time I decided to change how the files are committed to the branch. Instead of working from a single local git repo, I decided to clone the repo to a second <em>_deploy</em> directory, then copy the <em>_site</em> files to that directory. Turns out this was fairly simple to do as well. </p>

<p>With that work out of the way I turned my focus to the categories name problem. Turns out it was caused by a space replacement in the Jekyll plugin I use to generate the categories list. That was the easiest, fastest fix of the day.</p>

<p>With a smile on my face and feeling of success I decided to do one more thing. I decided to update my install of Jekyll. And this is when everything fell apart. The sense of success and feeling of being productive evaporated quickly. Long story short, turns out I had rvm and rbenv installed at the same time, and apparently having both installed at the same time causes problems when updating gems. Unfortunately it took me a long while to figure out what had happened. I didn’t realize rvm was installed, but once I did I uninstalled it. I did another update and made sure I had rbenv-gem-rehash installed. </p>

<p>All is well now. In fact, the only reason I’m writing this post is to make sure everything is working as expected. And now that I have a faster way to create new posts, I’m hoping to post here more frequently. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>