<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs</title>
    <description>The blog site for Kirby Turner, an independent software developer, where he shares tips and advice for programmers, indie devs, and solopreneurs.</description>
    <link>http://www.thecave.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.thecave.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 09:55:07 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 09:55:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Present An Alert View Using UIAlertController When You Don&#39;t Have A View Controller</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the summer I updated a number of apps to iOS 9. A common tasks for me was replacing the deprecated &lt;code&gt;UIAlertView&lt;/code&gt; with new &lt;code&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt; class. Generally this is easy to do, but there is one scenario that &lt;code&gt;UIAlertView&lt;/code&gt; handles well that &lt;code&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt; doesn’t support at all: displaying an alert view from parts of your code without a reference to the current view controller, for instance, displaying an alert view from the app delegate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to display an alert view using &lt;code&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt; from a non-UI specific class such as the app delegate is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26952061/present-uialertcontroller-from-appdelegate&quot;&gt;common problem&lt;/a&gt;, and developers have found different &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26554894/how-to-present-uialertcontroller-when-not-in-a-view-controller&quot;&gt;workarounds&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/a/30941356&quot;&gt;One particular solution&lt;/a&gt; that caught my eye was this one from agilityvision, who writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At WWDC I stopped in at one of the labs and asked an Apple Engineer this same question: “What was the best practice for displaying a UIAlertController?” And he said they had been getting this question a lot and we joked that they should have had a session on it. He said that internally Apple is creating a UIWindow with a transparent UIViewController and then presenting the UIAlertController on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got me thinking about how I would solve the problem for apps I work on. Liking the approach mentioned by the Apple Engineer, I decided to give that a try. But unlike some of the other solutions that use a category, I decided to create a new class, &lt;code&gt;WPSAlertController&lt;/code&gt;, that is a subclass of &lt;code&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt;, and provide additional convenience methods making it possible to display an alert view with a single call…like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NSString *title = ...
NSString *message = ...
[WPSAlertController presentOkayAlertWithTitle:title message:message];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or display the &lt;code&gt;localizedDescription&lt;/code&gt; from an &lt;code&gt;NSError&lt;/code&gt; object:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[WPSAlertController presentOkayAlertWithError:error];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, since &lt;code&gt;WPSAlertController&lt;/code&gt; is a subclass of &lt;code&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt;, you can create your alert the same way as you do using &lt;code&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt;. The only difference is you call &lt;code&gt;show&lt;/code&gt; to present the alert when you don’t have a view controller. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NSString *title = ...
NSString *message = ...
WPSAlertController *alertController = [WPSAlertController alertControllerWithTitle:title message:message preferredStyle:UIAlertControllerStyleAlert];
[alertController addAction:[UIAlertAction actionWithTitle:@&quot;OK&quot; style:UIAlertActionStyleDefault handler:^(UIAlertAction * _Nonnull action) {
  // Your code.
}]];

[alertController show];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can grab the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kirbyt/WPSKit/blob/master/WPSKit/UIKit/WPSAlertController.m&quot;&gt;source code for &lt;code&gt;WPSAlertController&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from my github repository and include it in your project, or use the entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kirbyt/WPSKit&quot;&gt;WPSKit.framework&lt;/a&gt; in your project if you want to use &lt;code&gt;WPSAlertController&lt;/code&gt; plus other handy classes that I use when creating iOS apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 15:46:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/28/how-to-present-an-alert-view-using-uialertcontroller-when-you-dont-have-a-view-controller/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/28/how-to-present-an-alert-view-using-uialertcontroller-when-you-dont-have-a-view-controller/</guid>
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>objective-c</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tags And Categories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing a bit of tinkering here at thecave. I realized I was using categories as if they were tags and for one simple reason. I didn’t have a way to support tags. That is, until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tag support is provided in Jekyll, but I wanted something slightly different. I want the list of tags to appear at the end of a post just like the categories have for last couple of years. I searched for different ways to support tags with Jekyll, but I didn’t find anything suiting my needs. Then it occurred to me I could tweak the category plugins I use to work with tags, so that’s exactly what I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/recurser/jekyll-plugins&quot;&gt;Jekyll category plugins&lt;/a&gt; I use come from Dave Perretter. I made copies of &lt;em&gt;category_generator.rb&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;category_list_tags.rb&lt;/em&gt; naming the new plugins &lt;em&gt;tag_generator.rb&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;tag_list_tags.rb&lt;/em&gt;. Then I replace references to &lt;code&gt;categories&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;category&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tag&lt;/code&gt; in the source code. And BAM! I now have tag support at thecave.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the source code for the plugins in my site’s github &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kirbyt/site-www-thecave-com/tree/master/_plugins&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 19:45:44 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/21/tags-and-categories/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/21/tags-and-categories/</guid>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trying Something New To Avoid Feast Or Famine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working for myself for nearly 12 years, and for the most part I love it. But there is one aspect of being an independent software developer that I could happily do without, the cycle of feast or famine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My products don’t always sell as well as I would like, so I rely on consulting work to keep my annual income at a level that allows me to provide for my family. Some years I do less consulting work than other years thanks to product sales. But other years, I must rely more on consulting to keep food on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Independent consulting work often times comes with the feast or famine cycle. Some months you have more work than you can handle, the feast, while other times you experience dry spells where you are not billing any hours, the famine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feast or famine is often times a result of not keeping a flowing pipeline of opportunities. But as a consultancy of one, keeping that pipeline flowing can be hard when you are focused on delivering a solution to a client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried different approach over the years to avoid the feast or famine cycle, and I continue trying new approaches each year. For instance, at the beginning of this year I agreed to work full time on a project for an agency. My hope was that by working with this agency, I would have a constant funnel of project work. However, the workload from the end-client was only part time at best, and since I was being paid hourly I didn’t earn nearly as much as I had planned&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. After a number of chats with the agency, I decided it was in the best interest for everyone for me to end the relationship so I could focus on projects that would get my income level back to where it was last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m trying something else new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While combing through my leads I came across a posting for &lt;a href=&quot;http://toptal.com/&quot;&gt;Toptal&lt;/a&gt;. Topal connects top freelance developers to businesses world wide looking to hire someone for a project. Now I know what many of my friends are thinking right now, this is another one of those crappy freelancer dot com, elancer, or up-something type of sites. And Toptal may in fact turn to be like those other sites. But I won’t know unless I try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the day I used guru.com to find iOS project work, and guess what? It worked and worked well. My first client iOS project came from guru, and I earned $36K off that one project. And my client became a repeat client of mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the guru site work today? In my opinion, no, it does not. But at least I tried it. And that’s what I’m &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.toptal.com/app&quot;&gt;joining Toptal&lt;/a&gt;, to try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Toptal works out for me and I’m able to reduce, or even eliminate the feast or famine cycle, then it’s a win win situation for everyone involved. And if it does not workout, well, I’m only out a couple hours of my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: After writing this post I learned more about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toptal.com/top-3-percent&quot;&gt;Toptal screening process&lt;/a&gt;. Their screening process alone separates them from the other sites mentioned in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I have since learned that in this situation I should have charged a fixed weekly or monthly rate instead of an hourly rate. This would have ensured I met my earning goals while still being available to the end-client even when the workload itself was lacking in hours. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 11:05:11 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/10/trying-something-new-to-avoid-feast-or-famine/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/10/trying-something-new-to-avoid-feast-or-famine/</guid>
        
        <category>indie life</category>
        
        
        <category>business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Upcoming Share Extension Talk At 360idev-Min</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to be one of the speakers at the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;http://min.360idev.com&quot;&gt;360idev-min&lt;/a&gt; conference in Greenville, SC. In my talk I’ll share the things you need to know about when writing a share extension for your iOS app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan to attend &lt;a href=&quot;http://min.360idev.com&quot;&gt;360idev-min&lt;/a&gt;, then use the coupon code &lt;strong&gt;SpeakerFriend&lt;/strong&gt; to save $100 when purchasing your ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let me know if you are attending so we can meet up in person.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 11:37:39 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/07/my-upcoming-share-extension-talk-at-360idev-min/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/07/my-upcoming-share-extension-talk-at-360idev-min/</guid>
        
        <category>conference</category>
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wish I Could Help But It&#39;s Not My App</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A well known global company is using some open source code I wrote in one of their apps (yay!). Like a good company, they included my name and licensing information in app’s about screen. Now I’m getting emails from one of the app’s users seeking help with the app. The person thinks I wrote the app because my name appears in the licensing section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely a first for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:37:18 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/01/wish-i-could-help-but-its-not-my-app/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/01/wish-i-could-help-but-its-not-my-app/</guid>
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>open source</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kicking Procrastination In The Ass</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I attended a video cast thingie today - I think the kids call it a webinar - hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/amyhoy&quot;&gt;Amy Hoy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexhillman&quot;&gt;Alex Hillman&lt;/a&gt; titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crowdcast.io/e/procrastination&quot;&gt;Kick Procrastination’s Ass&lt;/a&gt;. It was really good, especially the first hour. If you have some spare time, I highly recommend watching it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the keys points for me included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reasons-for-procrastinating&quot;&gt;Reasons for Procrastinating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Motivation) Lack of motivation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Destination) Not really defining a specific goal. Too vague in what you want to accomplish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Implementation) Breaking things down into small tasks, but they will be vague if the goals are vague. You need to have structure, a schedule that you stick to to over come this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-reason-for-procrastinating&quot;&gt;Other Reason for Procrastinating&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The more you care about it, the harder it is to do. You are too emotionally involved. For example, it has to be perfect and since you feel like you can’t make it perfect right now, you put it off.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get over the fantasy that you are great and your product has to be perfect. Ship it. Make mistakes. And learn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ship early. Example, ship when you only have 5 percent of the features complete. No one will know you didn’t ship the other 95 percent of features. (Note, the 5 percent must still be good and solve pains.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-points-and-thoughts-from-my-notes&quot;&gt;Other Points and Thoughts From My Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you had to ship today then what choices would you make?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t ship a time tracking system without a timer or invoicing.” Sure you can. Once you solve a pain, ship. Other features can be added later. Another example, Early versions of &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsfreckle.com&quot;&gt;Freckle&lt;/a&gt; shipped without a way to change your password. To change your password, you had to email support and have them change it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think about what can you ship this month? This week? Today?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When do you ship? When you kill one pain. Then kill another pain and ship. Rinse and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-one-of-my-favorite-points&quot;&gt;And One of My Favorite Points&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get hung up on the long term destination, think of the short term destination to get it out the door in the near term. Note: You still want to have a long term goals, but don’t let them distract/delay from shipping today&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: When Alex started &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.indyhall.org&quot;&gt;Indy Hall&lt;/a&gt;, he asked friends if they wanted to meet at the same time and same coffee shop each day. It cost him nothing and that was Indy Hall for the first year. Meeting daily at a coffee shop wasn’t his long term goal, but it was a start. (If you can’t find people to meet at the coffee shop, you’re not going to attract them to your co-working space that you are paying for.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the video. Good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 20:57:22 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/31/kicking-procrastination-in-the-ass/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/31/kicking-procrastination-in-the-ass/</guid>
        
        <category>indie life</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
        <category>business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Don&#39;t Need Motivation. You Need Good Habits</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Amy Hoy answers the question “&lt;a href=&quot;https://unicornfree.com/2013/how-do-you-stay-motivated-when-youre-not-making-any-money&quot;&gt;How do you stay motivated when you’re not making any money&lt;/a&gt;”. The post is a couple of years old, but her answer is as relevant today as it was back then. It’s not about finding and having motivation. It’s about developing good habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To paraphrase Amy, you don’t let your kids or pets starve just because you’re not motivated to feed them. You do it anyways. And that exactly what you need to do when starting or running your business, creating a new product, or doing anything that matters to you. You just need to do it even when your not motivated to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think back to the time when I was writing the first edition of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.learningipadprogramming.com&quot;&gt;Learning iPad Programming&lt;/a&gt;. I was struggling to stay motivated, and I would go long periods of time (days, weeks, months) without writing a word. I read anything and everything I could find on how to stay motivated, but those tips didn’t help me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What helped me was structuring my day so that I worked on my book at least an hour each day. I started work on the book at the same time every day, which was 9 am. Some days I only worked on it for an hour, other days I would work on it all day. It depended on how I felt. But I always worked on it for at least one hour starting at 9 am every day even when I wasn’t motivated to work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This structure got me into the habit of writing daily. And after I developed the habit, I found writing became easier for me. And I was able to ship the book. The structure worked so well, I used it again and developed the same habit (and then some&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) to ship the second edition, which I completed in a fraction of the time compared to the time spent on the first edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don’t let a lack of motivation stop you from getting things done. If you are struggling, then setup a structure that will help you develop the habits you need to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Another habit I developed while writing the second edition of my book, and one I still use today, is to listen to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/user/kirbyt/playlist/6QUgiw9WPf8qXdgnrdXGvZ&quot;&gt;Music to Write To&lt;/a&gt; playlist on Spotify. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 14:49:56 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/31/you-dont-need-motivation-you-need-good-habits/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/31/you-dont-need-motivation-you-need-good-habits/</guid>
        
        <category>indie life</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
        <category>business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Retiring My CSV Editor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I did something that I’ve been saying I will do for a long time. I retired my CSV editor, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/&quot;&gt;Killink&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first release of Killink CSV Editor was back on March 22, 2007, and over the years it has done well despite the fact that I haven’t been actively working on the app or marketing it. Killink had great potential, especially if I had followed the business advice from those smarter than me to focus on the enterprise, but I honestly lost interest in the editor after I started writing apps for Mac and iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did start work on a Mac version of Killink CSV Editor, and I have still have a semi-working version of it on my iPhone. But I struggled to create the user experience that I wanted on those two platforms. Given enough time I could have conquered the UX challenges, but I knew the market for the editor was small and spending the extra time to do what I wanted didn’t make good business sense. So the Mac and iOS versions never shipped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always found the customers of Killink CSV Editor fascinating. While we developer types view CSV as antiquated technology, these customers work with CSV files regularly. And most are business users from large, well known companies. We developer types often times forget that people around the world are using old technologies like CSV daily to do their job, and they too would like a better way to work with old tech like CSV files. Killink CSV Editor was a better way for many for a number of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It saddens me to retire Killink CSV Editor, but at the same time I feel like a burden has been lifted off my shoulders. The app is rock solid and support is minimum, but I have felt guilty for a long time about selling a software product that I know isn’t actively being worked on. And with the recent Windows 10 release, I finally decided now is the time to retire my CSV editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard many good things about Windows 10. But if I keep selling Killink to Windows users I will have no choice but to install it some day. And honestly, I don’t want to do that. I have zero interest in Windows these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do plan to continuing supporting licensed users of Killink CSV Editor, which I talk about over at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/&quot;&gt;company blog site&lt;/a&gt;. The support load is minimum, so providing ongoing support isn’t a concern for me. Killink is a native Win32 app built using Delphi. It’s rock solid and hasn’t had a serious issue that I couldn’t resolve in email in years. So I’m happy to continue answering questions about Killink and helping folks if they happen to run into a problem. That said, I’m not looking forward to the emails I’m going to receive when people try to buy a new license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I retired SMTP Diagnostics, another Windows app I sold for years, I received emails for nearly a year asking why it was no longer available and why I couldn’t make an exception this one time and sell a new license. Most of the time the people understood, but a few sent angry emails. I fully expect the same will happen with the retirement of Killink, and all I can say to those folks is sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retiring my CSV editor ends another chapter in my long software career. I’m a bit sad by this, but I’m also excited by no longer having the mental burden that came with having my editor sit untouched for such a long time while people were still buying licenses for it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 11:23:09 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/18/retiring-my-csv-editor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/18/retiring-my-csv-editor/</guid>
        
        <category>white peak software</category>
        
        <category>windows</category>
        
        
        <category>business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Wish There Was Something Better Than Meetup.Com</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a Meetup.com subscriber for years, but I hate using them. Their website isn’t very user-friendly, and I often times find their messages to be misleading and or confusing. For example during the transition of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nshappyhour.org&quot;&gt;NSHappyHour&lt;/a&gt; meetup, which had over 250 members, I tried to disable the account. Turns out that is not an option, or at least it wasn’t at the time. I learned that the account had been deleted when I went to re-enable the account a few days later. The only option was to start a new account. This meant we lost the 250+ members that has joined over the years, and we had no way of reaching out to those members to ask them to join the new meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that experience I decided I would not use Meetup.com again. But earlier this year I decided to start a new group, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apres-code.com&quot;&gt;Après Code&lt;/a&gt;, and the best way to get the word out was to start another Meetup.com meet up. Meetup did help get the word out and people have been attending the gathering each month. But I still haven’t fully leveraged Meetup.com because the web interface is still just as confusing and crappy as ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I received yet another confusing, and misleading, message from Meetup.com that will cost a member $10, and I’m once again regretting my decision to use Meetup.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently there is an option with Meetup to allow members to send a contribution. I thought this option was turned off, and according to my account settings contributions were not enabled. Yet, a member was still able to send a $10 contribution. I decided not to accept the contribution because it just seems weird to me to have someone spend me money for this meet up group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I changed my mind this morning when I received the misleading email reminding me of the contribution. The Meetup email said, “You can choose to use it toward your Organizer Subscription.” My bi-annual subscription is due in a few days and I thought, sure, why not apply the $10 to the subscription amount. Turns out it’s not that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a single click of the mouse button, I started the process of accepting the contribution, but accepting the contribution means setting up a new account with some service named WePay and linking my bank account to WePay. This is not something I’m interested in doing. I know nothing about WePay. Not only that, WePay is taking $1.50 from the $10 contribution as a processing fee. That’s 15% of the contribution, which I find ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why can’t Meetup take the contribution and apply it directly to the Organizer Subscription? It seems like a simple enough task. After all, Meetup has the ability to process online credit card payments. And in doing this, members like me would not need to sign up for yet another service, link a bank account to a service they know nothing about, and the full contribution amount can be applied instead of only 85%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I’m having to waste time contacting both Meetup and WePay requesting the member be refunded his contribution because Meetup misled me. And with my bi-annual subscription renewal coming up in a few days, I’m once agree debating whether I should continue using Meetup.com or not. I’m leaning towards not renewing, but I know if I don’t then they will delete the account and the members will be lost forever if I decide to renew later. And if I let the account expire before this contribution mess is resolved, the member who was kind enough to send the contribution will likely be out $10 and WePay will have an extra $10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether or not I renew for another 6 months or not, I will not ever use Meetup.com again for any other group in the future. The subscription is not worth the hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 07:28:35 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/17/i-wish-there-was-something-better-than-meetupcom/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/17/i-wish-there-was-something-better-than-meetupcom/</guid>
        
        
        <category>rant</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two Years Ago Today</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We moved to Stowe two years ago today. It seems like we’ve been here a lot longer, but in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 09:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/15/two-years-ago-today/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/15/two-years-ago-today/</guid>
        
        <category>family</category>
        
        <category>stowe</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
