<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man</title>
    <description>thecave.com is the blog site for Kirby Turner, an independent software developer for Mac and iOS.</description>
    <link>http://www.thecave.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.thecave.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 09:20:21 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 09:20:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building An App From Start To Finish</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Amy Hoy wrote the first version of her book &lt;a href=&quot;https://unicornfree.com/just-fucking-ship&quot;&gt;Just Fucking Ship&lt;/a&gt; in 24 hours, which is awesome. Along those same lines, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_davidsmith&quot;&gt;David Smith&lt;/a&gt; built an app from start to finish in about 6 hours - also awesome, and he posted this video that shows the entire process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rEkuRFO6xTw?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these, the book and the app, are motivating me to do more faster. I just need to stop letting excuses and fear of not being perfect get in my way.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 09:09:35 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish/</guid>
        
        
        <category>apps</category>
        
        <category>bootstrapping</category>
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>videos</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It&#39;s Better To Try An Idea</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite quotes about shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s better to try an idea and see if it works than worry too much about its potential and never ship. - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_davidsmith&quot;&gt;@_davidsmith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 08:54:23 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/its-better-to-try-an-idea/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/its-better-to-try-an-idea/</guid>
        
        
        <category>bootstrapping</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stuck Working For Others</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love this quote from Amy Hoy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you only do what pays immediately, you will be stuck working for other people. Or you will be stuck doing what other people want you to do…forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quote come from her talk about &lt;a href=&quot;https://unicornfree.com/2015/be-your-own-angel-a-revenue-model-for-slow-startups?inf_contact_key=33d23f3cc326dbb9432ca21551e5c05960ba9e460978b642f3bc69a5e6171317&quot;&gt;being your own angel investor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 16:31:38 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/04/stuck-working-for-others/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/04/stuck-working-for-others/</guid>
        
        
        <category>bootstrapping</category>
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where I Blog These Days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently, and “recently” as in the last couple of years, cut back on the number of blog sites I have. I’m down to three sites now, and that seems manageable. The sites are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/&quot;&gt;thecave.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  That’s this site. It’s my personal blog, and it’s where I post most often. I talk about everything from what’s going on with me personally to snowboarding to programming. The site is broken down into categories, and I have plans to publish an RSS feed for each category so readers can filter out topics they might consider noise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/&quot;&gt;blog.whitepeaksoftware.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  This is my company blog site. The focus of this site is to talk about the company and the products I sell. Granted I’m doing a horrible job at keeping up with the posts. That’s probably one of the many reasons my stuff doesn’t sell as well as it did a few years back.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rowanturner.net/&quot;&gt;rowanturner.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  Yep, my son has his own website. But he has no interest in making posts here, so I do it for him. I usually post pictures and videos of Rowan and his friends off having fun. My mom might be the only person reading this site regularly, but that’s fine. I’ll keep posting because I like looking back on past articles and reliving fun moments with my kid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These sites each have RSS feeds, so you don’t have to remember to visit. And some day I’ll do a better job of mentioning when new posts are available on the various social networks for those who don’t want to subscribe to the feeds. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 09:40:11 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Snow River At Stowe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This looks like it was a lot of fun. Wish I had known about it when it happened last year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wfWUHKUt-Q0?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 11:24:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe/</guid>
        
        
        <category>snowboarding</category>
        
        <category>stowe</category>
        
        <category>videos</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Views Created In Code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I posted an article that talks about why &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout/&quot;&gt;I stopped using Interface Builder&lt;/a&gt; in favor of writing code to create views. There are some who disagree with me, and to them I say, “To each his own.” And there are some who agree with me, but choose not to publicize it. No matter. Every programmer has tricks that make them more productive, and creating views in code just happens to be one trick that works well for me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What works for me doesn’t necessarily work for others. But I have to say, I had a brief “HA!” moment when I read this comment from Peter Steinberger’s post about &lt;a href=&quot;http://petersteinberger.com/blog/2015/researching-researchkit/&quot;&gt;researching Apple’s research kit&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All views are created in code. Apple uses a Storyboard for the example catalog, but that’s it. Apple uses the standard pattern of overriding &lt;code&gt;viewDidLoad&lt;/code&gt; to build UI in combination with Auto Layout and the visual format language, whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great minds think alike.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Though I don’t override &lt;code&gt;viewDidLoad&lt;/code&gt; to create my views. I usually create a view class, and I add an instance of the class to the view controller’s view in &lt;code&gt;loadView&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 12:58:45 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/15/views-created-in-code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/15/views-created-in-code/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No WWDC Or SF Trip</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple announced the dates for this year’s WWDC, and once again a lottery is being used to decide who gets to buy a ticket. I have no interesting is attending WWDC other than to attend the labs since I do have questions I would love to ask an Apple engineer. But it’s not worth spending $1599 on a ticket just for that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, I’m struggling to justify spending the money to stay in San Francisco the week of WWDC just to hang out with friends and drink beer. Certainly reconnecting with friends and making news ones is very enjoyable, but there are cheaper ways for me to do that. So I’ve decided I’m not going to SF for this year’s WWDC. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 09:20:56 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Should Feel Guilty But I Don&#39;t</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I played hooky from work afternoon. I should feel guilty but I don’t. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I picked up Rowan from school this afternoon, and we headed to the mountain. Unfortunately I forgot his skis boots, so we had to stop by the house. Then as we tried to get on the lift I realized I left our passes in our jackets. The temperature was in the 60, so we weren’t wearing our jackets. They were still at the house. The afternoon was off to a bad start, but our luck changed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were able to get two runs in before the lifts closed thanks to the nice lifties that let us through without our passes. Also we ran into some friends in our first run, including a class mate of Rowan’s. After the lifts shut down for the day we hung out in the parking lot for a bit of après ski with friends. Then we headed to Rimrocks where we ran into more friends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8776/16952950809_f0103c0255_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great father son afternoon with wonderful friends, and when I’m 85 years old I’ll remember how much fun Rowan and I had today. I won’t remember the work I should have done today, and that’s why I don’t feel guilty about how I spent my time this afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8722/16951598160_95cb6df7cc_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 20:15:11 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/13/i-should-feel-guilty-but-i-dont/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/13/i-should-feel-guilty-but-i-dont/</guid>
        
        
        <category>family</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>rowan</category>
        
        <category>snowboarding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Argh! Thanks A Lot Apple</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 2:45 am this morning to buy a new Apple Watch. I ordered the 42mm space gray with black sport band Apple Watch Sport, but I’m still annoyed. I got a delivery date of May 13 to May 27, and that annoys me because I was ready to order at 3 am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at my computer trying to load store.apple.com at 3 am, but the site was down. I foolishly kept refreshing the web page for 6 minutes before deciding to try the Apple Store app on my iPhone. The app worked perfectly, and thanks to Apple Pay, the order process was fast. But it was too late to get the watch I wanted in the first set of shipments, and all because I wasted my time trying to use the damn website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, “first world problems.” All I can say is I’m grumpy when I have to use an alarm clock to wake up, and I become more grumpy when my time is wasted because of a website outage after waking up so freakin’ early.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 03:13:14 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/10/argh-thanks-a-lot-apple/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/10/argh-thanks-a-lot-apple/</guid>
        
        
        <category>rant</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apple Watch Will Make iPhone 6 Plus Size Less Annoying</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things that annoys me most about the size of my iPhone 6 Plus is pulling it out of my pocket while at a bar or restaurant just to see why my phone buzzed. The majority of the time my phone buzzes because of an incoming text message. I have notifications turned off for almost all other apps, and I rarely. if ever, get phone calls these days, which is why I know the buzz is most likely a text message. And if I’m at the bar without my wife, then the person trying to reach me is most likely my wife. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when the text message comes in, I have to pull out this big honkin’ device out of my pocket and light up the room just to see the message. I may reply, and if I do, it’s a short reply because, after all, I’m busy at the bar. Then I put the phone back into my pocket only to repeat all of this a few minutes later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Receiving text messages doesn’t annoy me, but having to pull out and put away this big device every few minutes does annoy me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It occurred to me that one of the possible reasons why Apple decided to release the larger iPhones was because they knew, thanks to the Apple Watch, that there would be no reason to pull out these larger devices from pockets and purses just to check notifications and send simple text messages and replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apple Watch will make the iPhone 6 Plus size less annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 21:42:53 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
