<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man</title>
    <description>thecave.com is the blog site for Kirby Turner, an independent software developer for Mac and iOS.</description>
    <link>http://www.thecave.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.thecave.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 23:25:45 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 23:25:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Raw Denim</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;16 months ago I bought my first pair of raw denim, a pair of Levi’s 501 Shrink to Fit, and I’m lovin’ the look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8610/16578344836_a0c09db97c_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 23:13:25 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/raw-denim/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/raw-denim/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>random</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Startup Is Not For Me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While writing my previous post on how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer/&quot;&gt;working 80+ hours is not the answer&lt;/a&gt;, I was reminded of a Wall Street startup I interviewed for back in December 1999. The startup was staffed with many brilliant programmers, and I certainly would learn a lot from them. The startup was well funded, and they offered me more money than any other company had offer me. But in the end I turned down their offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While walking around the their office, I noticed most of the programmers had sleeping bags under their desks. And every one was sitting in cubes with no natural light. No one had toys on their desks, no pictures of loved ones, and no smiles on their faces. It seemed no one was having fun. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned down their offer, and in the end I accepted another offer that paid $45,000 per year less. Why? Because the company I did join had passion, and the people working there shared that passion. We were going to work hard and play hard, and in the end build something great. And we did. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I know I made the right decision. Sure, an extra $45,000 would have been nice, but it’s wasn’t worth spending a year in hell.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 08:27:44 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/this-startup-is-not-for-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/this-startup-is-not-for-me/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working 80+ Hours Isn&#39;t The Answer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A founder, or maybe the person is a manager type, asked on Quora, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/How-do-you-make-programmers-work-60-80-hours-per-week&quot;&gt;How do you make programmers work 60-80 hours per week?&lt;/a&gt;” While the question is a pathetic one, the answers that follow, especially the first one, are worth a read. And you should certainly read the answers if you happen to be one of those sad founders/manager types who wants their of programmers to work long hours. In short, if you are trying to force your programmers to work 60, 80 or more hours per week, then you are doing it wrong. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-experience&quot;&gt;Personal Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have first hand experience working 80+ hours per week. Heck, there were times I worked more than 100 hours in a single week at one particular startup. There were times when I would go days without going home, choosing instead to sleep in the office for an hour here and an hour there. And if I needed a change of clothes for an important meeting, I would go to the Banana Republic that was below my office to buy a change of clothes instead of going home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference with this experience, however, was that I was never forced to put in those insane hours. No one ever asked me to work 80+ hours. I did it because I truly believed in what we were building. But I also knew what it took to be productive, and that’s why I often times made sure my team did not follow my lead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encouraged my team to work no more than 40 hours, and if I noticed someone reaching 50 hours I usually asked that person to take a break, go home, and enjoy life a bit. The work can wait. Sometimes the team member would take my suggestion and leave, other times they would not. But the choice was theirs. I never asked for more than 40 hours per week and in the end we created some amazing things in a short amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-to-the-point&quot;&gt;Get To The Point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s my point here? My point is that you can’t force a programmer to work long hours. That person has to want to do it. There has to be a love or passion for what they are doing, otherwise it’s just work. And people max out, especially creative types, after about 32 to 40 hours of work in a single week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-now&quot;&gt;And Now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked at a few startups putting in 60 or more hours per week, but those days are behind me. Those were fun times with lots of good memories, but I now find it’s more important to break up work with other interest. Today I’m a proponent of what I like to call underworking, or as I more often times jokingly call “being a slacker.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life’s too short to overwork yourself today in hopes you will have the time later in life for the fun things. Who knows what will happen in the future. You could be hit by a beer truck tomorrow and die. That’s why I believe you should make a point to spend more time &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/&quot;&gt;doing what you love&lt;/a&gt; now. The work can wait. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-long-trail-and-me&quot;&gt;The Long Trail And Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years back I did a talk on the topic of underworking at the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.360intersect.com/&quot;&gt;360intersect&lt;/a&gt;. In it I talk about my time hiking the Long Trail and the effect it has had on me and the amount of time I spend working each week. Here’s the video for those interested in watching it and learning more about the benefits of working less.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;vimeo-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/65740037&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Funny how working only 32 to 40 hours a week is thought to be slacking.  &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sorry the first couple of minutes of the talk are missing. Someone forgot to push the record button. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 07:41:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>long trail</category>
        
        <category>opinion</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>videos</category>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>For-In Loop vs Using Block</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brent Simmons talks about &lt;a href=&quot;http://inessential.com/2015/02/19/looping_through_objects_in_an_array&quot;&gt;for-in loops&lt;/a&gt; in a recent post. In it he says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;most of the time the for-in enumeration is the straightforward and less clever approach. (“Less clever” is a good thing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with Brent. I’m a fan of the for-in syntax. It’s straightforward and easy to read. But I have to admit in recent years I’ve been using &lt;code&gt;enumerateObjects​UsingBlock:&lt;/code&gt; more often than for-in loops. I’ve been favoring the block syntax because something bbum &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/users/25646/bbum&quot;&gt;said on Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; a while back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;enumerateObjectsUsingBlock:&lt;/code&gt; will be as fast or faster than fast enumeration (&lt;code&gt;for(... in ...&lt;/code&gt;) uses the &lt;code&gt;NSFastEnumeration&lt;/code&gt; support to implement enumeration). Fast enumeration requires translation from an internal representation to the representation for fast enumeration. There is overhead therein. Block-based enumeration allows the collection class to enumerate contents as quickly as the fastest traversal of the native storage format. Likely irrelevant for arrays, but it can be a huge difference for dictionaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t know who &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/users/25646/bbum&quot;&gt;bbum&lt;/a&gt; is, he’s Bill Bumgarner. He works at Apple and knows a thing or two about Cocoa. So I believe him when he says “&lt;code&gt;enumerateObjectsUsingBlock:&lt;/code&gt; will be as fast or faster than fast enumeration.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 13:17:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/20/for-in-loop-vs-using-block/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/20/for-in-loop-vs-using-block/</guid>
        
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Temperature Inversion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Seeing “temperature inversion” in the Stowe snow report this morning is music to my ears. It’s -20°F in town but a balmy 2°F at the summit. Time to ride. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of odd temperatures…Whistler Village is 50°F warmer than the Village of Stowe this morning. I’m starting to think our Whistler winter vacation next week will feel more like a spring break vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 11:24:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/temperature-inversion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/temperature-inversion/</guid>
        
        
        <category>snowboarding</category>
        
        <category>stowe</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reliving The Past</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just spent the last two hours looking through past posts here at thecave. I was writing a lot for the four or five years, and some of those old posts are actually good. But more importantly reading through those old posts gave me a chance to relive my past. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes me realize I need to post here more even if the post is short like this one. All too often I’ll post something short to Twitter or Facebook, but I need to start posting it here too. It will be great to re-read my old posts five years from now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 01:38:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/reliving-the-past/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/reliving-the-past/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Site Theme</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been on a website redesign kick lately updating sites such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kirbyturner.com&quot;&gt;kirbyturner.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rowanturner.net&quot;&gt;rowanturner.net&lt;/a&gt;. The recent update to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kirbyturner.com&quot;&gt;vanity website&lt;/a&gt; gives it a more modern look, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rowanturner.net&quot;&gt;Rowan’s website&lt;/a&gt; now has a clean, fresh look that focuses on the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I especially like Rowan’s new site design. It uses a responsive design site theme so it looks good on the desktop as well as on mobile devices. I also like how it has custom header images for posts, and the clean and simply layout for posts makes it easy to focus on the content in each post. I like the site design for Rowan’s website so much that I decided to use the same site theme here at thecave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t, however, use the site theme as is. thecave is a bit more involved given that it uses categories. Plus, I want to provide a complete &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/archive.html&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; of every post available. These are things not found on Rowan’s site, so I’ve spent the last couple of evenings tweaking the site theme to be more appropriate for thecave.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other changes I made include adding a footer to each page that shows recent articles and a link list to other sites that I run, and adding an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/archive.html&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; link to the top that gives you access to every post made here since 2002. There is also a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/categories.html&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/a&gt; link in the top bar for those who would rather find an article based on a category. But the change that I like the most is the rotating header images for each post. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original site theme lets me pick a header image for a new post, and if I do not specify a header image then the default header image is used. This works but it felt a bit boring to me. I want to see other header images when reading through old posts, not the same one over and over. So I tweaked the theme to pick the header image, when not specified, by performing a modulus operation on the day of the month. It’s not random, but it’s also not boring. Now as you page through posts you will see different header images&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more work I want to do to this site such as adding an RSS feed for each category. Actually the site has had a feed file for each category for years. I just haven’t made the URL to the category feed files obvious. But that should be easier to do now that there is a page dedicated to listing all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/categories.html&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it…the new site theme for thecave.com. Let me know what you think&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I made the same change to the theme on Rowan’s website. Now you can see more fun pictures of Rowan as you read through the posts. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You will find links to me on various social networks such as App.net and Twitter below in the page footer. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 22:53:03 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/16/new-site-theme/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/16/new-site-theme/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bad Case Of Buyer&#39;s Remorse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve very disappointed in my new snowboard purchase. It’s fair to say I have a bad case of buyer’s remorse. I thought I was saving a few dollars by buying online, but at the same time I felt rushed. My gut was telling me not to do it. It told me to wait. But I didn’t listen. I’ll know better next time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7291/16512353495_71314188f0_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new board arrived yesterday, but I still cannot ride it. It’s missing the M6 hardware needed for my old bindings. Burton will send the hardware to me for free but it means going a few more days without riding the board. And if I were to buy the board today from AJ’s I would get a 25% discount and they would likely throw in the necessary hardware for my bindings for free. That said, I stopped by AJ’s to buy a pair of new bindings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why new bindings? I need something to feel good about with regards to this snowboard purchase. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why feel bad? It’s not just the money. Turns out the board I bought is a Burton 2nd. This is a pre-production board. This means it has visual defects with the graphics. The board is just as good as a production board. It’s just that the graphic may or may not have blemishes. And my new board certainly has noticeable blemishes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel a bit cheated because the site I bought the board from did not make it clear I was buying a 2nd. The product title had “Blem” at the end, but I had no idea that meant blemish. I certainly would not have bought the board had I known. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought about returning the board, but then I decided it was more trouble than it was worth. Plus it was my mistake for buying it, so I owned up to the mistake and decided to keep the board. But that’s also why I decided to buy the new bindings. I wanted something to feel good about with this entire messed up purchasing experience. And I have to say, I really like the new bindings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the ride of the board too. I’m still getting use to it. I finally took it out for 3 run, wish I had had more time. The board feels like a craving machine. The board is a little longer than I’m use to, and I’m using a wider stance than before, but I’m sure I’m going to love this board as much if not more than my Malolo. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I learned something from the experience. Buy locally even if the price is slightly higher. Always check in-store locally for the best deals, don’t trust the website. And wait until February, or later, to buy new snowboard gear. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 07:48:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/13/bad-case-of-buyers-remorse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/13/bad-case-of-buyers-remorse/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>rant</category>
        
        <category>snowboarding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Consider The Environmental Cost</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two days ago I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about how I bought a new snowboard online because it was cheaper than buying locally, or so I thought. Turns out a local shop in Stowe was offering a 20% discount on the board I bought, but I didn’t know this at the time since that shop didn’t advertise the sale on their website. So in the end I paid a little more to buy a new snowboard from another local shop located on the other side of the country. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I read an article written by Hana Beaman about how we might want it all but we don’t need it all, see the picture below, when it hit me I was totally missed the point in my earlier post. I should have bought locally even if the price was slightly higher. I forgot about the cost on the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/B8uV-gMCcAAYfXp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, I thought I was saving a few dollars by buying online, but now that snowboard must travel across the United States by truck, airplane or some sort of and combination of fuel sucking transport. Regardless the means of transport the snowboard takes to get from Oregon to Vermont, it will have a negative impact on the environment. The environmental impact would have been much lower if I had bought locally since I live only a mile or so away from the store, a store that ultimately had the better price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lesson here for me is that I need to buy locally more than I already do&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and I need to consider more than just how much an item will cost me. I need to also consider the cost to the environment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;My spending habits have changed a lot since moving to Stowe. I buy a lot more things locally, from eggs to gear. Even my Amazon purchases have dropped to a third of what they were 3 years ago. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 07:56:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/06/consider-the-environmental-cost/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/06/consider-the-environmental-cost/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>skiing</category>
        
        <category>snowboarding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hey Local Retail Stores, Update Your Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a new Burton snowboard the other day. I ordered it online from a mom and pop shop in the Oregon. I wanted to buy locally here in Stowe but the price I paid was 10% cheaper than the price listed on the websites of local shops. Combined with the fact that I didn’t have to pay sales tax and shipping was free, I felt I was getting a great deal. Still, I would have preferred to support a local shop here in Vermont, but at least I supported a local shop in Oregon. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All good, right? Well…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife stopped by one of the local Stowe shops today to buy a pair of new skis. Turns out the shop has a sale going on…20% off all Burton boards! Turns out if I had bought my new board locally I would have saved more money than buying online. Plus I would have my board now instead of waiting until next week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why didn’t I buy locally given that the sale is going on? It’s because I didn’t know about the sale. Being the type of person I am, I check online before going into brick and mortar stores, and I checked the websites of the local Stowe shops before looking elsewhere. But the shop having the awesome sale did not advise the sale on their website. And because they didn’t advise the sale I ended up taking my business elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What could this store have done to win my business? They could have shown the sale price on their website. And if they didn’t want to offer the sale price for online orders, then they could have advised the sale on the front page of their website. Something as simple as “20% Off All Snowboards” for in-store purchases only would have brought me into the store two days ago. And since they have the snowboard I want in stock, it would have been an easy sell. I would have been in and out of the store in under 10 minutes, and they would have a few hundred more dollars in the cash register.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I’m happy with my purchase. With my online purchase I was able to support a locally owned, small business…granted in Oregon instead of Vermont, but that’s still better than buying from a big corporate retail chain. And while I spent more money with my online order, it was only $32 more than I would have paid locally when you add sales tax. So I didn’t lose out too much. The Stowe shop, and the state of Vermont for that matter, lost out more than I did and all because the shop didn’t update their website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 13:08:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
        <category>rant</category>
        
        <category>skiing</category>
        
        <category>snowboarding</category>
        
        <category>stowe</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
