<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs</title>
    <description>The blog site for Kirby Turner, an independent software developer, where he shares tips and advice for programmers, indie devs, and solopreneurs.</description>
    <link>http://www.thecave.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.thecave.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 11:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 11:50:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>sample post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sample post.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 07:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/16/sample-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/16/sample-post/</guid>
        
        <category>microblog</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mastodon and thecave.social</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I first heard about &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; last week while lurking on Twitter. For those who don’t know, Mastodon is a free, open source, decentralized social network with instances run mostly by individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I read more about Mastodon, I became more intrigued. It didn’t take long before I registered the domain name &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecave.social/&quot;&gt;thecave.social&lt;/a&gt;. The idea of hosting a Mastodon instance, even if just for myself, piqued the geek in me. The realist in me said I don’t have the extra time to take on such an endeavor. Still, I wanted to learn more about Mastodon, and what better way than hosting an instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I looked at hosting my Mastodon instance on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openshift.com&quot;&gt;OpenShift Online&lt;/a&gt;. I’m a long time fan of OpenShift, but it’s been a while since I played on it. Turns out, a new OpenShift Online supporting Docker containers is in the works. Right now, the new OpenShift Online is in Developer Preview, and accounts are active for only 30 days. The time limit doesn’t work for me because I can see myself hosting my Mastodon instance for more than a month. So OpenShift is not an option for me at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at hosting the instance somewhere else, like Digital Ocean, but I decided I don’t have the time to do all the extra work. Thankfully, there is an experimental Heroku install option for Mastodon, and given that I already have some basic experience with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heroku.com&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;, I decided it is the way to go for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After deciding where to host my instance, I did a “test” install. I created a single dyno and played around with Mastodon. Liking what I saw, I scrapped the dyno and created another one, this time for thecave.social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me about four hours total to get my Mastodon instance setup and configured the way I want it. A more experienced admin could have probably done the work in half the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mailgun.com&quot;&gt;Mailgun&lt;/a&gt; for emails and &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/s3/&quot;&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt; for file storage. And now that Heroku has an automatic certificate manager that uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org&quot;&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;, acquiring and installing an SSL/TLS certificate for the site was a snap. I’m continually amazed at how easy it is to host a server these days thanks to services like Mailgun, S3, and Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecave.social/&quot;&gt;thecave.social&lt;/a&gt; has been live for a few days now, and everything is running smoothly. Of course, I am the only user on this instance, and I do not support the streaming API yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve even made a few toots on Mastodon, which is impressive for me given that I don’t spend a lot of time on social networks these days. (I’ve checked Facebook once in the last 28 days, and I lurk on Twitter only once or twice a month.) Still, I can see myself getting into Mastodon because it represents what I like about social networks, and it doesn’t have the crap that has turned me off of social networks in general, ads and political rants being the top offenders for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, registration on thecave.social is closed, though I’m considering opening it up to family and friends soon. Let me know if you are interested in having an account so I can tell you when registration is open. I can’t guarantee how long I will keep the server up and running, but I don’t see myself shutting it down anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I’m not looking to grow a big community with hundreds or even thousands of users. Instead, I want a place that is my own just like I have with my personal email address. Some family and friends have thecave.com email address, and I see the same thing happening with thecave.social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you on other Mastodon instances, feel free to follow me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecave.social/@kirby&quot;&gt;@kirby@thecave.social&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 18:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/12/mastodon-and-thecavesocial/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/12/mastodon-and-thecavesocial/</guid>
        
        <category>mastodon</category>
        
        <category>microblogging</category>
        
        <category>open source</category>
        
        <category>social</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>After 17 Days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After 17 days of no Facebook, I finally took a peek at my feed. I was totally uninterested, and I signed out after a minute. I think I’m over my Facebook addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 12:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/03/after-17-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/03/after-17-days/</guid>
        
        <category>microblog</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ain't No April Fools' Joke</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What a beautiful morning. Winter is still going strong here in Stowe. &lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/4/3754/32957940243_5ae40ae89a_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 10:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/01/aint-no-april-fools-joke/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/01/aint-no-april-fools-joke/</guid>
        
        <category>facebook</category>
        
        <category>microblog</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No Facebook for 11 Days!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been on Facebook for 11 straight days. #breakingtheaddiction&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 10:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/26/no-facebook-for-11-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/26/no-facebook-for-11-days/</guid>
        
        <category>microblog</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Love this picture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love this picture of Rowan and his cousin Sedona. Taken last weekend at Stowe Mountain Resort. &lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2813/32769104684_cec6f7e85b_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 12:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/love-this-picture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/love-this-picture/</guid>
        
        <category>microblog</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Micro blogging from thecave</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing, testing. 1, 2, 3…I moved my RSS feed for &lt;a href=&quot;http://micro.blog&quot;&gt;micro.blog&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecave.com/&quot;&gt;thecave.com&lt;/a&gt; since I’m no longer actively working on my app, Cross Post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 11:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/micro-blogging-from-thecave/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/micro-blogging-from-thecave/</guid>
        
        <category>microblog</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Experienced Programmer's Guide to Getting Started with Swift</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple Vermont-based software developers recently asked me how to get started with Swift and writing apps for iOS. I emailed them individually, but when I was asked again today, I thought, time to write a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an experienced programmer looking to get started with Swift and iOS development, I suggest starting with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/swift/resources/&quot;&gt;Apple developer guides&lt;/a&gt;. I also recommend reading the language guide, available in the iBooks Store and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/content/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/Swift_Programming_Language/index.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40014097-CH3-ID0&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;. It is a dry read, but very detailed. Besides, I still find myself referring to it from time to time, so it is on my “must read” list for those new to Swift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great place to get started is over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raywenderlich.com&quot;&gt;raywenderlich.com&lt;/a&gt;. The site contains tons of great tutorials, books, and videos. Some are free, others you pay for, but the materials are some of the best learning materials outside of Apple. Take a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raywenderlich.com/category/swift&quot;&gt;Swift category&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in game development, the book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raywenderlich.com/store/2d-ios-tvos-games-by-tutorials&quot;&gt;2D Apple Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is an awesome read. It focuses on writing iOS games using Swift 3 and SpriteKit, giving you step by step instructions. I have read half the book so far, and it has been a blast learning how to create games for iOS (even though I am not a game developer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you have an iPad, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/swift/playgrounds/&quot;&gt;Swift Playgrounds&lt;/a&gt;. It teaches you how to code, which is not something you need if you are an experienced programmer, but from what I have heard, the advance lessons can be helpful in teaching experienced programmer how to write Swift code. Also, you can experiment with all aspects of the device, from accessing the various iOS frameworks, such as SpriteKit and UIKit, to directly controlling hardware, such as the gyroscope, accelerometer, and camera. (Download the Swift Playgrounds app &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/swift-playgrounds/id908519492?mt=8&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps get you started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 16:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/02/02/the-experienced-programmers-guide-to-getting-started-with-swift/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2017/02/02/the-experienced-programmers-guide-to-getting-started-with-swift/</guid>
        
        <category>app</category>
        
        <category>getting-started</category>
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>swift</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wow! Busy weekends ahead</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend emailed me asking if I’m around in two weekends. He wants to visit me in Stowe and do a little riding together. I haven’t seen this friend in years, and it will be great to catch up ago. The problem is, I discovered I’m busy every weekend through the end of March. Turns out, when you live in a ski town, lots of people want to come for a visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you want to visit me in Stowe, and you want to ride together, it’ll have to be during the weekday or a weekend towards the end of March beginning of April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case you’re wondering, the skiing and riding in Stowe has been superb recently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 01:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/30/wow-busy-weekends-ahead/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/30/wow-busy-weekends-ahead/</guid>
        
        <category>snowboarding</category>
        
        <category>stowe</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hey Siri, Text Evernote</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you use &lt;a href=&quot;https://evernote.com&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;? Ever wish you could quickly save a note to Evernote hands-free? I found a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For nearly a year now, I’ve been using Evernote to store everything. Even the draft of this blog post was written using Evernote. As my dependency on Evernote grew, so did my need to quickly capture new ideas when I wasn’t near my computer. Sure, I can use my iPhone to save a note, but how do I save one when I can’t using my phone. What if I’m driving and an idea comes to mind that I want to capture. What then? Pull the car over just to use Evernote. Sorry, I’m obsessed with using Evernote, but not that obsessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I found a way to record my ideas to Evernote that I can do it even while driving. All I do is say, “Hey Siri text Evernote…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/&quot;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; is an online service that lets you connect one service to another. It’s watching for actions from one service, and when they happen, it triggers an action in the other service. For instance, if you post a picture to Instagram, then save it to Dropbox. IFTTT can do that for you. It’s even in their name. IFTTT is If This, Then That. If I post a picture to Instagram, then save it to Dropbox. If This, Then That.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IFTTT supports incoming SMS messages. IFTTT can also save a note Evernote. I created an applet — that’s what IFTTT calls the rules that connect services together — that combines these two services. The applet accepts an incoming SMS message, then saves the message to Evernote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IFTTT provides the phone number for the SMS message, which I added to my contacts list. I named the contact Evernote. Now, whenever I need to save an idea to Evernote quickly, I just send a text message to my Evernote contact. Cool, eh? Wait, it gets even cooler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hey-siri-text-evernote&quot;&gt;Hey Siri, Text Evernote&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPhone and Apple Watch have a nifty feature where you can say, “Hey Siri” and have Siri do some task for you. I use this all this time for things like setting a timer. “Hey Siri, set a 5 minute timer.” BAM! Siri sets a 5-minute timer for me. But Siri can do more. She can send a text message. Heck, she’ll even type the message as you speak. So while I’m driving, I raise my wrist and say into my Apple Watch, “Hey Siri, text Evernote, write a blog post on how I save ideas to Evernote without using my hands.” My watch sends the message to my iPhone, which sends out the SMS to IFTTT, which saves the message to Evernote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty dang cool, eh?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 11:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/20/hey-siri-text-evernote/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/20/hey-siri-text-evernote/</guid>
        
        <category>evernote</category>
        
        <category>productivity</category>
        
        <category>siri</category>
        
        <category>tip</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
