<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man</title>
        <description>thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man - </description>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com</link>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2015-06-22T12:16:35-04:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2015-06-22T12:16:35-04:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>Tips To Being More Focused</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I tweeted the other day that “I have the problem of wanting to do too many things at once, which is distracting. It’s time for me to learn how to scale back and focus.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/420/18776596119_d03e98a590_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true. Right now there are a number of things I’m working on and there are even more things that I want to work on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I’ve been bouncing back and forth between a number of projects, but I haven’t been very productive. I start work on a task but before I finish I let myself get distracted with another task. For instance, I’ll work on a client project and before I finish the task at hand I’ll jump to another task from another project. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t always worked this way, and I’m not sure why I now struggle to stay focused. It could be the changing of seasons. I had my daily routine dialed in during the winter months, but something has changed recently and it’s not just the seasons. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe my struggle with focus is a sign of being burnt out, maybe it’s the type of projects I’m working on - I’m certainly less excited about certain projects while much more excited about others. Maybe it’s because the kid is out of school and my work day is broken up into smaller chunks than during school time. Or maybe it’s a combination of all of the above. All I know for sure is that I find it difficult to focus, so last week I set out to find new ways to get focused and stay focused&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. And here’s what I came up with…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-check-email-first-thing-in-the-morning&quot;&gt;Don’t Check Email First Thing In The Morning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have stopped checking email first thing in the morning. This is probably one of the hardest habit for me to break, but I’ve come to realize that checking email first thing in the morning leads to the biggest distractions for me. So it is a must change habit for me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a typical day I start the morning excited about what I’m planning to do during the day only to have that excitement squashed because of emails. The emails will often times change my plans for the day. Emails, in other words, control my day when I should be controlling my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of checking email at the start of the day I now check it later in the morning, usually just before I break for lunch. This gives me a chance to really focus on the work at hand and not let my day get off on the wrong foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admit this hasn’t been the easiest change for me to make. I’ve become accustom to checking my email as soon as I wake up…often times while still in bed. But I recognize that checking email first thing each morning typically controls the rest of my day. It causes me to change the priorities I set the evening before, which in turn makes me feel like I didn’t spend nearly as much time on the most important tasks for the week. That’s why I’ve stopped checking email first thing each day and I have replaced that habit with the next tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-whats-most-important-first&quot;&gt;Do What’s Most Important First&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of checking email at the start of my day, I begin my work day by working on the task that is most important for the day. It could be bug fixes for a client’s app, work on a new landing page, writing a blog post, or adding a new feature to one of my apps. I decide the night before what is the most important thing to do and that’s the first task I work on the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following this tip for only a few days, and so far I feel more productive. Plus I feel a greater sense of accomplishment at the end of the day because that task that was most important got the love it deserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend get into the habit of starting your day by doing the most important task first. If you are writing a book, start your day by writing. If you are working on a client project, and have a upcoming deadline, start your day by working on the project. And remember to work on this important task before you check your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the biggest changes I’ve made to my daily routine, and I’m seeing immediate results. But I decided to try a couple of more things to see if I can make more improvements to my focus and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;limit-meetings-to-tuesday-and-thursday&quot;&gt;Limit Meetings to Tuesday and Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next tip is to limit meetings with others to two specific days each week. For me those two days are Tuesday and Thursday. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main benefit to doing this is to give me more control over the other days of the week. I can use those other days to focus on productive work without the disruption of meetings. Meetings are, after all, disruptive to a productive day. Nothing kills my productivity faster than having to stop what I’m working on to waste time in a meeting. And yes, most meetings are a waste of time. Even the ones that are not a complete waste of time do waste some time. That casual chit chat at the beginning of the meeting, for example, is unproductive time. So I’m limiting those periods of unproductive time to two days a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get that this isn’t something everyone can do. Heck I’m not 100% sure I can make it happen for me. But if you work for yourself and/or have control over your schedule, then you should be able to make this happen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also if you are like me, you already have meetings on your calendar. I, for example, have a recurring client meeting every Monday and Thursday mornings, another client meeting on Monday afternoon, one on Wednesday morning, and just recently a client asked to do a daily stand-up meeting each morning&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This means there will be a transition period for me as I get my meetings re-scheduled for Tuesday and Thursday. But this is something I’m going to make happen come hell or high water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pomodoro-technique&quot;&gt;Pomodoro Technique&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if not checking email first thing each morning isn’t already a big change to my daily routine, I’ve decided to give the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pomodorotechnique.com&quot;&gt;Pomodoro Technique&lt;/a&gt; a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pomodoro Technique is simple. You set a timer for 25 minutes and during that time you focus on a particular task. When the 25 minutes are up, you take a 5 minute break. Then you start another pomodoro, setting the timer for 25 minutes; focus, focus, focus; then take another 5 minute break. After four pomodoros you take a longer break (15 to 30 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard about the Pomodoro Technique a number of times over the years. I felt the process was not for me, but since focus has become a recent problem for me I decided to give it a try. So far the small blocks of 25-minute work cycles is working well for me given the amount of distractions that can happen throughout the day especially when my wife and kid are home. With the Pomodoro Technique I focus for 25 minutes, then I can use the 5 minute break answer a question my wife might have or see the latest LEGO creation my son has built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time will tell if this technique will work for me long term. And I should mention I’m not following the Pomodoro Technique by the book either. There are times when I reach the end of my 25 minute work cycle and I don’t want to stop. So I don’t. I skip my 5 minute break, and I continue working using a new pomodoro. But I do force myself to take a break after the second pomodoro when I combine two of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-these-tips-really-work&quot;&gt;Do These Tips Really Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So do these tips really work? It’s hard for me to say with absolutely certainty that they work. I’m seeing some positive results already, but only time will tell what works and doesn’t work for me long term. And obviously not every tip will work for every person. Heck, I’m not sure if all the tips will work for me. But these are the tips I’m trying right now, and after only a few days I’m seeing good results. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m getting more done faster, and that feeling of being overwhelmed that I got at the end of each day has been replaced with a greater sense of accomplishment and a feeling of being more productive. But the real test for me will be following these tips for a month and see what happens. Trying these tips for a month is the only way I will know what works and doesn’t work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll post an update on my progress in a few weeks. Meanwhile I encourage you to give one, some or all the tips a try to see what works for you. And let me know how it works out for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Yes, I see the irony in that my search for ways to become more focused distracted me from the work that I needed to do last week. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I personally think daily stand up meetings, like most meetings, are a waste of time, and it’s certainly not a productive use of my time. A daily status email is far more productive in my opinion, and you have the report captured for historical purposes.  &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/22/tips-to-being-more-focused/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/22/tips-to-being-more-focused</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-06-22T11:51:20-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Video of Stowe, Vermont</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Ashley came across another video of Vermont. This time it’s about Stowe, the town I live in. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9_Wk5j_4Uc4?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video is from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vtscapes.com&quot;&gt;VermontScapes&lt;/a&gt;. Go checkout the site if you want to see more beautiful photos of Vermont and the Stowe area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/video-of-stowe-vermont/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/video-of-stowe-vermont</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-06-18T22:22:58-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Essence Of Vermont</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise I love living in Vermont in part because it’s different from other places I have lived. And this video from Skyworks really captures parts of why I love it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UBwqn9BRWhA?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/essence-of-vermont/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/essence-of-vermont</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-06-18T06:16:26-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Do I Need Another Twitter Account</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier tonight I setup a new Twitter account that tweets a link each time I publish a new post here at thecave.com. The new Twitter account is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thecave_com/&quot;&gt;@thecave_com&lt;/a&gt;. Of course now that this is setup, I’m wondering…Do I really need a separate Twitter account, or should I just tweet the links from my &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kiryt/&quot;&gt;@kirbyt&lt;/a&gt; account?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I will keep the two separate accounts, and I’ll retweet via @kirbyt any links that I feel might be of greater interest, which is basically what I’ve always done. So if you want to know each time a new post is published, follow @thecave_com. Otherwise just keep doing what you’ve been doing.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-06-14T23:09:24-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>thecave On Twitter</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Uli &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/uliwitness/status/600656348272001024&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do you have a Twitter feed that lets me know when you post something new?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It only took me a month, but I finally have a Twitter account for thecave. Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thecave_com/&quot;&gt;@thecave_com&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter if you want to know when I post something new to this blog. And as always you can subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/feed.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; if you prefer feed readers over Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-technical-how-to&quot;&gt;The Technical How To&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few different ways to automate the process of posting a link on Twitter when you publish a new blog post. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitterfeed.com&quot;&gt;Twitter Feed&lt;/a&gt; is one service I tried. It is fast and easy to setup, and it includes options such as including the title, description, or title and description in the tweet. Even though Twitter Feed is a cinch to setup, I decided to go with &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/&quot;&gt;If This Then That (IFTTT)&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using IFTTT create a new recipe. Select &lt;em&gt;Feed&lt;/em&gt; for the trigger and &lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt; for the action. Be sure to connect your Twitter account to the IFTTT if you have not already done so. And that’s it. Next time you make a blog post, IFTTT will update your Twitter account with the title and link to the post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/uliwitness&quot;&gt;@uliwitness&lt;/a&gt; for suggesting I do this.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-06-14T22:31:52-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Building An App From Start To Finish</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Amy Hoy wrote the first version of her book &lt;a href=&quot;https://unicornfree.com/just-fucking-ship&quot;&gt;Just Fucking Ship&lt;/a&gt; in 24 hours, which is awesome. Along those same lines, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_davidsmith&quot;&gt;David Smith&lt;/a&gt; built an app from start to finish in about 6 hours - also awesome, and he posted this video that shows the entire process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rEkuRFO6xTw?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these, the book and the app, are motivating me to do more faster. I just need to stop letting excuses and fear of not being perfect get in my way.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-06-08T09:09:35-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>It's Better To Try An Idea</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite quotes about shipping:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s better to try an idea and see if it works than worry too much about its potential and never ship. - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_davidsmith&quot;&gt;@_davidsmith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/its-better-to-try-an-idea/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/its-better-to-try-an-idea</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-06-08T08:54:23-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Stuck Working For Others</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I love this quote from Amy Hoy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you only do what pays immediately, you will be stuck working for other people. Or you will be stuck doing what other people want you to do…forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quote come from her talk about &lt;a href=&quot;https://unicornfree.com/2015/be-your-own-angel-a-revenue-model-for-slow-startups?inf_contact_key=33d23f3cc326dbb9432ca21551e5c05960ba9e460978b642f3bc69a5e6171317&quot;&gt;being your own angel investor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/04/stuck-working-for-others/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/04/stuck-working-for-others</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-06-04T16:31:38-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Where I Blog These Days</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently, and “recently” as in the last couple of years, cut back on the number of blog sites I have. I’m down to three sites now, and that seems manageable. The sites are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/&quot;&gt;thecave.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  That’s this site. It’s my personal blog, and it’s where I post most often. I talk about everything from what’s going on with me personally to snowboarding to programming. The site is broken down into categories, and I have plans to publish an RSS feed for each category so readers can filter out topics they might consider noise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/&quot;&gt;blog.whitepeaksoftware.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  This is my company blog site. The focus of this site is to talk about the company and the products I sell. Granted I’m doing a horrible job at keeping up with the posts. That’s probably one of the many reasons my stuff doesn’t sell as well as it did a few years back.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rowanturner.net/&quot;&gt;rowanturner.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  Yep, my son has his own website. But he has no interest in making posts here, so I do it for him. I usually post pictures and videos of Rowan and his friends off having fun. My mom might be the only person reading this site regularly, but that’s fine. I’ll keep posting because I like looking back on past articles and reliving fun moments with my kid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These sites each have RSS feeds, so you don’t have to remember to visit. And some day I’ll do a better job of mentioning when new posts are available on the various social networks for those who don’t want to subscribe to the feeds. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-05-19T09:40:11-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Snow River At Stowe</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This looks like it was a lot of fun. Wish I had known about it when it happened last year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wfWUHKUt-Q0?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-05-09T11:24:25-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Views Created In Code</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I posted an article that talks about why &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout/&quot;&gt;I stopped using Interface Builder&lt;/a&gt; in favor of writing code to create views. There are some who disagree with me, and to them I say, “To each his own.” And there are some who agree with me, but choose not to publicize it. No matter. Every programmer has tricks that make them more productive, and creating views in code just happens to be one trick that works well for me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What works for me doesn’t necessarily work for others. But I have to say, I had a brief “HA!” moment when I read this comment from Peter Steinberger’s post about &lt;a href=&quot;http://petersteinberger.com/blog/2015/researching-researchkit/&quot;&gt;researching Apple’s research kit&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All views are created in code. Apple uses a Storyboard for the example catalog, but that’s it. Apple uses the standard pattern of overriding &lt;code&gt;viewDidLoad&lt;/code&gt; to build UI in combination with Auto Layout and the visual format language, whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great minds think alike.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Though I don’t override &lt;code&gt;viewDidLoad&lt;/code&gt; to create my views. I usually create a view class, and I add an instance of the class to the view controller’s view in &lt;code&gt;loadView&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/15/views-created-in-code/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/15/views-created-in-code</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-04-15T12:58:45-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>No WWDC Or SF Trip</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple announced the dates for this year’s WWDC, and once again a lottery is being used to decide who gets to buy a ticket. I have no interesting is attending WWDC other than to attend the labs since I do have questions I would love to ask an Apple engineer. But it’s not worth spending $1599 on a ticket just for that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, I’m struggling to justify spending the money to stay in San Francisco the week of WWDC just to hang out with friends and drink beer. Certainly reconnecting with friends and making news ones is very enjoyable, but there are cheaper ways for me to do that. So I’ve decided I’m not going to SF for this year’s WWDC. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-04-14T09:20:56-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>I Should Feel Guilty But I Don't</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I played hooky from work afternoon. I should feel guilty but I don’t. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I picked up Rowan from school this afternoon, and we headed to the mountain. Unfortunately I forgot his skis boots, so we had to stop by the house. Then as we tried to get on the lift I realized I left our passes in our jackets. The temperature was in the 60, so we weren’t wearing our jackets. They were still at the house. The afternoon was off to a bad start, but our luck changed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were able to get two runs in before the lifts closed thanks to the nice lifties that let us through without our passes. Also we ran into some friends in our first run, including a class mate of Rowan’s. After the lifts shut down for the day we hung out in the parking lot for a bit of après ski with friends. Then we headed to Rimrocks where we ran into more friends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8776/16952950809_f0103c0255_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great father son afternoon with wonderful friends, and when I’m 85 years old I’ll remember how much fun Rowan and I had today. I won’t remember the work I should have done today, and that’s why I don’t feel guilty about how I spent my time this afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8722/16951598160_95cb6df7cc_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/13/i-should-feel-guilty-but-i-dont/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/13/i-should-feel-guilty-but-i-dont</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-04-13T20:15:11-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Argh! Thanks A Lot Apple</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 2:45 am this morning to buy a new Apple Watch. I ordered the 42mm space gray with black sport band Apple Watch Sport, but I’m still annoyed. I got a delivery date of May 13 to May 27, and that annoys me because I was ready to order at 3 am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at my computer trying to load store.apple.com at 3 am, but the site was down. I foolishly kept refreshing the web page for 6 minutes before deciding to try the Apple Store app on my iPhone. The app worked perfectly, and thanks to Apple Pay, the order process was fast. But it was too late to get the watch I wanted in the first set of shipments, and all because I wasted my time trying to use the damn website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, “first world problems.” All I can say is I’m grumpy when I have to use an alarm clock to wake up, and I become more grumpy when my time is wasted because of a website outage after waking up so freakin’ early.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/10/argh-thanks-a-lot-apple/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/10/argh-thanks-a-lot-apple</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-04-10T03:13:14-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Apple Watch Will Make iPhone 6 Plus Size Less Annoying</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things that annoys me most about the size of my iPhone 6 Plus is pulling it out of my pocket while at a bar or restaurant just to see why my phone buzzed. The majority of the time my phone buzzes because of an incoming text message. I have notifications turned off for almost all other apps, and I rarely. if ever, get phone calls these days, which is why I know the buzz is most likely a text message. And if I’m at the bar without my wife, then the person trying to reach me is most likely my wife. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when the text message comes in, I have to pull out this big honkin’ device out of my pocket and light up the room just to see the message. I may reply, and if I do, it’s a short reply because, after all, I’m busy at the bar. Then I put the phone back into my pocket only to repeat all of this a few minutes later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Receiving text messages doesn’t annoy me, but having to pull out and put away this big device every few minutes does annoy me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It occurred to me that one of the possible reasons why Apple decided to release the larger iPhones was because they knew, thanks to the Apple Watch, that there would be no reason to pull out these larger devices from pockets and purses just to check notifications and send simple text messages and replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Apple Watch will make the iPhone 6 Plus size less annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-04-06T21:42:53-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Best April Fools' Joke Ever</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I met a guy tonight at the bar. He was the victim of the best April Fools’ Joke ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He broke up with his girlfriend 5 weeks ago. At 8 am on April 1 she sent him a text message with a picture of a at-home pregnancy test that was positive. Yep, she was telling my new friend he was going to be a dad. 16 hours later, at midnight and after he consumed countless shots and another drinks, she sent him the text “Happy April Fools.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She really got him, and he really appreciated the joke. The fact that she let him think he was going to be a new dad for 16 hours is what makes the joke really great. Had she reply “April Fools” five minutes after the first text message, the joke wouldn’t be as funny. But the fact that she made him sweat it out all day makes this the best April Fools’ joke ever. I’m just glad the joke wasn’t played on me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/03/best-april-fools-joke-ever/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/03/best-april-fools-joke-ever</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-04-03T01:32:47-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>2600 Miles In 4 Minutes</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a very cool video of a guy who did a time-lapse of his Pacific Crest Trail thru hike. Enjoy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xyo8OIp7aHM?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/28/2600-miles-in-4-minutes/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/28/2600-miles-in-4-minutes</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-03-28T02:36:16-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Affordable Cloud Storage With Amazon Cloud Drive</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Amazon announced new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/clouddrive/pricing&quot;&gt;pricing plans&lt;/a&gt; for their cloud storage offering named &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/clouddrive/home&quot;&gt;Cloud Drive&lt;/a&gt;. You can store unlimited number of photos for $11.99 per year, or you can store unlimited number of files for $59.99. The later is a no-brainer for me as I have been looking for an affordable cloud storage solution like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I use a number of different services for cloud storage. I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://db.tt/Y2NovyiG&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; to sync files between computers and devices. The files I keep on Dropbox are ones I need immediate access to. In other words, these are the files I need to have on my laptop while also having access from other computers and devices such as my iPhone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.backblaze.com/r/00ytw8&quot;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt; to backup all the files on my laptop to the cloud. It’s my lifeline should something unexpected happen to my laptop. For photos I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.smugmug.com/signup?Coupon=8ZK2smzZYAS1I&quot;&gt;SmugMug&lt;/a&gt;, but more recently I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; more than SmugMug. And I use Rackspace Cloud File for my CDN. That’s content delivery network for my non-geeky friends reading this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with these different cloud storage providers is that I still had no easy way to upload and store files that I don’t need frequent access to. I don’t like to throw away data, but I also don’t need documents I wrote back in 2003 wasting space on my laptop. Dropbox has a way to not sync selected folders, but I don’t trust it. Plus, it’s not as straight forward as uploading and storing selected files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rackspace Cloud File works well for archiving my old data, but it can become costly if I have multi-terabytes of data to store. Same is true for Amazon S3, which I considered using in the past. In fact, when Amazon announced S3 Glacier I thought I had found the perfect cloud storage solution for me, but it’s not easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flickr and SmugMug are great for storing photos and videos, and they both make it easy to upload new ones. Heck, Flickr will even automatically upload new photos taken on my iPhone for me. It doesn’t get much easier than that. But these two only support photos and videos, and I have other file types I want to store in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I first heard about Amazon’s new pricing for Cloud Drive I thought, “Finally, an affordable cloud storage solution that fixes my needs for archiving old data.” At $60 per year for unlimited storage, I would be a fool not to try it out. But I don’t even need to spend the $60 right now. Amazon is offering a 3-month free trial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud Drive has desktop software for your Mac (and I’m guessing Windows too) to upload files, but I’m not a fan of the desktop software. It doesn’t let me pick where I want to store the files I’m uploading, and I like to use a very specific directory structure for my files. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Cloud Drive desktop software doesn’t suite my needs, the Cloud Drive web interface does. I can organize my storage area to my liking, create new folders and upload files to specific folders within the file system. And that’s just what I’ve been doing…uploading and organizing files - a few gigs so far to test out the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do, however, have one complaint about Cloud Drive. The Cloud Drive app for iOS only shows photos and videos. I want access to all the files stored on my Cloud Drive. Hopefully Amazon will change this soon, or maybe it’s an opportunity for me to write a new app. There is, after all, an API for Cloud Drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon Cloud Drive is the solution I’ve been looking for to archive my old data to the cloud. I’ll continue using external hard drives, Dropbox, Backblaze and such for backups, but my days with SmugMugs might be numbered. Still, I’m excited to finally have an affordable cloud storage solution for my old data.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/27/affordable-cloud-storage-with-amazon-cloud-drive/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/27/affordable-cloud-storage-with-amazon-cloud-drive</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-03-27T06:52:45-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Dress Code For Remote Job</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across one of the silliest benefits I’ve seen for a remote developer job: casual dress code. From the job &lt;a href=&quot;https://weworkremotely.com/jobs/1323&quot;&gt;posting&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What’s In It For You&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Medical and dental benefits&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Paid vacation and holidays&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Remote work environment … work where you work best&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dynamic and dedicated team&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Data/Cell (internet) stipend&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Casual dress code&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Most of all smart and driven team members that love to collaborate, seek feedback, and improve&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure I would want to work for a remote company that has a dress code even if it’s a casual dress code. I like coding in my pjs on many days, which means I would be in violation of the casual dress code. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/21/dress-code-for-remote-job/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/21/dress-code-for-remote-job</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-03-21T08:27:07-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Driver X</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I received my new pair of Burton Driver X snowboard boots this afternoon. Damn, these puppies are stiff, but that’s a good thing. I can’t wait to hit the hill with them in the morning. It’s going to be a whole new riding experience after wearing boots that I probably should’ve replaced a couple of seasons ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7634/16766864701_a383cbd8cc_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/09/driver-x/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/09/driver-x</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-03-09T16:11:50-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>