<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs</title>
        <description>thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs - </description>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com</link>
        <link>http://www.thecave.com</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2017-04-17T01:47:41+00:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2017-04-17T01:47:41+00:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>Convert Time with a TextExpander Snippet</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I find I am using &lt;a href=&quot;https://textexpander.com&quot;&gt;TextExpander&lt;/a&gt; more and more these days. It’s an awesome productivity tool that saves me time by inserting snippets of text into whatever I’m writing, be it code or words. What I didn’t know about TextExpander, that is, until today, is that it can run shell scripts to generate the text snippets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often meet with people on the West Coast. When I schedule a meeting time, I will say something like “Let’s meet at 01:30 PM EDT / 10:30 AM PDT” in the email. Not only is this a lot of text to type, but it also requires I calculate the Pacific time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How cool would it be if TextExpander could generate the time snippet for me? Guess what. It can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a shell script snippet that takes a local time, which I input, and calculates the Eastern and Pacific times. I use &lt;em&gt;timept;;&lt;/em&gt; for the snippet abbreviation. Now when I want to mention a particular time in an email, I type &lt;em&gt;timept;;&lt;/em&gt; and enter the time. TextExpander does the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the shell script code for anyone who might want it. Make sure you select &lt;strong&gt;Shell Script&lt;/strong&gt; as the &lt;em&gt;Content&lt;/em&gt; type when creating the snippet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#! /bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Enter a time using 24H. 1:30pm is 13:30 .&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;ENTERTIME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;%filltext:name=Time (in 24H)%&quot;&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# See https://gist.github.com/palaniraja/f8e21e8c66eac7e1b313 for a&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# list of time zone names.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;T1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;TZ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;America/New_York&quot;&lt;/span&gt; date -jf &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;%H:%M %z&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ENTERTIME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;date &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;+%z&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;+%I:%M %p %Z&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;T2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;TZ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;America/Los_Angeles&quot;&lt;/span&gt; date -jf &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;%H:%M %z&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ENTERTIME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;date &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;+%z&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;+%I:%M %p %Z&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; -n &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$T1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; / &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$T2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/16/convert-time-with-a-textexpander-snippet/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/16/convert-time-with-a-textexpander-snippet</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-04-17T01:14:46+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title></title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Why didn’t I setup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitrise.io&quot;&gt;Bitrise&lt;/a&gt; to generate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecave.com&quot;&gt;thecave.com&lt;/a&gt; sooner. It’s so much easier, and faster, to push to master and let Bitrise do the rest of the work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/16/why-didnt-i-do-this-earlier/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/16/why-didnt-i-do-this-earlier</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-04-16T23:59:11+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title></title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Another test to see if I got the time zone right this time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/16/timezone-test/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/16/timezone-test</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-04-16T14:27:23+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title></title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m experimenting with ways to add a new post from my iPhone to thecave.com, which is generated by Jekyll, and have the post show up on micro.blog.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/16/micropost-test/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/16/micropost-test</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-04-16T10:01:11+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Mastodon and thecave.social</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I first heard about &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tootsuite/mastodon&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; last week while lurking on Twitter. For those who don’t know, Mastodon is a free, open source, decentralized social network with instances run mostly by individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I read more about Mastodon, I became more intrigued. It didn’t take long before I registered the domain name &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecave.social/&quot;&gt;thecave.social&lt;/a&gt;. The idea of hosting a Mastodon instance, even if just for myself, piqued the geek in me. The realist in me said I don’t have the extra time to take on such an endeavor. Still, I wanted to learn more about Mastodon, and what better way than hosting an instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I looked at hosting my Mastodon instance on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openshift.com&quot;&gt;OpenShift Online&lt;/a&gt;. I’m a long time fan of OpenShift, but it’s been a while since I played on it. Turns out, a new OpenShift Online supporting Docker containers is in the works. Right now, the new OpenShift Online is in Developer Preview, and accounts are active for only 30 days. The time limit doesn’t work for me because I can see myself hosting my Mastodon instance for more than a month. So OpenShift is not an option for me at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at hosting the instance somewhere else, like Digital Ocean, but I decided I don’t have the time to do all the extra work. Thankfully, there is an experimental Heroku install option for Mastodon, and given that I already have some basic experience with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heroku.com&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;, I decided it is the way to go for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After deciding where to host my instance, I did a “test” install. I created a single dyno and played around with Mastodon. Liking what I saw, I scrapped the dyno and created another one, this time for thecave.social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me about four hours total to get my Mastodon instance setup and configured the way I want it. A more experienced admin could have probably done the work in half the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mailgun.com&quot;&gt;Mailgun&lt;/a&gt; for emails and &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/s3/&quot;&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt; for file storage. And now that Heroku has an automatic certificate manager that uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org&quot;&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;, acquiring and installing an SSL/TLS certificate for the site was a snap. I’m continually amazed at how easy it is to host a server these days thanks to services like Mailgun, S3, and Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thecave.social/&quot;&gt;thecave.social&lt;/a&gt; has been live for a few days now, and everything is running smoothly. Of course, I am the only user on this instance, and I do not support the streaming API yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve even made a few toots on Mastodon, which is impressive for me given that I don’t spend a lot of time on social networks these days. (I’ve checked Facebook once in the last 28 days, and I lurk on Twitter only once or twice a month.) Still, I can see myself getting into Mastodon because it represents what I like about social networks, and it doesn’t have the crap that has turned me off of social networks in general, ads and political rants being the top offenders for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, registration on thecave.social is closed, though I’m considering opening it up to family and friends soon. Let me know if you are interested in having an account so I can tell you when registration is open. I can’t guarantee how long I will keep the server up and running, but I don’t see myself shutting it down anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I’m not looking to grow a big community with hundreds or even thousands of users. Instead, I want a place that is my own just like I have with my personal email address. Some family and friends have thecave.com email address, and I see the same thing happening with thecave.social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you on other Mastodon instances, feel free to follow me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecave.social/@kirby&quot;&gt;@kirby@thecave.social&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/12/mastodon-and-thecavesocial/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/12/mastodon-and-thecavesocial</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-04-12T18:07:57+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title></title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After 17 days of no Facebook, I finally took a peek at my feed. I was totally uninterested, and I signed out after a minute. I think I’m over my Facebook addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/03/after-17-days/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/03/after-17-days</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-04-03T12:10:26+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title></title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;What a beautiful morning. Winter is still going strong here in Stowe. &lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/4/3754/32957940243_5ae40ae89a_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/01/aint-no-april-fools-joke/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/04/01/aint-no-april-fools-joke</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-04-01T10:56:58+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title></title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been on Facebook for 11 straight days. #breakingtheaddiction&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/26/no-facebook-for-11-days/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/26/no-facebook-for-11-days</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-03-26T10:32:14+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title></title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I love this picture of Rowan and his cousin Sedona. Taken last weekend at Stowe Mountain Resort. &lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2813/32769104684_cec6f7e85b_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/love-this-picture/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/love-this-picture</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-03-25T12:37:22+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title></title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing, testing. 1, 2, 3…I moved my RSS feed for &lt;a href=&quot;http://micro.blog&quot;&gt;micro.blog&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecave.com/&quot;&gt;thecave.com&lt;/a&gt; since I’m no longer actively working on my app, Cross Post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/micro-blogging-from-thecave/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/micro-blogging-from-thecave</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-03-25T11:15:34+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>The Experienced Programmer's Guide to Getting Started with Swift</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple Vermont-based software developers recently asked me how to get started with Swift and writing apps for iOS. I emailed them individually, but when I was asked again today, I thought, time to write a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an experienced programmer looking to get started with Swift and iOS development, I suggest starting with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/swift/resources/&quot;&gt;Apple developer guides&lt;/a&gt;. I also recommend reading the language guide, available in the iBooks Store and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/content/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/Swift_Programming_Language/index.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40014097-CH3-ID0&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;. It is a dry read, but very detailed. Besides, I still find myself referring to it from time to time, so it is on my “must read” list for those new to Swift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great place to get started is over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raywenderlich.com&quot;&gt;raywenderlich.com&lt;/a&gt;. The site contains tons of great tutorials, books, and videos. Some are free, others you pay for, but the materials are some of the best learning materials outside of Apple. Take a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raywenderlich.com/category/swift&quot;&gt;Swift category&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in game development, the book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raywenderlich.com/store/2d-ios-tvos-games-by-tutorials&quot;&gt;2D Apple Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is an awesome read. It focuses on writing iOS games using Swift 3 and SpriteKit, giving you step by step instructions. I have read half the book so far, and it has been a blast learning how to create games for iOS (even though I am not a game developer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you have an iPad, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/swift/playgrounds/&quot;&gt;Swift Playgrounds&lt;/a&gt;. It teaches you how to code, which is not something you need if you are an experienced programmer, but from what I have heard, the advance lessons can be helpful in teaching experienced programmer how to write Swift code. Also, you can experiment with all aspects of the device, from accessing the various iOS frameworks, such as SpriteKit and UIKit, to directly controlling hardware, such as the gyroscope, accelerometer, and camera. (Download the Swift Playgrounds app &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/swift-playgrounds/id908519492?mt=8&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps get you started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/02/02/the-experienced-programmers-guide-to-getting-started-with-swift/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/02/02/the-experienced-programmers-guide-to-getting-started-with-swift</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-02-02T16:32:49+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Wow! Busy weekends ahead</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend emailed me asking if I’m around in two weekends. He wants to visit me in Stowe and do a little riding together. I haven’t seen this friend in years, and it will be great to catch up ago. The problem is, I discovered I’m busy every weekend through the end of March. Turns out, when you live in a ski town, lots of people want to come for a visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you want to visit me in Stowe, and you want to ride together, it’ll have to be during the weekday or a weekend towards the end of March beginning of April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case you’re wondering, the skiing and riding in Stowe has been superb recently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/30/wow-busy-weekends-ahead/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/30/wow-busy-weekends-ahead</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-01-31T01:34:29+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Hey Siri, Text Evernote</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you use &lt;a href=&quot;https://evernote.com&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;? Ever wish you could quickly save a note to Evernote hands-free? I found a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For nearly a year now, I’ve been using Evernote to store everything. Even the draft of this blog post was written using Evernote. As my dependency on Evernote grew, so did my need to quickly capture new ideas when I wasn’t near my computer. Sure, I can use my iPhone to save a note, but how do I save one when I can’t using my phone. What if I’m driving and an idea comes to mind that I want to capture. What then? Pull the car over just to use Evernote. Sorry, I’m obsessed with using Evernote, but not that obsessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I found a way to record my ideas to Evernote that I can do it even while driving. All I do is say, “Hey Siri text Evernote…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/&quot;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; is an online service that lets you connect one service to another. It’s watching for actions from one service, and when they happen, it triggers an action in the other service. For instance, if you post a picture to Instagram, then save it to Dropbox. IFTTT can do that for you. It’s even in their name. IFTTT is If This, Then That. If I post a picture to Instagram, then save it to Dropbox. If This, Then That.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IFTTT supports incoming SMS messages. IFTTT can also save a note Evernote. I created an applet — that’s what IFTTT calls the rules that connect services together — that combines these two services. The applet accepts an incoming SMS message, then saves the message to Evernote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IFTTT provides the phone number for the SMS message, which I added to my contacts list. I named the contact Evernote. Now, whenever I need to save an idea to Evernote quickly, I just send a text message to my Evernote contact. Cool, eh? Wait, it gets even cooler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hey-siri-text-evernote&quot;&gt;Hey Siri, Text Evernote&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPhone and Apple Watch have a nifty feature where you can say, “Hey Siri” and have Siri do some task for you. I use this all this time for things like setting a timer. “Hey Siri, set a 5 minute timer.” BAM! Siri sets a 5-minute timer for me. But Siri can do more. She can send a text message. Heck, she’ll even type the message as you speak. So while I’m driving, I raise my wrist and say into my Apple Watch, “Hey Siri, text Evernote, write a blog post on how I save ideas to Evernote without using my hands.” My watch sends the message to my iPhone, which sends out the SMS to IFTTT, which saves the message to Evernote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty dang cool, eh?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/20/hey-siri-text-evernote/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/20/hey-siri-text-evernote</guid>
                <pubDate>2017-01-20T11:52:48+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Trying a little experiment</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I want an easy way to share certain posts to social media sites, such as Facebook and Twitter, at the time I publish the post. The more I can automate, the better. The problem is this site is a static HTML site generated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do I automatically share a post to Facebook or Twitter? That’s what I’m experimenting with right now, and this post is my test post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-going-on&quot;&gt;What’s Going On&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the techies reading this, here’s what I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I updated my tags plugin to generate an RSS feed file for each tag. Next, I setup &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com&quot;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; to monitor the feed files for the tags “facebook” and “twitter”. When IFTTT detects a new feed file item (i.e., a new blog post), it will post the item to the appropriate social media site. If I want to share a post to Facebook, I simply tag it with “facebook”. And if I want to share the post on Twitter, I tag it with “twitter”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kirbyt/site-www-thecave-com&quot;&gt;source code for this site&lt;/a&gt; is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kirbyt/site-www-thecave-com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; for those who want to look under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to start work on the hard part…writing more blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2016/12/30/trying-a-little-experiment/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2016/12/30/trying-a-little-experiment</guid>
                <pubDate>2016-12-30T23:01:52+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>From Trace To Slopes</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a software developer but I’m also a snowboard bum. And with the start of the 2016/2017 snowboard season upon us – that is, for those of us living in the Northern Hemisphere – I’m eager to hit the slopes. Over the last few years I’ve used &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.traceup.com/trace-for-snow&quot;&gt;Trace Snow&lt;/a&gt;, formerly AlpineReplay, to track my time on the slopes. It’s a good iPhone app but far from perfect. One feature it lacks is reporting the number of days spent on the slopes in a season. Trace isn’t alone in not having this feature. None of the ski and snowboard tracking apps I’ve tried have this feature. It seems these apps are more commonly used by individuals who only get a small number of days on the slopes, say 5 or 10 days, which is easy to count. But when you average 80+ days each season, counting the number of days can be a pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As luck would have it I had the pleasure of meeting &lt;a href=&quot;https://curtisherbert.com&quot;&gt;Curtis Herbert&lt;/a&gt; at this year’s 360idev. For those who don’t know Curtis, he’s an iOS developer who just happens to have written an excellent ski and snowboard tracking app appropriately named &lt;a href=&quot;https://getslopes.com&quot;&gt;Slopes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried Slopes once last year, but I wasn’t won over by it. I don’t remember the reasons, but I do remember it was lacking the one feature I really wanted, which is the see the number of days I’ve ridden in a season. I mentioned this to Curtis and before the end of the conference Slopes had a day count feature. And Curtis had a new customer. I decided right away I would use Slopes this season instead of Trace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I was bummed that I could not use Slopes to view the years of data I had collected in Trace. I mentioned this in email to Curtis and within a minute he replied telling me about Slopes’ import process. “Wow,” I thought, “he’s thought of everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I immediately went to the Trace website to see if I could export my data, and sure enough I could. But there was a problem. I had to export each day one at a time. I’ve logged over 250 days in Trace and manually downloading each day was not something I wanted to do. So I put on my developer hat and wrote a python script that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kirbyt/trace-export&quot;&gt;downloads the GPX files from Trace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; is the perfect language for a task like this especially when combined with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crummy.com/software/BeautifulSoup/&quot;&gt;Beautiful Soup&lt;/a&gt;, a Python library for parsing HTML. I’ve written similar screen scraping scripts using Python and Beautiful Soup before, so writing a script that downloads the GPX files from the Trace site took me a fraction of the time it would have taken me to manually download each GPX file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my Trace data in hand I was ready to import the GPX files into Slopes, but I hit another wall. To import a GPX file into Slopes, you email the file to yourself, then on your iPhone, you open the GPX file in Slopes. This is a great process if you have one or two GPX files to import, but if you have hundreds, well, it’s less than ideal. But thankfully Curtis thought that too. You can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201301&quot;&gt;iTunes File Sharing&lt;/a&gt; to import GPX files. Simply tether your iPhone to your Mac, open iTunes, select your iPhone, select the Apps section in the left panel, and scroll down to the File Sharing section in the right panel (thanks, Apple, for making this not so straight forward). Select the Slopes app, then drag and drop your GPX files into the Slopes Documents area. Finally, launch the Slopes app on your iPhone. Slopes was able to import all my files in a matter of seconds, and now I have all my tracked data, dating back to the 2012/2013 snowboard season, in Slopes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you are a Slopes user too and you previously used Trace, you can use my Python script to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kirbyt/trace-export&quot;&gt;download your past GPX recordings&lt;/a&gt;. I open sourced it so others can quickly download their data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for Slopes, I have to say it’s a great app and Curtis is awesome. He has thought of just about everything for Slopes, and for those features not in it, he seems like the type of guy who will add them if it makes sense for the app and its users. In fact one feature missing that I’ve already requested is an option to export all my GPX data from Slopes. I don’t plan to stop using Slopes anytime soon, but I would still like to see this feature on the off chance I have to make another switch in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2016/11/19/from-trace-to-slopes/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2016/11/19/from-trace-to-slopes</guid>
                <pubDate>2016-11-19T15:52:31+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>How To Do A Case Insensitive Search Using Parse SDK</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across this question about searching using the Parse SDK for iOS. Simon asks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What would be the best practice for search in a large user database and return e..g 10 first results based on name or email?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing a lot with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parse.com&quot;&gt;Parse&lt;/a&gt; recently, from building a new iOS app to adding a license key &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/licenselookup&quot;&gt;lookup&lt;/a&gt; feature to my company website, and the reason Simon’s question caught my attention was because I asked myself a similar question the other day when working on the license key lookup feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The license key data comes from my order processing provider. A customer who has lost they license key can visit my website and retrieve for their license information by entering their email address. The problem, however, is that the person might enter the email address using a different case than used when the order was placed. And Parse does not have a way to perform a case insensitive search on string values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you get around this problem? And as Simon asks, what are some best practices for searching data in Parse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;force-strings-to-all-lowercase&quot;&gt;Force Strings To All Lowercase&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For starters, you should force all string values that can be searched to lower case, and do the same with the search string entered by the user. This produces the same effect as performing a case insensitive search while getting around the fact that Parse, as well as other types of data stores, doesn’t support case insensitive searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While storing the string value in all lowercase works fine for some value types, such as an email address, it’s not ideal for other value types. A person’s first and last names are not something you want to store in lowercase only. After all, you will likely display the person’s name on a profile screen or in an email message, and you want to display the name exactly as entered by the person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you search by data such as a first or last name without the ability to perform a case insensitive search? Simple. You create a search field for each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;define-search-fields&quot;&gt;Define Search Fields&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say your Parse class contains three properties, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firstName&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lastName&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;email&lt;/code&gt;. All three contain data entered by a person. When you add a new instance of this class to Parse containing the data entered by the person, you can force the value for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;email&lt;/code&gt; to be lowercase (e.g., &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-[NSString lowercaseString]&lt;/code&gt; if you’re using Objective-C). However, you don’t want to do this for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firstName&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lastName&lt;/code&gt;. Instead, you want to use search fields for those two properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To search on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firstName&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lastName&lt;/code&gt;, add two additional properties to your class, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firstNameSearch&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lastNameSearch&lt;/code&gt;. Then, just as you did with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;email&lt;/code&gt;, force the values for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firstNameSearch&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lastNameSearch&lt;/code&gt; to be all lowercase before saving the data to Parse. Now when you want to perform a search, use the search properties &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firstNameSearch&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lastNameSearch&lt;/code&gt; instead of the other two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! You’ve achieved case insensitive searching in an environment that does not support it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/12/03/how-to-do-a-case-insensitive-search-using-parse-sdk/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/12/03/how-to-do-a-case-insensitive-search-using-parse-sdk</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-12-03T15:16:56+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>How To Present An Alert View Using UIAlertController When You Don't Have A View Controller</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the summer I updated a number of apps to iOS 9. A common tasks for me was replacing the deprecated &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UIAlertView&lt;/code&gt; with new &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt; class. Generally this is easy to do, but there is one scenario that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UIAlertView&lt;/code&gt; handles well that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt; doesn’t support at all: displaying an alert view from parts of your code without a reference to the current view controller, for instance, displaying an alert view from the app delegate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to display an alert view using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt; from a non-UI specific class such as the app delegate is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26952061/present-uialertcontroller-from-appdelegate&quot;&gt;common problem&lt;/a&gt;, and developers have found different &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26554894/how-to-present-uialertcontroller-when-not-in-a-view-controller&quot;&gt;workarounds&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/a/30941356&quot;&gt;One particular solution&lt;/a&gt; that caught my eye was this one from agilityvision, who writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At WWDC I stopped in at one of the labs and asked an Apple Engineer this same question: “What was the best practice for displaying a UIAlertController?” And he said they had been getting this question a lot and we joked that they should have had a session on it. He said that internally Apple is creating a UIWindow with a transparent UIViewController and then presenting the UIAlertController on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got me thinking about how I would solve the problem for apps I work on. Liking the approach mentioned by the Apple Engineer, I decided to give that a try. But unlike some of the other solutions that use a category, I decided to create a new class, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WPSAlertController&lt;/code&gt;, that is a subclass of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt;, and provide additional convenience methods making it possible to display an alert view with a single call…like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NSString *title = ...
NSString *message = ...
[WPSAlertController presentOkayAlertWithTitle:title message:message];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or display the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;localizedDescription&lt;/code&gt; from an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;NSError&lt;/code&gt; object:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[WPSAlertController presentOkayAlertWithError:error];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, since &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WPSAlertController&lt;/code&gt; is a subclass of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt;, you can create your alert the same way as you do using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UIAlertController&lt;/code&gt;. The only difference is you call &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;show&lt;/code&gt; to present the alert when you don’t have a view controller. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NSString *title = ...
NSString *message = ...
WPSAlertController *alertController = [WPSAlertController alertControllerWithTitle:title message:message preferredStyle:UIAlertControllerStyleAlert];
[alertController addAction:[UIAlertAction actionWithTitle:@&quot;OK&quot; style:UIAlertActionStyleDefault handler:^(UIAlertAction * _Nonnull action) {
  // Your code.
}]];

[alertController show];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can grab the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kirbyt/WPSKit/blob/master/WPSKit/UIKit/WPSAlertController.m&quot;&gt;source code for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WPSAlertController&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from my github repository and include it in your project, or use the entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kirbyt/WPSKit&quot;&gt;WPSKit.framework&lt;/a&gt; in your project if you want to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WPSAlertController&lt;/code&gt; plus other handy classes that I use when creating iOS apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/28/how-to-present-an-alert-view-using-uialertcontroller-when-you-dont-have-a-view-controller/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/28/how-to-present-an-alert-view-using-uialertcontroller-when-you-dont-have-a-view-controller</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-09-28T19:46:02+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Tags And Categories</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing a bit of tinkering here at thecave. I realized I was using categories as if they were tags and for one simple reason. I didn’t have a way to support tags. That is, until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tag support is provided in Jekyll, but I wanted something slightly different. I want the list of tags to appear at the end of a post just like the categories have for last couple of years. I searched for different ways to support tags with Jekyll, but I didn’t find anything suiting my needs. Then it occurred to me I could tweak the category plugins I use to work with tags, so that’s exactly what I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/recurser/jekyll-plugins&quot;&gt;Jekyll category plugins&lt;/a&gt; I use come from Dave Perretter. I made copies of &lt;em&gt;category_generator.rb&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;category_list_tags.rb&lt;/em&gt; naming the new plugins &lt;em&gt;tag_generator.rb&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;tag_list_tags.rb&lt;/em&gt;. Then I replace references to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;category&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tag&lt;/code&gt; in the source code. And BAM! I now have tag support at thecave.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the source code for the plugins in my site’s github &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kirbyt/site-www-thecave-com/tree/master/_plugins&quot;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/21/tags-and-categories/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/21/tags-and-categories</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-09-21T23:45:44+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Trying Something New To Avoid Feast Or Famine</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working for myself for nearly 12 years, and for the most part I love it. But there is one aspect of being an independent software developer that I could happily do without, the cycle of feast or famine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My products don’t always sell as well as I would like, so I rely on consulting work to keep my annual income at a level that allows me to provide for my family. Some years I do less consulting work than other years thanks to product sales. But other years, I must rely more on consulting to keep food on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Independent consulting work often times comes with the feast or famine cycle. Some months you have more work than you can handle, the feast, while other times you experience dry spells where you are not billing any hours, the famine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feast or famine is often times a result of not keeping a flowing pipeline of opportunities. But as a consultancy of one, keeping that pipeline flowing can be hard when you are focused on delivering a solution to a client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried different approach over the years to avoid the feast or famine cycle, and I continue trying new approaches each year. For instance, at the beginning of this year I agreed to work full time on a project for an agency. My hope was that by working with this agency, I would have a constant funnel of project work. However, the workload from the end-client was only part time at best, and since I was being paid hourly I didn’t earn nearly as much as I had planned&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. After a number of chats with the agency, I decided it was in the best interest for everyone for me to end the relationship so I could focus on projects that would get my income level back to where it was last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m trying something else new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While combing through my leads I came across a posting for &lt;a href=&quot;http://toptal.com/&quot;&gt;Toptal&lt;/a&gt;. Topal connects top freelance developers to businesses world wide looking to hire someone for a project. Now I know what many of my friends are thinking right now, this is another one of those crappy freelancer dot com, elancer, or up-something type of sites. And Toptal may in fact turn to be like those other sites. But I won’t know unless I try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the day I used guru.com to find iOS project work, and guess what? It worked and worked well. My first client iOS project came from guru, and I earned $36K off that one project. And my client became a repeat client of mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the guru site work today? In my opinion, no, it does not. But at least I tried it. And that’s what I’m &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.toptal.com/app&quot;&gt;joining Toptal&lt;/a&gt;, to try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Toptal works out for me and I’m able to reduce, or even eliminate the feast or famine cycle, then it’s a win win situation for everyone involved. And if it does not workout, well, I’m only out a couple hours of my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: After writing this post I learned more about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toptal.com/top-3-percent&quot;&gt;Toptal screening process&lt;/a&gt;. Their screening process alone separates them from the other sites mentioned in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I have since learned that in this situation I should have charged a fixed weekly or monthly rate instead of an hourly rate. This would have ensured I met my earning goals while still being available to the end-client even when the workload itself was lacking in hours.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/10/trying-something-new-to-avoid-feast-or-famine/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/10/trying-something-new-to-avoid-feast-or-famine</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-09-10T15:05:11+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>My Upcoming Share Extension Talk At 360idev-Min</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to be one of the speakers at the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;http://min.360idev.com&quot;&gt;360idev-min&lt;/a&gt; conference in Greenville, SC. In my talk I’ll share the things you need to know about when writing a share extension for your iOS app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan to attend &lt;a href=&quot;http://min.360idev.com&quot;&gt;360idev-min&lt;/a&gt;, then use the coupon code &lt;strong&gt;SpeakerFriend&lt;/strong&gt; to save $100 when purchasing your ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let me know if you are attending so we can meet up in person.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/07/my-upcoming-share-extension-talk-at-360idev-min/</link>
                <guid>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/07/my-upcoming-share-extension-talk-at-360idev-min</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-09-07T15:37:39+00:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>