<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general | thecave | Ramblings from a crotchety old man]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/category/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-25T19:57:27-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Weight Lost Continues]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/08/17/the-weight-lost-continues/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/08/17/the-weight-lost-continues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Weighed myself today. I&#8217;m down to 153 pounds. That&#8217;s 17 pounds lighter than I was 4 months ago. Only three more pounds to go before I hit my target weight.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sleeping In]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/07/20/sleeping-in/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2012/07/20/sleeping-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Rowan has recently been sleeping later into the mornings. This is great because Melanie and I both prefer sleeping in as well. I remember when Rowan first started sleeping through the night. He would wake up at 5:30 in the morning to start his day. I used to say, if only he would sleep until 6 am. And of course he did start sleeping until 6 am over time. When that happened, I starter saying, if only he would sleep until 6:30 am. As he slept later, I continued saying to myself, sleep until 7 am. Then it was 7:30 am. Then 8 am.</p>

<p>He is now consistently sleeping until sometime between 8 and 9 am each morning, and I&#8217;m loving it. But as the saying goes, all good things must come to an end. Lucky for me that end doesn&#8217;t come for another year when the kid start kindergarten. Until that time, I&#8217;m going to enjoy the extra sleep.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Cave Tent]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/08/22/the-cave-tent/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/08/22/the-cave-tent</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m not sure I would <a href='http://uncrate.com/stuff/the-cave-tent/'>buy this tent</a>, but I do like the name. An inflatable tent does sound interesting, but at 11.5 pounds plus a hand pump, I&#8217;m not sure it&#8217;s for me. Then again, my current &#8220;big&#8221; tent does take 5 to 10 minutes to setup and teardown.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I've Done This Weekend That I Normally Don't Do]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/08/21/things-ive-done-done-this-weekend-that-i-normally-dont-do/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/08/21/things-ive-done-done-this-weekend-that-i-normally-dont-do</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m in the final stagings of writing my book, and to help out, the wife gave me the okay to spend a few days in Vermont along. No wife. No kid. Just me and my laptop.</p>

<p>The trip to Vermont has, so far, been great. It&#8217;s given me the time I need to make some real progress on the completing the book. It&#8217;s also given me time to do things I don&#8217;t normal get to do anymore.</p>

<p>(Acknowledgement: Yes, I know what follows will likely anger the wife, but hey, I&#8217;m just trying to <a href='http://www.funnyordie.com/videos/2c8c4b3b58/chappelle-show-when-keeping-it-real-goes-wrong-1'>keep it real</a>.)</p>

<p>Things I&#8217;ve done this weekend that I normally don&#8217;t do: <ul>
<li>Write code for hours on end...uninterrupted.</li>
<li>Work the book...uninterrupted.</li>
<li>Go to sleep when I want, but more importantly wake up when I want.</li>
<li>Have hours of peace and quiet. No talking. No socializing with others.</li>
<li>And best of all, take a shower each day.</li>
</ul></p>

<p>The combination of sleep and alone time is just want I needed. And the daily showers, icing on the cake.</p>

<p>Thanks Melanie and Rowan for giving me this time.</p>

<p>Update: I do miss having reliable high-speed Internet access.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome Back]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/08/15/welcome-back/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2011/08/15/welcome-back</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey! What&#8217;s going on here? A new blog post after more than a year and a half?</p>

<p>Yes, that&#8217;s right. I&#8217;m slowing getting back into the swing of things, and one of those things is updating thecave.com with my pointless, boring, thoughts.</p>

<p>A lot has happened since that last post in December 2009. My company, <a href='http://whitepeaksoftware.com/'>White Peak Software</a>, has changed directions and is now focused entirely on iOS and Mac OS X development. Rowan has gotten older. And I&#8217;m nearing the end of writing my <a href='http://learnipadprogramming.com/'>first book</a>.</p>

<p>Time will tell if I&#8217;m truly back into the swing of things, but I&#8217;m hopeful I will have more time to post personal rants. Welcome back…to me.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>