<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general | thecave | Ramblings from a crotchety old man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-14T20:35:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone 6 and 6 Plus Pocket Test]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/10/iphone-6-plus-pocket-test/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/10/iphone-6-plus-pocket-test</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://flic.kr/p/pa23Ro"><img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5581/15198258832_1daebf3355_m.jpg" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> I printed out this <a href="http://arstechnica.com/apple/2014/09/how-big-is-the-iphone-6-plus-find-out-with-our-handy-paper-template/">iPhone 6 and 6 Plus paper template</a>. I cut out each template and taped cardboard to the back. Then I did a pocket test with each one. I tested each template with different pants and shorts that I wear often. I found that both the iPhone 6 and iPhone 6 Plus fit in all my pockets, but a corner of the iPhone 6 Plus cutout does stick out of the pocket on my gym shorts. I also found that while the iPhone 6 Plus does fit in the pockets of my Levis 501, my jeans of choice, the cutout was annoyingly noticeable when I sat down.</p>

<p>For those wondering, I’m 5 foot 6 and typically wear 32 inch waist pants and shorts. Taller folks with roomier pants and shorts might not notice the size difference of the Plus as much as I did.</p>

<p>As for holding the two cutouts, I found that the iPhone 6 cutout fits comfortably and securely in my hand. The iPhone 6 Plus cutout, on the other hand, just feels too big to hold and use with one hand. Granted I have small hands, but in acting like I’m interacting with a real iPhone I found I kept using two hands with the iPhone 6 Plus whereas I was comfortable using only one hand with the iPhone 6 cutout.</p>

<p>Conclusion: I will be buying the iPhone 6. The larger display of the iPhone 6 Plus would be nice for reading and watching shows and movies, but it’s just too damn large to be pocket device for me.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Simple. It's You, Not Me.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/03/dear-simple-its-you-not-me/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/03/dear-simple-its-you-not-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For more than a year and a half I’ve been in love with <a href="http://www.simple.com">Simple</a>, my online bank. From the very beginning it was as if Simple were designed specifically for me. Safe-to-spend and Goals changed how I managed and saved money, and it worked. It worked really well. So well in fact that I have more cash on hand today than I’ve had in years, and it’s all thanks to Simple. But something went wrong.</p>

<p>A month ago Simple did a major update to their backend system/platform, and since that dreadful day my financial world has been turned upside down. Payments were not sent while other scheduled payments simply disappear. My account balance has been all over the place. My account activity shows payments with the wrong payee name. And there have been times where the same debit appears in the account activity multiple times. It’s been a total nightmare.</p>

<p>For the last month I’ve been patient with Simple in hopes that they would resolve the problems caused by the platform upgrade, but instead of seeing improvements I continue to find and have more problems. I loved the Simple before the upgrade, but today I have zero confidence in Simple. And I don’t know how long it will be before I can trust Simple for my banking needs. Who knows, I may never trust them with my money again.</p>

<p>Following the advice of Simple’s own customer support representative, who said I should seek “alternative means of payment for the time being,” I decided to open a new account at <a href="http://ally.com">Ally</a>. It will take about a week before I have all my money moved over, but at least then I will know payments are going out as scheduled, and I do not have to worry about being late paying my rent.</p>

<p>I have to say I’m not thrilled about my breakup with Simple. Ally’s online experience is the same experience found with most other banks. Simple spoiled me with a better way (before the upgrade) to bank, and going back to a more traditional experience really sucks. But I would rather have a sucky online experience with a reliable bank than to have to worry about whether or not my bills are being paid on time.</p>

<p>Sorry Simple, but I must break up with you now. And it’s you, not me, that has caused this to happen. There might be a day in the future when we can get back together, but for the moment I  need a bank I can trust.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enjoy Less and Love More]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To some my life seems like a non-stop vacation. I’m a ski bum, a slacker, someone who rarely works. I’m always off on some adventure, snowboarding in the winter months, hiking and kayaking in the summer months. And from one point of view this is true. Over the last 12 months I have spent a great deal of my time snowboarding, hiking and kayaking. But I’ve also been focused on writing code and building apps.</p>

<p>Writing code and building software is a passion of mine. It’s the one thing I’m most passionate about. I’ve been writing code for more than 30 years, and I cannot image doing anything else with my life.</p>

<p>Over the last year I’ve been enjoying my passion more than ever. I’ve written more code in the last year than I did in the previous 3 years combined. I realized just this morning I have worked on and contributed to 22 different apps in the last 12 months, of which 15 are available in the App Store today. That’s a lot of time behind the keyboard.</p>

<p>Business is booming and life is good. So what changed? How is it I can live the ski bum, slacker life and still get a ton of work done? How is it I’m able to work on more apps today compared to a few years ago and still have time for adventure and family? The answer for me was to cut out those things from my life that I enjoy but do not love. (I already cut out those things I hate years ago.)</p>

<p>I stopped writing. I stopped organizing meet ups events. I stopped speaking at conferences. And while I haven’t completely stopped attending conferences and meet up events, I’ve cut way back. In the last 12 months I’ve attended one CocoaHeads event, one conference, and I socialized in San Francisco for only a 3 days during WWDC. This is a big change from just a few years ago when I was writing more words than code, attending and often times speaking at a conference every other month on average, and attending and organizing multiple social gatherings and meet ups each month.</p>

<p>I’ve also made changes to my daily routines. I don’t spend as much time reading news and following the latest happenings on social sites like App.net, Facebook and Twitter. I still make posts to these sites, but I limit the amount of time I spend reading what others have to say. And I’m not as active as I once was in chat rooms and irc. Cutting back on these distractions gives me more time each day to focus on things I love doing.</p>

<p>Some friends and family members have pointed out that I seem happier since moving to Stowe, and they are right. I am happier these days, but it’s not just because I moved to Stowe. It’s because I’m doing more of what I love, and I accomplished this by doing less of what I only enjoy.</p>

<p>By not doing the things I enjoy, I’ve been able to spend more time doing the things I love.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Organizing Events]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/06/not-organizing-events/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/06/not-organizing-events</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I lived in NYC I organized and ran events for computer geeks like me. It was a lot of fun, and a great way to meet new people. Then I moved to Salem, Mass, a suburb of Boston, and again I organized and ran events in Salem and Boston. And again it was a lot of fun and a great way to meet new people.</p>

<p>I now live in Stowe, Vermont, and as of right now I have zero desire to organize and run events for like-minded computer nerds. After being so involved organizing meetups and such for over 10 years, it’s nice to take a break. That said, I sometimes wish someone had a tech-focused garthering in Stowe. I wonder how long before I end up organizing something.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross Posting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/03/14/cross-posting/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/03/14/cross-posting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to go back to cross posting between ADN, Twitter, and Facebook. I’m not as active as I once was on any one of these social networks, so I figured cross posting won’t cause too much noise in the streams of followers. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>