<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-27T14:00:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/27/finally/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-27T13:54:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/27/finally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Northeast has been getting slammed with a major snow storm, but unfortunately Stowe, Vermont, is too far northwest to get the full force of the storm. I had hoped for a bit of new snow overnight, but it didn’t happen. So I waited before hitting the slopes this morning in hopes the edge of the storm would inch its way into the Stowe, but it didn’t happen. So Melanie and I hit the slopes anyways, braving the -26 degrees Fahrenheit wind chill. We got in two runs before deciding today would be a good day for a lunch date. So we left the hill, and headed for lunch in town. And then the snow finally came…guess I’ll be hitting the hill first thing tomorrow morning. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eliminating Distractions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/18/eliminating-distractions/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-18T13:49:47-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/18/eliminating-distractions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dan Counsell wrote an excellent post about <a href="http://dancounsell.com/articles/removing-distractions">removing distractions</a>. In the post he talks about how he removed distractions by removing social media apps such as Twitter and Facebook from his iPhone. He’s done other things too such as reading a book instead of checking Twitter, and he started a “No Technology Day” on Saturdays, which is something I think I might start doing as well.</p>

<p>Over the last year I too have been eliminating distractions in my life by spending more of my time <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing what I love</a> and changing the way I use social networks. Changing the way I use social networks is one of the reasons I wrote my app <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>. With Cross Post I can share pictures, thoughts, and comments on Facebook, Twitter, and App.net without the worry of being distracted by those sites. Cross Post sends updates to social media sites, but it does not read the time lines or streams from those sites. Cross Post is a tool for making, not reading, micro-blog posts, hence it’s ability to help eliminate distractions. </p>

<p>I did one other thing to help me eliminate distractions. I turned off notifications on all but the most important apps on my iPhone<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>. Unlike Dan I did not remove the social media apps from my phone. I still want to be able to reply to mentions via my iPhone, which is why I left the apps installed. And in the case of Facebook, it’s the easiest way for me to get news about my family via my sister down in Mississippi, so I still check Facebook once or twice a day. But I do not receive notifications from any of the social media apps on my phone.</p>

<p>So how can you start eliminating distractions in your life. I suggest starting with Dan’s new website, <a href="http://thegreatdisconnect.info">The Great Disconnect</a>. It contains articles, videos and information about how to remove distractions by living a less connected life. Check it out because we all can benefit from being a bit less connected these days.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Examples of app that are important to me and which I still have notifications turned on are ones for my bank and credit cards. I want to make sure I’m alerted if a fraudulent charge is ever made against one of my accounts. Slack is another app that I use with notifications turned on since I use this for work purposes. Beyond that, I have notifications turned off. Oh, and in case you were wondering, I let sites like Twitter notify me of mentions via email, and I only check email a few times a day. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New kirbyturner.com Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/new-kirbyturnercom-site/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-15T16:20:35-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/new-kirbyturnercom-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have owned the vanity domain name <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">kirbyturner.com</a> for a long time, but I didn’t anything with it after buying it. That changed back when I was writing <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">Learning iPad Programming</a>. My publisher asked that I setup a website that talks about me, so I finally put kirbyturner.com to use. Unfortunately I never liked the look of the site. I used a bland template to create the website quickly. The site was ugly, but it served its purpose. Then Justin Williams created a new “professional web site” for <a href="http://www.justinw.me">himself</a>.</p>

<p>My first thought after seeing Justin’s new site was, “Wow! That looks really nice.” My second thought was, “Man my site sucks donkey balls.” So I spent the last couple of days working on a new look for <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">kirbyturner.com</a>. I just finished the site, and I can say with 100% certainty that the new site looks much, much better than my <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/16288802435/">old site</a>. Thanks for the inspiration, Justin.</p>

<p>Take a look at the new and improved <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">kirbyturner.com</a>, and let me know what you think.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snow is White, Not Brown and Green]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/snow-is-white-not-brown-and-green/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-15T13:22:07-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/snow-is-white-not-brown-and-green</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This screen shot says it all.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/16286890482"><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8571/16286890482_5fc6e96929_n.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goodbye Fitbit Ultra, Hello Fitbit One]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/14/goodbye-fitbit-ultra-hello-fitbit-one/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-14T19:42:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/14/goodbye-fitbit-ultra-hello-fitbit-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On November 15, 2011, I started using my Fitbit Ultra, and after only 1157 days I have finally switched to the Fitbit One.</p>

<p>The Ultra has been an outstanding device, and it’s darn tough too. Mine has bits of plastic missing and the casing has separated on one side. And yet the thing continues working. The only problem is the button, which stopped working two days ago. That’s why I decided to upgrade. Still, the Ultra has been one of the best little devices I’ve ever owned.</p>

<p>Together the Ultra and I have taken 7,625,047 steps, climbed the equivalent of 22,711 floors, walked 3,401.97 miles, and burned 5,035,126. My Ultra was with me on my Long Trail thru hike as well as countless other hikes. It’s been with me to New York, San Francisco, Paris, Amsterdam, Montreal, and many other places. It’s the last thing I pull out of my pocket each night before bed, and the first thing I put back in my pocket after waking up. In all that time I’ve left my Ultra behind for fewer than 5 days. But as of this afternoon I’m no longer using my Ultra. I’m now using my new Fitbit One.</p>

<p>I’m excited to use the One. It certainly has features not available on the Ultra, most notably the ability to sync wirelessly over Bluetooth. The Ultra requires plugging in to sync, and often times I would go 6 or 7 days without syncing because it wasn’t convenient for me to plug in. But with the One and the option to sync via my iPhone, I will be syncing more frequently. </p>

<p>The One is smaller than the Ultra, and I have to say I’m really digging the smaller size. The display on the One is better than the Ultra too, but then again the display on my Ultra looked good when it was new. My Ultra has been through a lot and the wear and tear is showing on it. That might be why the One’s display looks much better to me right now.</p>

<p>I do have a couple of minor issues with the One. First, the wireless sync might mean I forget to charge my One as frequently as I did the Ultra. Time will tell if this is a valid concern or not for me. The other issue is that I rarely clipped my Ultra onto myself, but I did do it from time to time…mostly in the morning if I walked around the house in my boxers. I would clip the Ultra to my boxers until I put on pjs, shorts, or pants. The One comes with a clip, but since I rarely need the clip I’m not planning to use it. But there will still be those rare early mornings when I wish I could clip my One to my boxers. Maybe I’ll keep the clip on my nightstand next to my bed so it’s easy to grab when I do need it.</p>

<p>Hmmm, so it seems I don’t really have any issues with the One…at least not yet. And based on my experience with the Ultra, I don’t expect to have any issues with the One either. I’m hoping the One is as good, if not better, than the Ultra. Time will tell. I’ll try to remember to write a follow up about my One in, say, 1157 days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>