<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-14T20:23:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goodbye Fitbit Ultra, Hello Fitbit One]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/14/goodbye-fitbit-ultra-hello-fitbit-one/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-14T19:42:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/14/goodbye-fitbit-ultra-hello-fitbit-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On November 15, 2011, I started using my Fitbit Ultra, and after only 1157 days I have finally switched to the Fitbit One.</p>

<p>The Ultra has been an outstanding device, and it’s darn tough too. Mine has bits of plastic missing and the casing has separated on one side. And yet the thing continues working. The only problem is the button, which stopped working two days ago. That’s why I decided to upgrade. Still, the Ultra has been one of the best little devices I’ve ever owned.</p>

<p>Together the Ultra and I have taken 7,625,047 steps, climbed the equivalent of 22,711 floors, walked 3,401.97 miles, and burned 5,035,126. My Ultra was with me on my Long Trail thru hike as well as countless other hikes. It’s been with me to New York, San Francisco, Paris, Amsterdam, Montreal, and many other places. It’s the last thing I pull out of my pocket each night before bed, and the first thing I put back in my pocket after waking up. In all that time I’ve left my Ultra behind for fewer than 5 days. But as of this afternoon I’m no longer using my Ultra. I’m now using my new Fitbit One.</p>

<p>I’m excited to use the One. It certainly has features not available on the Ultra, most notably the ability to sync wirelessly over Bluetooth. The Ultra requires plugging in to sync, and often times I would go 6 or 7 days without syncing because it wasn’t convenient for me to plug in. But with the One and the option to sync via my iPhone, I will be syncing more frequently. </p>

<p>The One is smaller than the Ultra, and I have to say I’m really digging the smaller size. The display on the One is better than the Ultra too, but then again the display on my Ultra looked good when it was new. My Ultra has been through a lot and the wear and tear is showing on it. That might be why the One’s display looks much better to me right now.</p>

<p>I do have a couple of minor issues with the One. First, the wireless sync might mean I forget to charge my One as frequently as I did the Ultra. Time will tell if this is a valid concern or not for me. The other issue is that I rarely clipped my Ultra onto myself, but I did do it from time to time…mostly in the morning if I walked around the house in my boxers. I would clip the Ultra to my boxers until I put on pjs, shorts, or pants. The One comes with a clip, but since I rarely need the clip I’m not planning to use it. But there will still be those rare early mornings when I wish I could clip my One to my boxers. Maybe I’ll keep the clip on my nightstand next to my bed so it’s easy to grab when I do need it.</p>

<p>Hmmm, so it seems I don’t really have any issues with the One…at least not yet. And based on my experience with the Ultra, I don’t expect to have any issues with the One either. I’m hoping the One is as good, if not better, than the Ultra. Time will tell. I’ll try to remember to write a follow up about my One in, say, 1157 days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Plans For A Third Edition]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/08/no-plans-for-a-third-edition/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-08T08:18:28-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/08/no-plans-for-a-third-edition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A number of people have recently asked if there will be a third edition of <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/">Learning iPad Programming</a>. The short answer is no, there are no plans. There are many reasons why I decided to not update the book, but a few key reasons stand out more than others.</p>

<h2 id="i-enjoy-writing-but-i-dont-love-it">I Enjoy Writing, But I Don’t Love It</h2>

<p>Writing a tech book was on my bucket list for many years, and writing has long been an interest of mine. But writing a book like Learning iPad Programming takes a lot of time. The first two editions of the book consumed most of my time and life for nearly two and a half years, and this left me feeling stressed and depressed. That’s when I came to the conclusion that my time is better spent <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing things I love</a> and cutting back on doing things that I only enjoy. </p>

<p>If I had all the time in the world, then I certainly would consider updating the book each year or two. But my time is limited, and writing apps, snowboarding, spending time with my family, and going on outdoor adventures are all things I love doing. And those things leave me with little extra time to do things I only enjoy.</p>

<h2 id="no-financial-motivation">No Financial Motivation</h2>

<p>My <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">company</a> was booming just before I started work on the first edition of Learning iPad Programming. I saw a steady increase in product revenue year after year for five straight years, and I was becoming less dependent on consulting and contract work. In other words, I was on track for making a living selling my own products. In fact, that’s partly why I agreed to write a book in the first place. In my mind the book was another product in my expanding line of diversified products. But it turns out writing a book is hard. And writing the first edition was probably one of the hardest things I’ve ever done.</p>

<p>I had never written a book before, so I ended up spending a lot of time learning how to write a book. I also tried a number of different systems to get me into the habit of writing. All of this extra time spent on learning to write, how to get pass mental blocks, how to stay motivated, how to make daily progress, even the smallest bit, took my focus away from my company. And at one point I knew the only way I would finish the book was to devote 100% of my time to it, so that’s exactly what I did. I stopped working for a few months so I could work on the book full time.</p>

<p>All the time spent away from my company resulted in lost revenue as my product sales started a downward trend and I had zero time to offset the drop in product revenue with consulting. That meant I had to start living off of borrowed money. By the time the book was done I had well over $50K in credit card debt. And while sales of the book were great<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, the royalty payments I received were not enough to pay down the debt, debt that I’m still working on paying off today. </p>

<h2 id="mistakes-and-mishandling">Mistakes and Mishandling</h2>

<p>The third and possibly the number one reason there are no plans for a third edition were the mistakes and mishandling of both editions of the book by the publisher. The publisher’s decision to release the second edition two weeks before WWDC 2013 was the final straw for me. Apple announced iOS 7 with its new look at that WWDC making the second edition obsolete only two weeks after hitting the bookstores.</p>

<p>There were other mistakes made throughout my time working with the publisher, from production problems to not completing planned projects. But it was the handling, or as I call it, the mishandling of the second edition that led to my decision to not continue updating the book. </p>

<p>If the book were self-published, then things might be different. But as it stands Learning iPad Programming is owned by the publisher, and everything other than the final manuscript is controlled by the publisher. I certainly have some say and can provide input, but I don’t really have any control once the manuscript is turned over to them. And given the past mistakes and mishandling of projects, I cannot see myself working with the same group for a third edition (my editor and her assistant excluded - they were outstanding to work with).</p>

<h1 id="there-you-have-it">There You Have It</h1>

<p>So there you have it, the main reasons there are no plans for a third edition of Learning iPad Programming. I admit it makes me rather sad when I think about it not doing new editions of the book. I poured my heart and soul into the first two editions, and I had high hopes that there would be many more editions for years to come. But at the end of the day it just not worth struggle, stress, and toll that the first two editions took on me, my family, and our financial wellbeing.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Of the millions of books available on Amazon, my book was in the top 1100 for a few months. This is an outstanding and rare achievement for a tech book, and one of my proudest moments during my career. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Checkout The New Rowan T Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/checkout-the-new-rowan-t-site/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T13:49:49-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/checkout-the-new-rowan-t-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you haven’t seen it yet, be sure to checkout the new <a href="http://www.rowanturner.net">Rowan T</a> website. I moved it to Jekyll, updated it with a new site template, and I’ve starting sharing more about what’s going on with Rowan…after a two and a half year hiatus. So pop over to <a href="http://www.rowanturner.net">www.rowanturner.net</a> and see what the kid has been up to lately.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Minutes Of Writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/15-minutes-of-writing/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T13:19:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/15-minutes-of-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend, Greg Raiz, talks about <a href="http://www.raizlabs.com/graiz/2015/01/05/better-goals-via-better-systems/">using a system to achieve goals</a>. The particular goal he wants to achieve is writing more.</p>

<p>I’ve tried using a system similar to what Greg describes, but I fail each time I try. My system, or goal as I still often call it, has been to write an hour each day. Writing an hour day, often times more, was easy when I was writing my books, but I can’t seem to get into the routine now that I’m done with book writing (for now). I realized after reading Greg’s post that I’ve been doing it wrong. </p>

<p>Greg’s plan is to write about 100 words a day, or for about 15 minutes a day, which is about the amount of time he needs to write 100 words. And that sounds like a much more reasonable system than writing for an hour a day.</p>

<p>I wish I could write for at least an hour a day, but it’s just not in me to do that right now. Sure, if I were focused on writing a book then I would have no problem writing an hour a day. In fact, I would write more. But writing a book not my focus. Writing apps is my focus. And 15 minutes a day sounds like a perfect way for me to get back into writing.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Made Some Fixes To The Blog Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/28/made-some-fixes-to-the-blog-site/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-28T19:01:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/28/made-some-fixes-to-the-blog-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before doing some work today I decided to make some improvements to my blog site. I thought I would be playing with the site for only an hour or so, but instead it took most of the day. Typical when dealing with programming issues in an unfamiliar environment. </p>

<p>This site, as well as <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com">my company blog site</a>, uses <a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> to generate a static HTML version of the site that is in turned hosted on a server for your viewing pleasure. I noticed a while back that categories with embedded spaces, such as <em>cross post</em>, weren’t accessible from the categories list. The embedded space was being replaced with a dash. Also, the RSS feed was not including the time of the post, only the date. So I set out to fix these problems.</p>

<p>I started with the time problem first. I learned that Jekyll does not include the time of the post unless you include the <code>date</code> parameter in the front matter. Adding the parameter is easy enough to do, but I decided I wanted to make it even easier for me. So I created a Rakefile that has a <code>new_post</code> task. I could have used an existing Rakefile, maybe even the one from Octopress, but I decided it would be more fun to write my own. Turns out writing a Rakefile is pretty simple, and I had my <code>new_post</code> task working quickly. </p>

<p>The <code>new_post</code> task I wrote create a new markdown file for the post. The task also generates the YAML front matter for the post including the <code>date</code> parameter with the current local time. This solves my time problem in the RSS feed for new post. I thought about making a fix for older post, but I decided it wasn’t worth the effort.</p>

<p>Using the Rakefile to create a new post makes so much sense that I decided to add a <code>deploy</code> task the Rakefile. I’ve been using a shell script I wrote a few years ago to generate the Jekyll site then commit it to the <em>gh-pages</em> branch of the site’s git <a href="https://github.com/kirbyt/site-www-thecave-com">repo</a>. I thought it would be a fun exercise to re-implement this in the Rakefile. At the same time I decided to change how the files are committed to the branch. Instead of working from a single local git repo, I decided to clone the repo to a second <em>_deploy</em> directory, then copy the <em>_site</em> files to that directory. Turns out this was fairly simple to do as well. </p>

<p>With that work out of the way I turned my focus to the categories name problem. Turns out it was caused by a space replacement in the Jekyll plugin I use to generate the categories list. That was the easiest, fastest fix of the day.</p>

<p>With a smile on my face and feeling of success I decided to do one more thing. I decided to update my install of Jekyll. And this is when everything fell apart. The sense of success and feeling of being productive evaporated quickly. Long story short, turns out I had rvm and rbenv installed at the same time, and apparently having both installed at the same time causes problems when updating gems. Unfortunately it took me a long while to figure out what had happened. I didn’t realize rvm was installed, but once I did I uninstalled it. I did another update and made sure I had rbenv-gem-rehash installed. </p>

<p>All is well now. In fact, the only reason I’m writing this post is to make sure everything is working as expected. And now that I have a faster way to create new posts, I’m hoping to post here more frequently. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>