<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-08T08:58:46-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stuck Working For Others]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/04/stuck-working-for-others/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-04T16:31:38-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/04/stuck-working-for-others</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love this quote from Amy Hoy:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you only do what pays immediately, you will be stuck working for other people. Or you will be stuck doing what other people want you to do…forever.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The quote come from her talk about <a href="https://unicornfree.com/2015/be-your-own-angel-a-revenue-model-for-slow-startups?inf_contact_key=33d23f3cc326dbb9432ca21551e5c05960ba9e460978b642f3bc69a5e6171317">being your own angel investor</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where I Blog These Days]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-19T09:40:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve recently, and “recently” as in the last couple of years, cut back on the number of blog sites I have. I’m down to three sites now, and that seems manageable. The sites are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/">thecave.com</a><br />
  That’s this site. It’s my personal blog, and it’s where I post most often. I talk about everything from what’s going on with me personally to snowboarding to programming. The site is broken down into categories, and I have plans to publish an RSS feed for each category so readers can filter out topics they might consider noise.</li>
  <li><a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/">blog.whitepeaksoftware.com</a><br />
  This is my company blog site. The focus of this site is to talk about the company and the products I sell. Granted I’m doing a horrible job at keeping up with the posts. That’s probably one of the many reasons my stuff doesn’t sell as well as it did a few years back.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.rowanturner.net/">rowanturner.net</a><br />
  Yep, my son has his own website. But he has no interest in making posts here, so I do it for him. I usually post pictures and videos of Rowan and his friends off having fun. My mom might be the only person reading this site regularly, but that’s fine. I’ll keep posting because I like looking back on past articles and reliving fun moments with my kid.</li>
</ul>

<p>These sites each have RSS feeds, so you don’t have to remember to visit. And some day I’ll do a better job of mentioning when new posts are available on the various social networks for those who don’t want to subscribe to the feeds. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No WWDC Or SF Trip]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-14T09:20:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple announced the dates for this year’s WWDC, and once again a lottery is being used to decide who gets to buy a ticket. I have no interesting is attending WWDC other than to attend the labs since I do have questions I would love to ask an Apple engineer. But it’s not worth spending $1599 on a ticket just for that. </p>

<p>Likewise, I’m struggling to justify spending the money to stay in San Francisco the week of WWDC just to hang out with friends and drink beer. Certainly reconnecting with friends and making news ones is very enjoyable, but there are cheaper ways for me to do that. So I’ve decided I’m not going to SF for this year’s WWDC. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Affordable Cloud Storage With Amazon Cloud Drive]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/27/affordable-cloud-storage-with-amazon-cloud-drive/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-27T06:52:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/27/affordable-cloud-storage-with-amazon-cloud-drive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday Amazon announced new <a href="https://www.amazon.com/clouddrive/pricing">pricing plans</a> for their cloud storage offering named <a href="https://www.amazon.com/clouddrive/home">Cloud Drive</a>. You can store unlimited number of photos for $11.99 per year, or you can store unlimited number of files for $59.99. The later is a no-brainer for me as I have been looking for an affordable cloud storage solution like this.</p>

<p>Currently I use a number of different services for cloud storage. I use <a href="https://db.tt/Y2NovyiG">Dropbox</a> to sync files between computers and devices. The files I keep on Dropbox are ones I need immediate access to. In other words, these are the files I need to have on my laptop while also having access from other computers and devices such as my iPhone. </p>

<p>I use <a href="https://secure.backblaze.com/r/00ytw8">Backblaze</a> to backup all the files on my laptop to the cloud. It’s my lifeline should something unexpected happen to my laptop. For photos I use <a href="https://secure.smugmug.com/signup?Coupon=8ZK2smzZYAS1I">SmugMug</a>, but more recently I’ve been using <a href="http://www.flickr.com">Flickr</a> more than SmugMug. And I use Rackspace Cloud File for my CDN. That’s content delivery network for my non-geeky friends reading this.</p>

<p>The problem with these different cloud storage providers is that I still had no easy way to upload and store files that I don’t need frequent access to. I don’t like to throw away data, but I also don’t need documents I wrote back in 2003 wasting space on my laptop. Dropbox has a way to not sync selected folders, but I don’t trust it. Plus, it’s not as straight forward as uploading and storing selected files.</p>

<p>Rackspace Cloud File works well for archiving my old data, but it can become costly if I have multi-terabytes of data to store. Same is true for Amazon S3, which I considered using in the past. In fact, when Amazon announced S3 Glacier I thought I had found the perfect cloud storage solution for me, but it’s not easy to use.</p>

<p>Flickr and SmugMug are great for storing photos and videos, and they both make it easy to upload new ones. Heck, Flickr will even automatically upload new photos taken on my iPhone for me. It doesn’t get much easier than that. But these two only support photos and videos, and I have other file types I want to store in the cloud.</p>

<p>So when I first heard about Amazon’s new pricing for Cloud Drive I thought, “Finally, an affordable cloud storage solution that fixes my needs for archiving old data.” At $60 per year for unlimited storage, I would be a fool not to try it out. But I don’t even need to spend the $60 right now. Amazon is offering a 3-month free trial.</p>

<p>Cloud Drive has desktop software for your Mac (and I’m guessing Windows too) to upload files, but I’m not a fan of the desktop software. It doesn’t let me pick where I want to store the files I’m uploading, and I like to use a very specific directory structure for my files. </p>

<p>While the Cloud Drive desktop software doesn’t suite my needs, the Cloud Drive web interface does. I can organize my storage area to my liking, create new folders and upload files to specific folders within the file system. And that’s just what I’ve been doing…uploading and organizing files - a few gigs so far to test out the service.</p>

<p>I do, however, have one complaint about Cloud Drive. The Cloud Drive app for iOS only shows photos and videos. I want access to all the files stored on my Cloud Drive. Hopefully Amazon will change this soon, or maybe it’s an opportunity for me to write a new app. There is, after all, an API for Cloud Drive.</p>

<p>Amazon Cloud Drive is the solution I’ve been looking for to archive my old data to the cloud. I’ll continue using external hard drives, Dropbox, Backblaze and such for backups, but my days with SmugMugs might be numbered. Still, I’m excited to finally have an affordable cloud storage solution for my old data.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dress Code For Remote Job]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/21/dress-code-for-remote-job/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-21T08:27:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/21/dress-code-for-remote-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came across one of the silliest benefits I’ve seen for a remote developer job: casual dress code. From the job <a href="https://weworkremotely.com/jobs/1323">posting</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>What’s In It For You</p>

  <ul>
    <li>Medical and dental benefits</li>
    <li>Paid vacation and holidays</li>
    <li>Remote work environment … work where you work best</li>
    <li>Dynamic and dedicated team</li>
    <li>Data/Cell (internet) stipend</li>
    <li>Casual dress code</li>
    <li>Most of all smart and driven team members that love to collaborate, seek feedback, and improve</li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>

<p>I’m not sure I would want to work for a remote company that has a dress code even if it’s a casual dress code. I like coding in my pjs on many days, which means I would be in violation of the casual dress code. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>