<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: skiing | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/skiing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-03T21:42:26-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Return To Whistler Blackcomb]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/03/our-return-to-whistler-blackcomb/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-03T20:50:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/03/our-return-to-whistler-blackcomb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Years ago I, with help from a couple of friends, organized an annual snowboarding trip to Whistler Blackcomb. Even after the annual trips were no more, Melanie and I continued visiting Whistler once every year or two. Our last Whistler trip was in 2007, and we’ve been wanting to return for many years. But it just hasn’t worked out for us. That is until this year when we finally made our return to Whistler, and we brought Rowan with us. </p>

<p>In the same spirit as those past Whistler trips<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, I decided to write a daily blog post about our trip. But because I didn’t have a reliable Internet connection at the condo, I wasn’t able to publish the posts at the end of each day. So I combined the postings from each day into a single post that I have published them here. Enjoy.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-01-feb-23-2015">Day 0.1 (Feb 23, 2015)</h1>

<p>We started our trek to Whistler today. It’s the first time back to Whistler for Melanie and me since 2007. For those who might not know, Whistler was like a second home mountain for me for a while. I even had a season pass there one year. But we haven’t been back since Rowan was born. </p>

<p>Our day began with a 4 hour car drive to Boston. The Delta flights out of Burlington were full, so we had to fly out of Logan. We flew to Minneapolis St. Paul for our first leg of the trek. We stayed overnight before continuing on to Vancouver the next morning. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8618/16710139785_725dfcca0f_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="weather">Weather</h2>

<p>Recently I’ve been joking that our vacation in Whistler will feel more like a spring vacation than a winter one. As I type this the current temperature in Stowe is -27°F and 36°F in Whistler. That’s a 63°F temperature difference. Makes me think I should have packed a pair of shorts. </p>

<p>The weather in Whistler has been less than ideal. They haven’t received much new snow in recent weeks. And we’ve received more total snow in Stowe this season so far, 225 inches compared to the 186 inches in Whistler. On the plus side, there’s been plenty of sunshine in Whistler, which means lots of great views of the mountains. </p>

<p>Despite the lack of fresh snow and powder - 3 to 4 inches is in the forecast for tomorrow (woohoo!) - I’m sure we are going to have a great time. And Rowan is going to be amazed at the sheer size of the mountains. </p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-02-feb-24-2015">Day 0.2 (Feb 24, 2015)</h1>

<p>Our second and final leg to Whistler went smoothly. We even arrived earlier than expected giving us time to walk around the village. Rowan was tired by this point so he became a bit grouchy, but in general he was a real trooper the entire day. </p>

<p>Rowan was very excited to see how close to the gondolas we’re staying. We’re at the Executive Inn, and it’s the closest to the gondolas Melanie and I have ever stayed. We are literally a one to two minute walk to the lifts. </p>

<h2 id="a-first-for-me">A First For Me</h2>

<p>When we arrived in Vancouver we were starving. It was way past our normal lunch time thanks to the time change. The only food option for us was Tim Hortons, so we grabbed sandwiches from there. After visiting Canada for all these years - my first visit to Canada was in 1992 - it’s hard to believe this is the first time I’ve eaten at Tim Hortons. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8599/16502851387_470ba232a9_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="wheres-the-snow">Where’s The Snow</h2>

<p>The drive up the up the Sea to Sky highway was beautiful. Nothing but sunshine, which meant awesome views. But at the same time it was a bit depressing. There was no snow. Even as we arrived into Whistler, the lack of snow was obvious and not just from the sides of the road. Many trails on the lower parts of the mountains were bare, and many trails were already closed for the season. It felt more like late spring than late February. </p>

<p>I’m really curious what the upper part of the mountains will be like.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8601/16024150634_c8f88975bc_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-1-feb-25-2015">Day 1 (Feb 25, 2015)</h1>

<p>We finally hit the slopes today. After hearing about days and days of sunshine in Whistler, we get a cloudy day on the hill. And it was a bit colder than recent days. The snow was so so, about on par with the conditions during the second WASTED trip. And there was a lot more ice than I expected. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8654/16458871298_255f10c5a8_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="the-runaway-snowboard">The Runaway Snowboard</h2>

<p>The funniest part of the day happened before the first run. Outside the Roundhouse, Melanie asked me to take a picture of Rowan and her. For some reason Rowan let go of his snowboard while I took the picture. Next thing we know is his snowboard is heading down the mountain by itself. </p>

<p>I strapped on my board in hopes of catching it, but his board was heading down the hill too fast. We saw it go into a small section of woods, so I started my search for the run away board there. Thankfully I found his board jammed up between two trees. Had the board been six inches to rider’s left it would have exited the tree patch, and it might have been lost forever. We got lucky. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8629/16459039930_cef7a9d0ba_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="so-so-conditions">So So Conditions</h2>

<p>Rowan wasn’t into the conditions today. I don’t blame him. It wasn’t the best. The spring conditions from the previous day turned to hard pack when the colder temps rolled in. So we did 5 runs then called it a day.</p>

<h2 id="peak-2-peak">Peak 2 Peak</h2>

<p>The Peak 2 Peak gondola is a nice addition to the resort. We did a few runs on Whistler then jumped over the Blackcomb, something I wouldn’t consider doing before the Peak 2 Peak lift was installed.</p>

<h2 id="new-snow">New Snow</h2>

<p>Snow was falling when we left the top of the mountain. I hope it continues through the night, but I doubt it will. Still, looking forward to hitting the hill again tomorrow. </p>

<h2 id="another-disappointment">Another Disappointment</h2>

<p>The snow conditions weren’t the only disappointment today. We stopped by Longhorn Saloon for après ski and was told that kids until 21 are not allowed in after 2 pm. So no poutine for us today.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-2-feb-26-2015">Day 2 (Feb 26, 2015)</h1>

<p>Today was a bit better than yesterday. Moods were better too, which helped. </p>

<p>We rode Blackcomb in the morning, then took the Peak 2 Peak over to Whistler at lunchtime, which is where we stayed for the rest of the day. Visibility was good this morning, but very poor this afternoon after the clouds moved in. </p>

<p>We decided to wait for the glass bottom gondola on the Peak 2 Peak. Rowan and I enjoyed looking down below us. Melanie didn’t seem to care for it much. </p>

<p>While on the Whistler side, we went to the Tree Fort. Rowan had a lot of fun climbing up the fort and sliding back down. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8677/16633355726_02fd491174_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="swim-time">Swim Time</h2>

<p>Turns out the condo we rented has a heated swimming pool and hot tub, so we took Rowan swimming this afternoon, which he loved. </p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-3-feb-27-2015">Day 3 (Feb 27, 2015)</h1>

<p>I went out for a few runs before meeting up with Rowan and Melanie. Snow conditions were the same, but it was partly cloudy so we had some great views. </p>

<p>We had lunch at Longhorn since we can’t go there for après ski. The poutine there are soooo dang good. And we did a run from the top of Harmony Express to the bottom. </p>

<p>Rowan is finally over his jet lag, so we walked around the village. The new ice skating rink is nice, and Rowan wants to hit it tomorrow. The playground is all new too. Well, new since my last visit. </p>

<p>Rowan was excited to “discover” the ice rink and playground. Guess we’ll be visiting North Village more over the next couple of days. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8671/16682625426_c24c8e63fc_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-4-feb-28-2015">Day 4 (Feb 28, 2015)</h1>

<p>On Day 4 we took our time getting out to the mountain. Put quite frankly, riding hard pack day after day gets rather boring. Melanie and Rowan did a bit of shopping in the morning. When we did finally hit the hill, we did one long run down to Merlins for lunch. And of course we had to order the Nacho Daddy even though it was way to big for the three of us. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8605/16521165420_9761b71774_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After lunch we headed back up Blackcomb and did a few more runs. There wasn’t a cloud in the sky so we had plenty of incredible views. We rode 7th Heaven at the end of the day, and got last chair there twice - we were prepared to hike out but the lifties let us back on for one more ride up. We rode from the top of 7th Heaven down to Whistler Village to finish up our day on the mountain. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8582/16501194227_eac6f20595_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Afterwards we went to the swimming pool and hot tub. I stayed out of both opting to throw a ball from the side of the pool to Rowan who was playing in the pool. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8626/16501199847_3520680d7f_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Later in the evening we went ice skating, which I suck at, Rowan’s getting better at skating, and Melanie was the best of us three. The ice rink in the village is really nice. It’s outdoors and has a small hockey play area in the center. It’s also free to skate if you have your own skates, or $5 to rent a pair. Melanie wasn’t overly excited at first about ice skating, but when it was over she said she’s glad we did it and that she had a lot of fun skating. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8665/16708483725_ef98a3f1a3_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<hr />

<h1 id="day-5-mar-1-2015">Day 5 (Mar 1, 2015)</h1>

<p>Today was our final day on the hill. We took it easy today since the snow conditions were unchanged - still hard packed. We slept in this morning. When we did finally hit the slopes we did a warm up run then we headed straight for the Peak Chair and the top of Whistler. We rode back down to the village where we had lunch at Dubh Linn Gate. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8593/16088539943_c88384e301_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After lunch we headed back up to the Roundhouse so Melanie could shop for a shirt. Then we took the Peak 2 Peak gondola over to Blackcomb. Rowan wanted to play at the castle one last time. Unfortunately it was closed by the time we got there, so we made our way back down to the village. </p>

<p>When we got back to the condo, Rowan said he soooo tired. Melanie suggested relaxing at the condo for a bit, but he would have none of that. He wanted to go swimming, and he said the swimming pool would wake him up. So off Melanie and Rowan went while I stayed behind to shower.</p>

<p>We ended our final night in Whistler watching the Fire and Ice show. Three snowboarders and three skiers doing tricks off of a big kicker and through a ring of fire. Rowan was most excited to see the back flips. He had been wanting to see someone do a back flip since the start of the trip, and he got to see a number of them at the show including a one legged back flip on a snowboard (the rider’s back foot was unstrapped).</p>

<p>It’s been a great week in Whistler despite the lack of fresh snow. We all had a great time, and more importantly Rowan wants to come back. In fact, he says he doesn’t want to leave. So we’ll be back in a couple of years hopefully when the snow conditions are better. </p>

<hr />

<h1 id="the-trek-home-mar-2-2015">The Trek Home (Mar 2, 2015)</h1>

<p>The trek home was a long one. We packed up and left Whistler around 9 am Pacific time, and arrive back home in Vermont at 3:30 am Eastern. It was a long trek home, but all three of us were glad to be home. And it was nice to see a fresh 3 inches of snow on the ground. </p>

<p>For more photos from our trip, take a look at the <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/sets/72157650745528988/">complete photo album</a>.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Here are links to the daily postings I did for WASTED II, which was held in February 2003. The snow conditions that year were very similar to the conditions this year.</p>

      <ul>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/01/day-0-the-commute-begins/">Day 0</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/02/day-1-the-arrival/">Day 1</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/03/day-2-a-hundred-and-ten-percent/">Day 2</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/04/day-3-birthday-fondue/">Day 3</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/05/wasted-ii-day-4-bowl-of-sweetness/">Day 4</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/06/wasted-ii-day-5-park-fun/">Day 5</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/07/wasted-ii-day-6-return-to-blackcomb/">Day 6</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/08/wasted-ii-day-7-the-brotherhood/">Day 7</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/09/wasted-ii-day-8-beer-xbox-and-more-beer/">Day 8</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/13/wasted-ii-day-9-10-11-and-12-catch-up/">Day 9, 10, 11 and 12</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/16/wasted-ii-final-days-no-snow-but-still-a-great-time/">Final Days</a></li>
        <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/16/wasted-ii-im-so-glad-we-had-this-time-together/">Conclusion</a></li>
      </ul>
      <p><a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consider The Environmental Cost]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/06/consider-the-environmental-cost/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-06T07:56:46-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/06/consider-the-environmental-cost</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two days ago I wrote a <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website/">post</a> about how I bought a new snowboard online because it was cheaper than buying locally, or so I thought. Turns out a local shop in Stowe was offering a 20% discount on the board I bought, but I didn’t know this at the time since that shop didn’t advertise the sale on their website. So in the end I paid a little more to buy a new snowboard from another local shop located on the other side of the country. </p>

<p>Today I read an article written by Hana Beaman about how we might want it all but we don’t need it all, see the picture below, when it hit me I was totally missed the point in my earlier post. I should have bought locally even if the price was slightly higher. I forgot about the cost on the environment.</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/B8uV-gMCcAAYfXp.jpg" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<p>Sure, I thought I was saving a few dollars by buying online, but now that snowboard must travel across the United States by truck, airplane or some sort of and combination of fuel sucking transport. Regardless the means of transport the snowboard takes to get from Oregon to Vermont, it will have a negative impact on the environment. The environmental impact would have been much lower if I had bought locally since I live only a mile or so away from the store, a store that ultimately had the better price. </p>

<p>The lesson here for me is that I need to buy locally more than I already do<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, and I need to consider more than just how much an item will cost me. I need to also consider the cost to the environment. </p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>My spending habits have changed a lot since moving to Stowe. I buy a lot more things locally, from eggs to gear. Even my Amazon purchases have dropped to a third of what they were 3 years ago. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Local Retail Stores, Update Your Website]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-04T13:08:21-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought a new Burton snowboard the other day. I ordered it online from a mom and pop shop in the Oregon. I wanted to buy locally here in Stowe but the price I paid was 10% cheaper than the price listed on the websites of local shops. Combined with the fact that I didn’t have to pay sales tax and shipping was free, I felt I was getting a great deal. Still, I would have preferred to support a local shop here in Vermont, but at least I supported a local shop in Oregon. </p>

<p>All good, right? Well…</p>

<p>My wife stopped by one of the local Stowe shops today to buy a pair of new skis. Turns out the shop has a sale going on…20% off all Burton boards! Turns out if I had bought my new board locally I would have saved more money than buying online. Plus I would have my board now instead of waiting until next week. </p>

<p>So why didn’t I buy locally given that the sale is going on? It’s because I didn’t know about the sale. Being the type of person I am, I check online before going into brick and mortar stores, and I checked the websites of the local Stowe shops before looking elsewhere. But the shop having the awesome sale did not advise the sale on their website. And because they didn’t advise the sale I ended up taking my business elsewhere.</p>

<p>What could this store have done to win my business? They could have shown the sale price on their website. And if they didn’t want to offer the sale price for online orders, then they could have advised the sale on the front page of their website. Something as simple as “20% Off All Snowboards” for in-store purchases only would have brought me into the store two days ago. And since they have the snowboard I want in stock, it would have been an easy sell. I would have been in and out of the store in under 10 minutes, and they would have a few hundred more dollars in the cash register.</p>

<p>Still, I’m happy with my purchase. With my online purchase I was able to support a locally owned, small business…granted in Oregon instead of Vermont, but that’s still better than buying from a big corporate retail chain. And while I spent more money with my online order, it was only $32 more than I would have paid locally when you add sales tax. So I didn’t lose out too much. The Stowe shop, and the state of Vermont for that matter, lost out more than I did and all because the shop didn’t update their website.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/27/finally/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-27T13:54:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/27/finally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Northeast has been getting slammed with a major snow storm, but unfortunately Stowe, Vermont, is too far northwest to get the full force of the storm. I had hoped for a bit of new snow overnight, but it didn’t happen. So I waited before hitting the slopes this morning in hopes the edge of the storm would inch its way into the Stowe, but it didn’t happen. So Melanie and I hit the slopes anyways, braving the -26 degrees Fahrenheit wind chill. We got in two runs before deciding today would be a good day for a lunch date. So we left the hill, and headed for lunch in town. And then the snow finally came…guess I’ll be hitting the hill first thing tomorrow morning. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We're Moving to a Ski Town...Finally]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/05/moving-to-a-ski-town/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/05/moving-to-a-ski-town</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s official. It’s really going to happen. We’re moving to a ski town! We’re moving to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stowe,_Vermont">Stowe, Vermont</a>, in August. </p>

<p>While this isn’t really new news for most, it’s now official with the signing on a lease for a condo in Stowe and the signing of a property management agreement for our house in Salem. I’ve been talking about this move for many months, but it almost didn’t happen despite being part of a longer term plan since we left NYC.</p>

<p>Melanie and I love NYC, and living in Manhattan was definitely one of the best things either of us have ever done. But skiing - for Melanie - and snowboarding - for me - was becoming a bigger part of our lives. It may sounds strange, but I got into snowboarding while living in New York. People think of New York as a big city with tall buildings, great food, wonder entertainment, and people everywhere. But New York has something to offer everyone including snowboarding. The closest slope is Mountain Creek in New Jersey, and there are buses that run from Grand Central to Hunter and Windham mountains in the Catskills. During the winter of 2000/2001 I spent many a Saturday and or Sunday at one of these “local” mountains snowboarding. I may have never become obsessed with snowboarding if not for living in New York City.</p>

<p>Fast forward a few years, Melanie and I bought a “city car.” It was a Subaru Impreza that we paid $1500 cash for. I call it a city car because it sat in a parking lot most of the time and the body would get dinged up from other cars. But we didn’t care. The car served one purpose and one purpose only - to get us to and from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Killington,_Vermont">Killington, Vermont</a>. </p>

<p>Like many living in Manhattan, we would leave the city on the weekend during the winter. Our weekend journeys took us up to Killington, Vermont, where Melanie’s parents have a condo. We would spend the weekend snowboarding with the crowds. At the time I wasn’t bothered by the crowds like I am today. I was just happy to be out on the slopes. The problem, however, was the drive. Depending on traffic it could take us up to 7 hours to drive from the West Village to Killington. </p>

<p>Melanie and I realized priorities for us had changed since getting married, and living closer to the slopes was one of those changes. Plus the drive was starting to drive us crazy. We decided to explore for places to live in New England. Because Melanie would be working out of New York City, we knew we needed to live near an airport. And we weren’t sure how Melanie’s commute each week to JFK would be, so we settled on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salem,_Massachusetts">Salem, Massachusetts</a>, as a “temporary” place to live while she tried out life as a commuting flight attendant. The plan was: If the commute sucked we would move back to NYC, but if the commute was okay then we would start looking for a more permanent New England town closer to the slopes to call home. </p>

<p>But something distracted us from this plan. Melanie got knocked up. It was a planned knock up, but it caused more changes in our priorities. Instead of finding a new town to call home, we found a house in Salem to buy. Nesting, gotta love it.</p>

<p>Despite becoming more settled in Salem we keep snowboarding (and skiing) a priority for our family of three. Rowan has made numerous trips to the slopes over the last five years of his life, and he has become quite the good little skier. And now he is learning to snowboard. </p>

<p>Having Rowan in our lives hasn’t limited our time skiing and snowboarding. Sure, there were seasons early on were we didn’t get to hit the slopes as much as we would have liked, and we had to make compromises such as me snowboarding in the morning and Melanie skiing in the afternoon so one of us could watch the kid. But we tried hard to make sure having a kid wouldn’t distract us from our love of being on the mountain. We were also not limited to riding only the hills of New England. Rowan has joined us on trips to places such as Breckenridge, Colorado, and Ogden, Utah. But now we face another distraction that would limit our ability to play on the snow as much as we would like. </p>

<p>Rowan starts kindergarten in September.</p>

<p>Having Rowan in school five days a week will be a change for us, but not being able to pull him out of school regularly is an even bigger change. Rowan has been signed up for pre-school and daycare three days a week for years, but he doesn’t always go three days a week. Instead we take him on fun trips. While pulling him out of pre-school is okay, in fact probably better for him than being in pre-school five days week, pulling him out of kindergarten, first grade, second grade, and so on on a regular basis isn’t going to fly with school officials. And we ain’t no teachers so home skooling the kid ain’t ah option fur us. But having Rowan in school five days a week does not mean we have to cut back on our time riding magic powder, as Rowan likes to call it.</p>

<p>Knowing that Rowan is starting “real” school soon reminded Melanie and me of why we left NYC - to live closer to the slopes. Salem was supposed to be a temporary stop, but it has become more permanent especially with the purchase of our house. The fact that we might have to drive 3 hours to Killington to ride with weekend crowds (we tend to be on the mountains week days only to avoid crowds) wasn’t something I was happy about. So last year Melanie and I started talking about our original plan to move closer to the slopes and possibly live in a ski town.</p>

<p>Planning this move has been an emotional roller coaster ride. We would get excited about the possibility of living the dream only to hit rock bottom when it looked like it wasn’t going to happen. One of the biggest challenges has been finding a suitable place to live. Finding an apartment in Manhattan is a cut-throat process but at least new apartments become available daily. The same isn’t true for Stowe. There are not as many places available, and making matters worse is that many of the available rental properties, especially houses, are seasonal rentals where the owner can earn a lot of money renting out the place weekly during the winter months. </p>

<p>We were able to find apartments and condos available for long-term rental (6 to 12+ months), but most came furnished. This also bothered us. Living in a place for a year with someone else’s furniture doesn’t feel like home. The other problem was the size of most places. Unless we were willing to pay three grand or more a month in rent, we would have the settle on a 2-bedroom place. For someone who works from home this is a problem. Before we bought our house we lived in 2-bedroom apartments while I worked from home, so I can make it work. However the difference this time around is the kid. We didn’t have the kid before, but now we do. Still, it should work out since the kid will be in school five days a week.</p>

<p>So over the course of the last four months finding a place in Stowe to live has looked grim. We’re were close to giving up.</p>

<p>You are probably wondering right now why we didn’t just look for a place in one of the surround towns. There are certainly many more affordable options including houses. But we want Rowan in the Stowe public school system, which means we must be a resident of Stowe. There is an option to pay a crap load of money to get your kid into the Stowe school system, but that’s not something we can afford to do. So finding a place to live in Stowe was a must for us.</p>

<p>As I said, we were close to giving up. In fact, in my head I had already given up. I started making plans to be in Salem for at least one more year. I decided I would be in San Francisco for WWDC. I even volunteered to help with labs at AltWWDC. But as luck would have it, a large 2-bedroom condo that we liked became available in Stowe. It didn’t really become available as much as we helped it become available by sparking an idea in the condo owner’s mind.</p>

<p>In May, we placed a wanted ad in the local Stowe newspaper. The ad was simple. </p>

<p>“Family of 3, no pets, looking for a long-term (12+ months), unfurnished house for rent in the Stowe public school district. Prefer July or August move in date.”</p>

<p>I don’t remember who gave us the idea to post an ad in the local paper. I think it was my sister-in-law Brooke, so that’s who I will credit for the idea. Thanks Brooke.</p>

<p>We received only one reply from the ad. It was from a retired couple living in Stowe. The couple did not have plans to leave Stowe anytime soon, but the ad got them thinking. They knew they would leave Stowe within the next couple of years to live closer to family. They called us to chat and explore the idea of leaving Stowe sooner. Long story short, they liked us, we liked them, and their family liked the idea of them moving closer sooner than later. So last week we made it official. </p>

<p>Just two weeks ago I was resolved to the fact that we would be in Salem for at least one more year, then few days later it looked like the move was back on. Melanie even said me excitedly, “This is really going to happen.” And yes, indeed it looked like it was going to finally happen. Melanie asked me not to say anything publicly last week, which is why I couldn’t share the details of why I canceled my trip to San Fran. But now that the lease is signed and we have a move-in date, I can tell the world. </p>

<p>We move in August. For the moment we take possession of the Stowe condo on August 15. However we’re hoping we can move up the date to August 1. </p>

<p>As for our house in Salem, we’re not selling it. Instead we’re going to try our hand at being landlords. But we will be silent landlords. We’ve hired a property management company to manage the house for us. Renting our house is part of the reason we hope we can move into the Stowe condo as early as August 1. We want to make our house available for tenants looking to move in before the school year starts in Salem.</p>

<p>And as for canceling my trip to San Francisco, as well as a visit to Memphis, I decided we need to hold on to as much cash as possible. The next few months are going to be expensive, and how expensive will depend on how quickly we can rent out our house. It’s great that I work for myself, but the indie income is itself a roller coaster ride. And while I’m bummed that I will not be in SF for WWDC, I’m not bummed about getting to snowboard almost daily this upcoming winter season.</p>

<p>So that’s my big announcement and the reason plans for this summer have changed. We’re moving to a ski town to make living the dream even better.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>