<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: fitness | thecave | Kirby Turner's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/fitness/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-10-04T01:39:47+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goodbye Fitbit Ultra, Hello Fitbit One]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/goodbye-fitbit-ultra-hello-fitbit-one/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-15T00:42:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/goodbye-fitbit-ultra-hello-fitbit-one</id>
    <tag>fitness</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>On November 15, 2011, I started using my Fitbit Ultra, and after only 1157 days I have finally switched to the Fitbit One.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On November 15, 2011, I started using my Fitbit Ultra, and after only 1157 days I have finally switched to the Fitbit One.</p>

<p>The Ultra has been an outstanding device, and it’s darn tough too. Mine has bits of plastic missing and the casing has separated on one side. And yet the thing continues working. The only problem is the button, which stopped working two days ago. That’s why I decided to upgrade. Still, the Ultra has been one of the best little devices I’ve ever owned.</p>

<p>Together the Ultra and I have taken 7,625,047 steps, climbed the equivalent of 22,711 floors, walked 3,401.97 miles, and burned 5,035,126. My Ultra was with me on my Long Trail thru hike as well as countless other hikes. It’s been with me to New York, San Francisco, Paris, Amsterdam, Montreal, and many other places. It’s the last thing I pull out of my pocket each night before bed, and the first thing I put back in my pocket after waking up. In all that time I’ve left my Ultra behind for fewer than 5 days. But as of this afternoon I’m no longer using my Ultra. I’m now using my new Fitbit One.</p>

<p>I’m excited to use the One. It certainly has features not available on the Ultra, most notably the ability to sync wirelessly over Bluetooth. The Ultra requires plugging in to sync, and often times I would go 6 or 7 days without syncing because it wasn’t convenient for me to plug in. But with the One and the option to sync via my iPhone, I will be syncing more frequently.</p>

<p>The One is smaller than the Ultra, and I have to say I’m really digging the smaller size. The display on the One is better than the Ultra too, but then again the display on my Ultra looked good when it was new. My Ultra has been through a lot and the wear and tear is showing on it. That might be why the One’s display looks much better to me right now.</p>

<p>I do have a couple of minor issues with the One. First, the wireless sync might mean I forget to charge my One as frequently as I did the Ultra. Time will tell if this is a valid concern or not for me. The other issue is that I rarely clipped my Ultra onto myself, but I did do it from time to time…mostly in the morning if I walked around the house in my boxers. I would clip the Ultra to my boxers until I put on pjs, shorts, or pants. The One comes with a clip, but since I rarely need the clip I’m not planning to use it. But there will still be those rare early mornings when I wish I could clip my One to my boxers. Maybe I’ll keep the clip on my nightstand next to my bed so it’s easy to grab when I do need it.</p>

<p>Hmmm, so it seems I don’t really have any issues with the One…at least not yet. And based on my experience with the Ultra, I don’t expect to have any issues with the One either. I’m hoping the One is as good, if not better, than the Ultra. Time will tell. I’ll try to remember to write a follow up about my One in, say, 1157 days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Weight Lost Continues]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/17/the-weight-lost-continues/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/17/the-weight-lost-continues</id>
    <tag>fitness</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Weighed myself today. I’m down to 153 pounds. That’s 17 pounds lighter than I was 4 months ago. Only three more pounds to go before I hit my target weight.</p>
]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Weighed myself today. I’m down to 153 pounds. That’s 17 pounds lighter than I was 4 months ago. Only three more pounds to go before I hit my target weight.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only 9 more pounds to go]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/05/31/only-9-more-pounds-to-go/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/05/31/only-9-more-pounds-to-go</id>
    <tag>fitness</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I weighed myself today. I’m 11 pounds lighter than I was 7 weeks ago, and I’ve lost a little more than an inch off my waist.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I weighed myself today. I’m 11 pounds lighter than I was 7 weeks ago, and I’ve lost a little more than an inch off my waist.</p>

<p>Like most people, I have slowly gained weight over the last 10 years. But that weight gain quickly accelerated after <a href="http://rowanturner.net/">Rowan</a> was born. I don’t know how much I have gained since he was born, but I estimate it to be around 15 to 20 pounds. I was the heaviest I’ve ever been.</p>

<p>And like most people, I have wanted to loss weight. I just don’t have the time to hit the gym 5 days a week. So how did I lose 11 pounds in 7 weeks?</p>

<p>It started shortly after <a href="http://ideveloper.tv/nsconference/">NSConference</a>. Drew McCormack <a href="http://twitter.com/drewmccormack/status/185247058398154752">tweeted</a> that he was under 80kg for the first time in years. What caught my attention was the #4hourbody hash tag. I immediately thought of the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307465357/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0307465357">The 4-Hour Workweek</a>, and I thought this hash tag might be related. Turns out, it is. The author of The 4-Hour Workweek wrote another book called <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/030746363X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=030746363X">The 4-Hour Body</a>.</p>

<p>While I enjoyed The 4-Hour Workweek, I thought the The 4-Hour Body would be nonsense. Still, I added to my wish list as something to read later.</p>

<p>That time came a few weeks later. I wanted something different to read, and thinking about my ever increasing weight I decided to buy The 4-Hour Body. I read through the first part of the book that talks about rapid fat loss. It recommends a diet that is very much inline with what I like to eat. Meat and beans. Lots of meat and beans.</p>

<p>After reading this part of the book, I decided to give it a try. I was already eating chicken and pork daily, but I was also eating ice cream and cereal every day. And my side dishes with my chicken and pork were usually rice or potatoes.  I cut out the daily ice cream, and I replaced the cereal with a fried egg. And I replaced my side dishes with beans.</p>

<p>I used to eat lots of beans, but my wife can’t stand them. So for years, I would only have beans a couple of times a week. Now I have them a couple of times a day.</p>

<p>In addition to the slight change to my daily diet, I decided to hire a personal trainer. For the longest time, I’ve wanted to get back into a route of go to the gym, but my busy life has made it hard to do. I knew hiring a trainer would motivate me to go, and so far it has worked. I’ve been going to the gym 1 hour a week since I started this personal challenge.</p>

<p>So that’s what I changed. I cut out daily ice cream, cereal, rice, and potatoes. I added an egg a day, lots of beans, and 1 hour per week at the gym. And as a result, I have lost 11 pounds in 7 weeks. Not the rapid results the book claims can be achieved, but I’m only loosely following the book’s advice. In fact, I haven’t even finished reading the book. I read what foods to eat and not eat then ran with it.</p>

<p>I also kept it a secret that I was on this mission to lose weight. Even my wife didn’t know for weeks that I was loosely following a diet (though she was noticing the results). That’s how minor of a change I made with my diet.</p>

<p>The trick for me now is to continue with the weight lost. I want to lose a total of 20 pounds, returning to my ideal weight of 150 pounds. I have only 9 pounds to go (woohoo!). The real fun, however, begins after I hit my goal - keeping the weight off.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>