<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: interface builder | thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/interface-builder/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-05-13T01:58:07+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wait, Justin and I Agree?]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/10/wait-justin-and-i-agree/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/10/wait-justin-and-i-agree</id>
    <tag>interface builder</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>My friend Justin wrote a post explaining why he thinks you should <a href="http://carpeaqua.com/2014/05/09/why-you-should-use-interface-builder-with-auto-layout/">use Interface Builder with Auto Layout</a>. It was in response to my post about <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout/">why I don’t use Interface Builder</a> these days thanks to Auto Layout. Justin’s post is good with plenty of valid points. Justin and I also agree iOS and Mac developers should be using Auto Layout. But he said something that got me wondering…does Justin agree with me more than he realizes. Regarding writing layout constraints in code, Justin says:</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Justin wrote a post explaining why he thinks you should <a href="http://carpeaqua.com/2014/05/09/why-you-should-use-interface-builder-with-auto-layout/">use Interface Builder with Auto Layout</a>. It was in response to my post about <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout/">why I don’t use Interface Builder</a> these days thanks to Auto Layout. Justin’s post is good with plenty of valid points. Justin and I also agree iOS and Mac developers should be using Auto Layout. But he said something that got me wondering…does Justin agree with me more than he realizes. Regarding writing layout constraints in code, Justin says:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s totally possible to do this, and there are situations where I do it as well. Small views with a few basic constraints are usually quicker and easier to write without a Xib. Insanely complex views such as the TED video player I wrote and maintain are also too heavy for a straight Xib implementation.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I found that almost all the apps I have worked on in recent years consists of views that fall into the category of either being small views or complex views. And even “insanely complex views” can likely be broken down into smaller views using the <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/13581816">composite view pattern</a>. In other words, in my experience many views can be broken down into smaller, more manageable views that end up needing only a few basic constraints. And even Justin agrees that “small views with a few basic constraints are usually quicker and easier to write without a Xib.” So it’s my style, my approach to solving UI problems that makes it quicker and easier for me to write UI with layout constraints in code rather than using IB.</p>

<p>Does this mean I’m right and Justin is wrong? No. Does it mean Justin’s right and I’m wrong? No.</p>

<p>In programming there are multiple ways to accomplish a task, and one approach isn’t always necessarily better or more right than another approach. The approach a programmer takes to solve a problem is often based on past experience and the solution often reflects the personal style of the programmer.</p>

<p>Over the years my style has changed and evolved to a point where I break down complex problems into smaller, more manageable tasks, and I use this style, or approach if you will, when implementing a UI. These days view controller containment and composite views work well for me. I like to write <a href="http://www.objc.io/issue-1/lighter-view-controllers.html">light weight view controllers</a>, and I use other objects to serve as the data source and delegate to my view controllers. And more recently I have found I don’t need to use Interface Builder to be a productive programmer.</p>

<p>Does this mean you should abandon IB as well? Certainly not. Does this mean I hate IB and I will never use it again? Most certainly not. When a task I need to accomplish is quicker and easier for me to do in IB, then I will most certainly use IB. Just like Justin will sometimes write layout constraints in code, I will sometimes use IB to put together a view.</p>

<p>Different situations call for different solutions. There isn’t just one way to solve a problem, and programmers shouldn’t do something just because one person says this is the way it should be done. Programmers should explore the different ways to accomplish a task, and decide what works best for them and what tools and approaches make them the best, most productive programmer they can be. And don’t get hung up on doing a task the same way each time. Challenge yourself by find new ways of accomplishing the same task. In doing this, you might find you agree much more with the person that you thought you disagreed with on the onset.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Stopped Using NIBs Thanks to Auto Layout]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout</id>
    <tag>interface builder</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The subject to this post might suggest I don’t like Auto Layout, but on the contrary I really like Auto Layout. I didn’t always like Auto Layout. For the longest time Auto Layout was a major pain in my ass, but it turns out it was Interface Builder that was causing me the majority of headaches when I used Auto Layout. So I stopped using Auto Layout in IB and I started using it in code only.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The subject to this post might suggest I don’t like Auto Layout, but on the contrary I really like Auto Layout. I didn’t always like Auto Layout. For the longest time Auto Layout was a major pain in my ass, but it turns out it was Interface Builder that was causing me the majority of headaches when I used Auto Layout. So I stopped using Auto Layout in IB and I started using it in code only.</p>

<p>It took me a while to get comfortable with Auto Layout in code, but once things clicked, I found it easy to get the layout I wanted. In fact, I have found Auto Layout saves me time when laying out a UI, and I’ve become so comfortable with Auto Layout that now I become annoyed if I have to work on a project that does not use Auto Layout.</p>

<p>Because I use Auto Layout in code I realized overtime I was using Interface Builder only to define the UI elements that made up the view. I would define all the Auto Layout constraints in code. This got me thinking, why do I need to define the UI elements in IB? So I did a small project with no NIBs or storyboards, and I loved it. I felt more productive, and I was banging my head against the wall a hell of a lot less.</p>

<p>(Credit also goes to <a href="https://twitter.com/mattie">Matt Massicotte</a> for encouraging me to try a project with no NIB or storboard files.)</p>

<p>I’ve now done a number of iOS projects where I don’t use a single NIB or storyboard, and I’m convinced this is the right approach for me. I see everything regarding a view and its subviews explicitly defined in source code, which makes it easier to see what’s going on and to make changes. No more bouncing between inspectors to figure out what is causing a problem or to understand how a view is rendered. I see it all in the source code defined in a single <em>.m</em> file.</p>

<p>So how do I construct my views using only source code? I have a base class that I call <a href="https://github.com/kirbyt/WPSKit/blob/master/WPSKit/UIKit/WPSCompositeView.h"><code class="highlighter-rouge">WPSCompositeView</code></a> in my <a href="https://github.com/kirbyt/WPSKit">WPSKit</a>, a set of classes and categories I use to build apps. <code class="highlighter-rouge">WPSCompositeView</code> has a class method named <code class="highlighter-rouge">+addToSuperview:</code> that creates the instance of the view, which must be a subclass of <code class="highlighter-rouge">WPSCompositeView</code>, then calls <code class="highlighter-rouge">-loadView</code> on the instance of the view. I place all the code needed to create the subviews of the view in the <code class="highlighter-rouge">-loadView</code> implementation. The constraints for the view are implemented in the <code class="highlighter-rouge">-updateConstraints</code> that is called by iOS when needed. That’s it.</p>

<p>Here’s an example of a composer view for a new app I’m working on:</p>

<p><a href="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7204/13920896030_4c53fbfe1c_o.jpg"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7204/13920896030_e0da352daf_m.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>And the code for creating this view is as follows:</p>

<div class="highlighter-rouge"><pre class="highlight"><code>- (void)loadView
{
  UIView *containerView = self;

  WPSTextView *textView = [[WPSTextView alloc] init];
  [textView setTranslatesAutoresizingMaskIntoConstraints:NO];
  [textView setAlwaysBounceVertical:YES];
  [textView setInputAccessoryView:[self toolbar]];
  [textView setFont:[UIFont systemFontOfSize:17.0]];
  [textView setPlaceholderText:NSLocalizedString(@"What's up?", @"Placeholder text.")];
  [self setTextView:textView];

  UIButton *locationButton = [UIButton buttonWithType:UIButtonTypeCustom];
  [locationButton setTranslatesAutoresizingMaskIntoConstraints:NO];
  [locationButton setImage:[UIImage wps_imageNamed:@"location" withMaskColor:[UIColor lightGrayColor]] forState:UIControlStateNormal];
  [locationButton setImage:[UIImage wps_imageNamed:@"location" withMaskColor:[UIColor wps_iOSDefaultBlue]] forState:UIControlStateSelected];
  [locationButton setSelected:NO];
  [locationButton addTarget:self action:@selector(_locationButtonTapped:) forControlEvents:UIControlEventTouchUpInside];
  [self setLocationButton:locationButton];

  UILabel *locationLabel = [[UILabel alloc] init];
  [locationLabel setTranslatesAutoresizingMaskIntoConstraints:NO];
  [locationLabel setTextColor:[UIColor lightGrayColor]];
  [locationLabel setTextAlignment:NSTextAlignmentLeft];
  [locationLabel setText:NSLocalizedString(@"Location Disabled", @"Location text.")];
  [self setLocationLabel:locationLabel];

  UILabel *characterCountLabel = [[UILabel alloc] init];
  [characterCountLabel setTranslatesAutoresizingMaskIntoConstraints:NO];
  [characterCountLabel setTextColor:[UIColor lightGrayColor]];
  [characterCountLabel setTextAlignment:NSTextAlignmentRight];
  [self setCharacterCountLabel:characterCountLabel];

  [containerView addSubview:textView];
  [containerView addSubview:locationButton];
  [containerView addSubview:locationLabel];
  [containerView addSubview:characterCountLabel];

  [textView wps_setDidChange:^(UITextView *aTextView) {
    NSString *countString = nil;
    NSUInteger length = [[aTextView text] length];
    if (length &gt; 0) {
      countString = [NSString stringWithFormat:@"%lu", (unsigned long)length];
    }
    [characterCountLabel setText:countString];
  }];
}

- (void)updateConstraints
{
  WPSTextView *textView = [self textView];
  UILabel *characterCountLabel = [self characterCountLabel];
  UIButton *locationButton = [self locationButton];
  UILabel *locationLabel = [self locationLabel];

  [locationButton wps_constrainToHeight:38.0f];
  [locationButton wps_constrainToWidth:38.0f];

  NSDictionary *bindings = NSDictionaryOfVariableBindings(textView, characterCountLabel, locationButton, locationLabel);
  [self addConstraints:[NSLayoutConstraint constraintsWithVisualFormat:@"V:|-0-[textView]-4-[characterCountLabel]-0-|" options:0 metrics:nil views:bindings]];
  [self addConstraints:[NSLayoutConstraint constraintsWithVisualFormat:@"H:|-0-[textView]-0-|" options:0 metrics:nil views:bindings]];
  [self addConstraints:[NSLayoutConstraint constraintsWithVisualFormat:@"H:|-8-[locationButton]-[locationLabel]-[characterCountLabel]-8-|" options:0 metrics:nil views:bindings]];
  [self addConstraint:[NSLayoutConstraint constraintWithItem:locationLabel attribute:NSLayoutAttributeBaseline relatedBy:NSLayoutRelationEqual toItem:characterCountLabel attribute:NSLayoutAttributeBaseline multiplier:1.0 constant:0.0]];
  [self addConstraint:[NSLayoutConstraint constraintWithItem:locationButton attribute:NSLayoutAttributeCenterY relatedBy:NSLayoutRelationEqual toItem:locationLabel attribute:NSLayoutAttributeCenterY multiplier:1.0 constant:0.0]];

  [super updateConstraints];
}

- (UIToolbar *)toolbar
{
  if (_toolbar == nil) {
    CGRect screenBounds = [[UIScreen mainScreen] bounds];
    UIToolbar *toolbar = [[UIToolbar alloc] initWithFrame:CGRectMake(0, 0, screenBounds.size.width, 44)];
    [toolbar setTintAdjustmentMode:UIViewTintAdjustmentModeNormal];


    NSUserDefaults *defaults = [NSUserDefaults standardUserDefaults];
    BOOL adnOn = [defaults cp_isAdnOn];
    BOOL facebookOn = [defaults cp_isFacebookOn];
    BOOL twitterOn = [defaults cp_isTwitterOn];

    UIColor *offColor = [UIColor lightGrayColor];
    UIColor *adnColor = adnOn ? [UIColor blackColor] : offColor;
    UIColor *facebookColor = facebookOn ? [UIColor wps_facebookBlue] : offColor;
    UIColor *twitterColor = twitterOn ? [UIColor wps_twitterBlue] : offColor;

    UIBarButtonItem *cameraButton = [self buttonWithImageName:@"camera" color:[UIColor wps_iOSDefaultBlue] action:@selector(_cameraButtonTapped:)];
    [self setCameraButton:cameraButton];

    UIBarButtonItem *adnButton = [self buttonWithImageName:@"adn" color:adnColor action:@selector(_adnButtonTapped:)];
    [adnButton setTag:adnOn];
    [self setAdnOn:adnOn];
    [self setAdnButton:adnButton];

    UIBarButtonItem *facebookButton = [self buttonWithImageName:@"facebook" color:facebookColor action:@selector(_facebookButtonTapped:)];
    [facebookButton setTag:facebookOn];
    [self setFacebookOn:facebookOn];
    [self setFacebookButton:facebookButton];

    UIBarButtonItem *twitterButton = [self buttonWithImageName:@"twitter" color:twitterColor action:@selector(_twitterButtonTapped:)];
    [twitterButton setTag:twitterOn];
    [self setTwitterOn:twitterOn];
    [self setTwitterButton:twitterButton];

    UIBarButtonItem *draftsButton = [self buttonWithImageName:@"drafts" color:[UIColor wps_iOSDefaultBlue] action:@selector(_draftsButtonTapped:)];
    [self setDraftsButton:draftsButton];

    UIBarButtonItem *flexibleButton = [[UIBarButtonItem alloc] initWithBarButtonSystemItem:UIBarButtonSystemItemFlexibleSpace target:nil action:nil];
    [toolbar setItems:@[adnButton, facebookButton, twitterButton, flexibleButton, draftsButton, cameraButton] animated:NO];

    _toolbar = toolbar;
  }
  return  _toolbar;
}
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>The only things not created or managed but this view are the navigation bar and collection view of photos. The navigation bar is provided by the <code class="highlighter-rouge">UINavigationController</code> used by the view controller that created this composer view. Also, the view controller uses controller containment to include the collection view of photos, which is actually managed by another view controller and custom view class.</p>

<p>Oh, I almost forgot to mention…I create the composite view in the <code class="highlighter-rouge">loadView</code> method implemented in the view controller. For example:</p>

<div class="highlighter-rouge"><pre class="highlight"><code>- (void)loadView
{
  [super loadView];
  UIView *contentView = [self view];

  CPComposeView *composeView = [CPComposeView addToSuperview:contentView];
  [self setComposeView:composeView];
}
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>After I create the view I might add more layout constraints to position and size the subview as needed within the main content view. I do that in the view controller’s <code class="highlighter-rouge">-loadView</code> when needed.</p>

<p>So that’s it. That’s why I have stopped using NIB and storyboard files in my iOS projects. This approach might not work for others, but it certainly works for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>