<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: long trail | thecave | Kirby Turner's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/long-trail/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-11-29T15:17:43+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working 80+ Hours Isn't The Answer]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-21T12:41:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer</id>
    <tag>long trail</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A founder, or maybe the person is a manager type, asked on Quora, “<a href="http://www.quora.com/How-do-you-make-programmers-work-60-80-hours-per-week">How do you make programmers work 60-80 hours per week?</a>” While the question is a pathetic one, the answers that follow, especially the first one, are worth a read. And you should certainly read the answers if you happen to be one of those sad founders/manager types who wants their of programmers to work long hours. In short, if you are trying to force your programmers to work 60, 80 or more hours per week, then you are doing it wrong.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A founder, or maybe the person is a manager type, asked on Quora, “<a href="http://www.quora.com/How-do-you-make-programmers-work-60-80-hours-per-week">How do you make programmers work 60-80 hours per week?</a>” While the question is a pathetic one, the answers that follow, especially the first one, are worth a read. And you should certainly read the answers if you happen to be one of those sad founders/manager types who wants their of programmers to work long hours. In short, if you are trying to force your programmers to work 60, 80 or more hours per week, then you are doing it wrong.</p>

<h2 id="personal-experience">Personal Experience</h2>

<p>I have first hand experience working 80+ hours per week. Heck, there were times I worked more than 100 hours in a single week at one particular startup. There were times when I would go days without going home, choosing instead to sleep in the office for an hour here and an hour there. And if I needed a change of clothes for an important meeting, I would go to the Banana Republic that was below my office to buy a change of clothes instead of going home.</p>

<p>The difference with this experience, however, was that I was never forced to put in those insane hours. No one ever asked me to work 80+ hours. I did it because I truly believed in what we were building. But I also knew what it took to be productive, and that’s why I often times made sure my team did not follow my lead.</p>

<p>I encouraged my team to work no more than 40 hours, and if I noticed someone reaching 50 hours I usually asked that person to take a break, go home, and enjoy life a bit. The work can wait. Sometimes the team member would take my suggestion and leave, other times they would not. But the choice was theirs. I never asked for more than 40 hours per week and in the end we created some amazing things in a short amount of time.</p>

<h2 id="get-to-the-point">Get To The Point</h2>

<p>So what’s my point here? My point is that you can’t force a programmer to work long hours. That person has to want to do it. There has to be a love or passion for what they are doing, otherwise it’s just work. And people max out, especially creative types, after about 32 to 40 hours of work in a single week.</p>

<h2 id="and-now">And Now</h2>

<p>I worked at a few startups putting in 60 or more hours per week, but those days are behind me. Those were fun times with lots of good memories, but I now find it’s more important to break up work with other interest. Today I’m a proponent of what I like to call underworking, or as I more often times jokingly call “being a slacker.”<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>Life’s too short to overwork yourself today in hopes you will have the time later in life for the fun things. Who knows what will happen in the future. You could be hit by a beer truck tomorrow and die. That’s why I believe you should make a point to spend more time <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing what you love</a> now. The work can wait.</p>

<h2 id="the-long-trail-and-me">The Long Trail And Me</h2>

<p>A couple of years back I did a talk on the topic of underworking at the first <a href="http://www.360intersect.com/">360intersect</a>. In it I talk about my time hiking the Long Trail and the effect it has had on me and the amount of time I spend working each week. Here’s the video for those interested in watching it and learning more about the benefits of working less.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<p><div class="vimeo-video"><figure><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/65740037" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></figure></div></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Funny how working only 32 to 40 hours a week is thought to be slacking.&nbsp;<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>Sorry the first couple of minutes of the talk are missing. Someone forgot to push the record button.&nbsp;<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back from the Long Trail Hike]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/09/25/back-from-the-long-trail-hike/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/09/25/back-from-the-long-trail-hike</id>
    <tag>long trail</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Hikes/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-2012/25322189_WRGQQ7"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Hikes/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-2012/i-2xkDqK9/0/Th/IMG0208-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> My southbound hike of the Long Trail didn’t go as planned. I had to stop after 13 days due to a knee injury. As I said in a tweet, “Th-Th-Th-Th-Th…That’s all, folks. I’m not continuing the hike due to constant pain that has zapped all the fun out of the journey.”
I’m disappointed that I wasn’t able to hike the trail end to end, but I’m glad I at least tried it. And I will be back next year to complete the remaining 182 miles.</p>
<h2 id="an-amazing-experience">An Amazing Experience</h2>
<p>Despite not finishing and having to deal with knee pain for weeks that followed leaving the trail, I still look back to my days on the trail and think to myself, “What an amazing experience.”
Leaving the trail was a hard thing to do. I struggled with mixed emotions. My heart was into the hike and I wanted to continue. But my brain, and the pain, said it was time to stop. Even after I decided I would not continue the hike, I would stare out at the mountains and daydream about being on the trail. Even now, weeks later, when I see a tree covered mountain I think to myself how great it would be hiking up and over the summit. But a thru hike wasn’t meant to be for me this year.</p>
<h2 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h2>
<p>This is not it for me and the Long Trail though. I’m planning to complete my hike next year, and I hope to re-attempt a thru hike again the following year.
Also, I want to write up a blog post about my experience hiking the first 90 miles of the Long Trail from the Canadian border to Jonesville, Vermont. I hope to do this within the next week or so, but I also need to finish writing the second edition of my iPad book. Time will tell if I actually write the blog post. Meanwhile, enjoy the <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Hikes/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-2012/25322189_WRGQQ7">pictures</a> I took during my journey.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Hikes/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-2012/25322189_WRGQQ7"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Hikes/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-2012/i-2xkDqK9/0/Th/IMG0208-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> My southbound hike of the Long Trail didn’t go as planned. I had to stop after 13 days due to a knee injury. As I said in a tweet, “Th-Th-Th-Th-Th…That’s all, folks. I’m not continuing the hike due to constant pain that has zapped all the fun out of the journey.”
I’m disappointed that I wasn’t able to hike the trail end to end, but I’m glad I at least tried it. And I will be back next year to complete the remaining 182 miles.</p>
<h2 id="an-amazing-experience">An Amazing Experience</h2>
<p>Despite not finishing and having to deal with knee pain for weeks that followed leaving the trail, I still look back to my days on the trail and think to myself, “What an amazing experience.”
Leaving the trail was a hard thing to do. I struggled with mixed emotions. My heart was into the hike and I wanted to continue. But my brain, and the pain, said it was time to stop. Even after I decided I would not continue the hike, I would stare out at the mountains and daydream about being on the trail. Even now, weeks later, when I see a tree covered mountain I think to myself how great it would be hiking up and over the summit. But a thru hike wasn’t meant to be for me this year.</p>
<h2 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h2>
<p>This is not it for me and the Long Trail though. I’m planning to complete my hike next year, and I hope to re-attempt a thru hike again the following year.
Also, I want to write up a blog post about my experience hiking the first 90 miles of the Long Trail from the Canadian border to Jonesville, Vermont. I hope to do this within the next week or so, but I also need to finish writing the second edition of my iPad book. Time will tell if I actually write the blog post. Meanwhile, enjoy the <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Trips/Hikes/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-2012/25322189_WRGQQ7">pictures</a> I took during my journey.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weighing In]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/21/weighing-in/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/21/weighing-in</id>
    <tag>long trail</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I decided to weigh every item going with me on my end-to-end hike of the Long Trail. I’m unfortunately carrying about 5 pounds more than I was hoping, but I remind myself this is a month long hike, not a 3 to 5 day trip. I can do without some gear, such as the Solio charger, on shorter trips.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to weigh every item going with me on my end-to-end hike of the Long Trail. I’m unfortunately carrying about 5 pounds more than I was hoping, but I remind myself this is a month long hike, not a 3 to 5 day trip. I can do without some gear, such as the Solio charger, on shorter trips.</p>

<p>Here are the final weigh-in numbers:</p>

<ul>
<li>Base pack weight: 24.45 pounds</li>
<li>Fuel: 1.62 pounds</li>
<li>Food: 11.44 pounds</li>
<li>Water: 5.71 pounds</li>
</ul>

<p>Total pack weight: 43.22 pounds</p>

<p>For the more curious, I posted my <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ai_IwjXXrirWdEZrSWh6c3YtR0Q2SmtMaUZRSWQ5cWc#gid=0">gear list</a> and <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ai_IwjXXrirWdDVCYWozak50SV9DTzdMTGxSenpUbHc#gid=0">food list</a> on Google Docs.</p>

<p>What would I do differently if I could? Update some gear, specifically my backpack and sleeping bag. Updating these two items could shave off as much as 2 pounds from the base pack weight.</p>

<p>I could also go without the fitbit, Solio charger, iPhone, and cables, but I really want to track my steps, have a way to call someone if an emergency happens, and keep charged up while on the trail. Still, a little weight could be saved by leaving these items at home.</p>

<p>I could also leave the Long Trail Guide book behind, but it might prove useful while out on the trail.</p>

<p>Well, it is what it is, and a base pack weight of 24.45 isn’t too bad. It’s not great, but it will do. It is, after all, a month long hike.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pack Unpack Repeat]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/18/pack-unpack-repeat/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/18/pack-unpack-repeat</id>
    <tag>long trail</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Random/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-Prep-2012/Packing-Practice/24840367_jkVX9C"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Random/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-Prep-2012/Packing-Practice/i-9cwLz2t/0/Th/IMG0180-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> With only 5 days left before I start my hike, I spent the day packing and unpacking my backpack. To my surprise, every thing fit. But also to my surprise, the unofficial total weight is 45 pounds. This includes food and water. I was hoping my total weight would be 5 to 10 pounds less.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Random/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-Prep-2012/Packing-Practice/24840367_jkVX9C"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Random/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-Prep-2012/Packing-Practice/i-9cwLz2t/0/Th/IMG0180-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> With only 5 days left before I start my hike, I spent the day packing and unpacking my backpack. To my surprise, every thing fit. But also to my surprise, the unofficial total weight is 45 pounds. This includes food and water. I was hoping my total weight would be 5 to 10 pounds less.</p>

<p>Not much I can do about it now other than to leave some gear behind. I’m planning to weigh each item on Monday, and will decide what absolutely needs to go and what can stay behind. I doubt, though, I will see much reduction of in weight. Some of my gear, such as my sleeping bag, are in desperate need of an upgrade.</p>

<p>My sleeping bag is 15 years year, and is much heavier than what I would buy today. But a new sleeping bag is not in my future anytime soon. With luck, and a change in our finical situation, I might be able to buy a lighter, better sleeping bag.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Planning to Thru Hike the Long Trail]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/16/planning-to-thru-hike-the-long-trail/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/16/planning-to-thru-hike-the-long-trail</id>
    <tag>long trail</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>One week from today, on August 23, I start a month long journey to hike the <a href="http://www.greenmountainclub.org/page.php?id=2">Long Trail</a> from end to end. I plan to start at the Vermont-Canadian border, and hike south to North Adams, Massachusetts. I’m not exactly sure how long the hike will take me, but it should be somewhere between 25 and 35 days depending on my daily mood, how much or little I hike each day, and so on.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One week from today, on August 23, I start a month long journey to hike the <a href="http://www.greenmountainclub.org/page.php?id=2">Long Trail</a> from end to end. I plan to start at the Vermont-Canadian border, and hike south to North Adams, Massachusetts. I’m not exactly sure how long the hike will take me, but it should be somewhere between 25 and 35 days depending on my daily mood, how much or little I hike each day, and so on.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://www.greenmountainclub.org/page.php?id=2">Long Trail</a> is the oldest long distance hiking trail in the U.S., and it was the inspiration for the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Appalachian_Trail">Appalachian Trail</a>. The Long Trail spans 272 miles from border to border as it follows the main ridge of the Green Mountains. And it crosses Vermont’s highest peaks, providing some beautiful views. </p>

<h2 id="whydothis">Why Do This?</h2>

<p>You may be asking yourself, why am I doing this? The answer is simple. Because I can. </p>

<p>Most people today are so wrapped up with work and life that taking a month off to backpack is but a dream. And many of those lucky few who can take the time off do so in their early adult life, before or after college, before kids, and before life’s burdens take hold. But for me - in my mid&#8211;40s, with a wife and a kid, running my own indie software shop - I’m lucky to have a very understanding wife and a structure to my life that makes it possible for me to do a trip like this. That said, now is still not a good time for me to take this hike. </p>

<p>I’m working on the second edition of my book, I need to focus on a new app that I’m writing, and product sales are still down after focusing so much attention on writing the first edition of my book last year. In other words, we’re broke and taking time off isn’t going to help matters. If anything, it will only make things worse from a financial point of view. But like planning to start a family, it seems there is never a good time to do an adventure like this. So why should I wait?</p>

<p>Another reason I’m doing this is because it’s something I’ve wanted to do for a long time. When I was a teenager, I dreamt of riding my bike across Tennessee, from Memphis to Kingsport. I had the bike. I bought maps, planned the route, and started collecting gear such as a small, light single-person tent. There was even a brief time when my mom entertained the thought of joining me, which would have been outstanding at the time. But alas, the bike trip never happened. I chickened out.</p>

<p>While hiking the Long Trail end to end is not the same as riding my bike across Tennessee, it’s still in the same spirit; the spirit of going on an adventure. For some, the adventure is backpacking across Europe like my wife did during her college years - though she didn’t sleep on the ground for 30 days nor did she have to carry all her food on her back. Still, it was the spirit of adventure, and that’s one of the reasons I’m doing this; to have the adventure I didn’t do when I was younger.</p>

<p>There’s another reason I’m doing this: the challenge. This is the number one reason I’m doing this. To see if I can conquer the challenge.</p>

<p>I live in a connected world. Email, Twitter, the Internet, are all very important aspects to my daily life and work. Disconnecting for a few days it great, but I start to stress out after being disconnected for more than 4 or 5 days. So disconnecting for a month is going to be challenging for me.</p>

<p>There is also the challenge of being self-supported on this adventure. I’m not planning to mail drop supplies and food. Instead, I will hike into towns once a week to buy supplies and food, 5 to 7 days worth each time. The food is probably one of the biggest challenges for me on this trip, and it’s definitely in my Top 2 Biggest Worries.</p>

<p>No, I will not starve, though there might be times when I feel very hungry. I’m a picky eater, and I honestly don’t know what to expect once I eat through my first week’s worth of food. Will I be able to buy foods I like that are also suitable for the trail? I’ll find out soon enough.</p>

<p>I also don’t know how much food I really need. I have an idea of the amount I need for 5 to 7 days, but is that amount accurate when I’m burning 4,000 to 5,000 calories at day? This is something I will only learn from experience, and I can only get the experience by doing it. So while food is one of my biggest worry, it’s not going to stop me from doing this adventure.</p>

<p>What will stop me, however, could be me. Can I handle this trip mentally? And that’s my other biggest worry about thru hiking the Long Trail. The hike represents a physical challenge, but I believe the mental challenge is far greater than the physical challenge.</p>

<p>I’ve read lots of books on long distance hiking, mostly about the Appalachian Trail. A majority of the people attempting to thru hike the AT don’t make it, and a majority of those folks give up within the first 7 days. While the LT is not the AT - they do share the same trail system for a span through southern Vermont - those first 7 days will be the same mentally.</p>

<p>Will I make it for more than 7 days on the trail? Will I make it 14 days, 21 days, even more? I think about this more and more as my start date draws closer. Will I enjoy the solitude, the wilderness, sleeping on the ground each night, being outside 24&#8211;7 through heat, cold, sun, and rain? Will it still be fun after eating yet another mug of Mac-and-Cheese for the N-th day in a row? And what effects will the physical demands of the hike put on my mental psyche?</p>

<p>Despite my worries, family and friends have been very supportive, saying things like, “You’ll do it. You’ll finish the hike.” But you really don’t know what will happen until you try. It’s a month of no family, no code slinging, no Internet, no email, and no creature comforts. I would be fooling myself if I didn’t think there is a mental challenge to hiking the Long Trail end to end, or doing any long distance hike for that matter. That said, I’m committed to making it to the end, but I really won’t know if I can make it to the end until I try.</p>

<h2 id="qa">Q&amp;A</h2>

<p>People have been asking me all sorts of questions about this trip, and I’m sure others will have similar questions upon learning about my crazy idea of thru hiking the Long Trail. Here are some of the more common questions and answers.</p>

<p><strong>What do you do about food?</strong> I pack the food and carry it on my backpack. I have a bear canister that holds 5 to 7 days worth of food. I prefer using the bear canister over hanging my food each night. With the bear canister, I just place it on the ground 200 feet or more from my camp site. This is so much easier than finding a tall tree and hanging my food. Plus, my bear canister doubles as stool for when I need to sit.</p>

<p><strong>What will you eat?</strong> I need to consume calories and lots of them, so I plan to eat a lot of Kraft Macaroni and Cheese, though I’ll likely only eat this at dinner time to save on fuel for my stove. I also have other packaged rice and pasta dishes for dinner like the ones from Knox. They cook quickly, and I’ll be able to save on fuel by using my <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/10/test-run-on-my-dyi-pot-cozy/">pot cozy</a>.</p>

<p>Breakfast, lunch, and snacks will be a combination of junk foods, peanut butter sandwiches, beef jerky, and trail mix. I’m still not exactly sure how to do the peanut button sandwiches yet, but I have a few more days to figure that out.</p>

<p><strong>What do you do when it rains?</strong> I get wet. I’ve hiked in the rain before, and I’ll be hiking in the rain on this trip. I have a rain cover for my backpack, and I will keep my extra clothes in a dry bag to ensure I have something dry to sleep in each night. And of course my tent has a rain fly. So while some days I will get wet on the hike, I do plan on being (mostly) dry when I sleep.</p>

<p><strong>How much will you hike each day?</strong> That’s depends on a number of things. Ideally, I should average about 10 to 12 miles a day to finish the hike in my allotted 35-day max time frame. Realistically, I’ll likely start the hike doing around 10 to 12 miles a day then gradually upping that number to 15, 20, maybe more miles per day. But my goal is 10 to 12 miles a day on average.</p>

<p><strong>Will you hike every day?</strong> Most likely, yes. Though I can see myself deciding to take a day off here and there depending on weather, tiredness, etc.</p>

<p><strong>How are you going to get food?</strong> I plan to hike into various towns at least one a week to get supplies and food. This means that while the Long Trail is 272 miles through Vermont, I’ll actually be hiking more miles. I estimate I will hike somewhere around 320 miles total by the time I make it to North Adams, Massachusetts.</p>

<h2 id="keepingintouch">Keeping in Touch</h2>

<p>I should also mention that while I will be disconnect from the world during the hike - meaning I will not be checking text messages, voice mails, emails, Twitter mentions, and so on - I do plan to do a daily, or almost daily, tweet to let family and friends know what’s going on. You can follow me, <a href="http://www.twitter.com/kirbyt">@kirbyt</a>, on Twitter if you want to read my updates during the hike.</p>

<p>I’ve debated long and hard about whether I should or should not do the daily tweet. I decided to try it, though I’m doing it using <a href="http://support.twitter.com/articles/14020-twitter-sms-commands">Twitter’s SMS feature</a>. This will help save battery life on my iPhone, and reduce the temptations to read my Twitter stream.</p>

<p>So now you know where I will be should you try to reach me between August 23 and the end of September.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>