<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: opinion | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/opinion/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-17T08:03:41-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Watch Will Make iPhone 6 Plus Size Less Annoying]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-06T21:42:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things that annoys me most about the size of my iPhone 6 Plus is pulling it out of my pocket while at a bar or restaurant just to see why my phone buzzed. The majority of the time my phone buzzes because of an incoming text message. I have notifications turned off for almost all other apps, and I rarely. if ever, get phone calls these days, which is why I know the buzz is most likely a text message. And if I’m at the bar without my wife, then the person trying to reach me is most likely my wife. </p>

<p>So when the text message comes in, I have to pull out this big honkin’ device out of my pocket and light up the room just to see the message. I may reply, and if I do, it’s a short reply because, after all, I’m busy at the bar. Then I put the phone back into my pocket only to repeat all of this a few minutes later. </p>

<p>Receiving text messages doesn’t annoy me, but having to pull out and put away this big device every few minutes does annoy me. </p>

<p>It occurred to me that one of the possible reasons why Apple decided to release the larger iPhones was because they knew, thanks to the Apple Watch, that there would be no reason to pull out these larger devices from pockets and purses just to check notifications and send simple text messages and replies.</p>

<p>The Apple Watch will make the iPhone 6 Plus size less annoying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working 80+ Hours Isn't The Answer]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-21T07:41:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A founder, or maybe the person is a manager type, asked on Quora, “<a href="http://www.quora.com/How-do-you-make-programmers-work-60-80-hours-per-week">How do you make programmers work 60-80 hours per week?</a>” While the question is a pathetic one, the answers that follow, especially the first one, are worth a read. And you should certainly read the answers if you happen to be one of those sad founders/manager types who wants their of programmers to work long hours. In short, if you are trying to force your programmers to work 60, 80 or more hours per week, then you are doing it wrong. </p>

<h2 id="personal-experience">Personal Experience</h2>

<p>I have first hand experience working 80+ hours per week. Heck, there were times I worked more than 100 hours in a single week at one particular startup. There were times when I would go days without going home, choosing instead to sleep in the office for an hour here and an hour there. And if I needed a change of clothes for an important meeting, I would go to the Banana Republic that was below my office to buy a change of clothes instead of going home.</p>

<p>The difference with this experience, however, was that I was never forced to put in those insane hours. No one ever asked me to work 80+ hours. I did it because I truly believed in what we were building. But I also knew what it took to be productive, and that’s why I often times made sure my team did not follow my lead. </p>

<p>I encouraged my team to work no more than 40 hours, and if I noticed someone reaching 50 hours I usually asked that person to take a break, go home, and enjoy life a bit. The work can wait. Sometimes the team member would take my suggestion and leave, other times they would not. But the choice was theirs. I never asked for more than 40 hours per week and in the end we created some amazing things in a short amount of time.</p>

<h2 id="get-to-the-point">Get To The Point</h2>

<p>So what’s my point here? My point is that you can’t force a programmer to work long hours. That person has to want to do it. There has to be a love or passion for what they are doing, otherwise it’s just work. And people max out, especially creative types, after about 32 to 40 hours of work in a single week.</p>

<h2 id="and-now">And Now</h2>

<p>I worked at a few startups putting in 60 or more hours per week, but those days are behind me. Those were fun times with lots of good memories, but I now find it’s more important to break up work with other interest. Today I’m a proponent of what I like to call underworking, or as I more often times jokingly call “being a slacker.”<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>Life’s too short to overwork yourself today in hopes you will have the time later in life for the fun things. Who knows what will happen in the future. You could be hit by a beer truck tomorrow and die. That’s why I believe you should make a point to spend more time <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing what you love</a> now. The work can wait. </p>

<h2 id="the-long-trail-and-me">The Long Trail And Me</h2>

<p>A couple of years back I did a talk on the topic of underworking at the first <a href="http://www.360intersect.com/">360intersect</a>. In it I talk about my time hiking the Long Trail and the effect it has had on me and the amount of time I spend working each week. Here’s the video for those interested in watching it and learning more about the benefits of working less.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<p><div class="vimeo-video"><figure><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/65740037" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></figure></div></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Funny how working only 32 to 40 hours a week is thought to be slacking.  <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>Sorry the first couple of minutes of the talk are missing. Someone forgot to push the record button. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's About More Than Shipping an App]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/01/its-about-more-than-shipping-an-app/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/01/its-about-more-than-shipping-an-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There have been a number of recent blog posts about the doom and gloom of being an indie developer especially in the iOS world. The theme of these posts are basically the same. A developer spends some time building an app. The app is released into the wild, and sales are much lower than expected. Some developers give up while others will try again.</p>

<p>The problem as I see it after reading these doom and gloom posts is that the developer has no strategy for building and running a business beyond releasing an app. Releasing an app should not be your only plan for building a business. Releasing an app is just one part of being an indie developer. Another part, a much bigger part of being an indie developer, is being a business owner. And as a business owner you must have a plan consisting of short and long term strategies for building and running your business.</p>

<h1 id="have-a-plan">Have a Plan</h1>

<p>Running a business, even as an indie, requires much more than building and releasing an app. For starters, you need a business plan. Even if it’s not something you write down, you need to know what your plans are for making money and surviving the dry spells. Your plan should change and evolve over time as your business changes and grows.</p>

<p>When I started White Peak Software, I had no plan. I was fed up with others controlling my life and career. I knew I wanted to control those things, so I started my company. In some ways taking control of my life and career was my initial business plan but that didn’t help pay the bills. And at the rate I was going using that plan I knew my company would not last twelve months with me as a full time employee.</p>

<p>After six months of having no real plan or strategy for building my business, I hired a small business coach. A small business coach is like a life coach or therapist for your business.<sup id="fnref:sbc"><a href="#fn:sbc" class="footnote">1</a></sup> The coach doesn’t necessarily tell you what to you do. Instead the coach gives you the steps and guidance needed to help you figure out what your short term and long term plans are for your company.</p>

<p>For three months, my small business coach and I met once a week to talk about my business. During these talks it became clear to me that I wanted to write and sell my own software, but more importantly I wanted to write software that I could be proud of, software that I could call my baby.<sup id="fnref:consulting"><a href="#fn:consulting" class="footnote">2</a></sup> These talks gave me short and long terms goals for my company, and a plan for how I will make it happen.</p>

<p>With the help of my coach I came up with a 3 month plan, 6 month plan, 1 year plan, 5 year plan, and a 10 year plan. I’m coming up on the end of the 10 year plan, and I admit I’m not likely to reach my goals from my 10 year plan. But that fine because before I had these plans the likelihood that I would still be in business for myself in 2014 looked grim.</p>

<h1 id="have-a-structure">Have a Structure</h1>

<p>Another key component to running your own business is having the right company structure for your situation. Should you operate your business as a sole proprietor, an LLC, an S-Corp or even a C-Corp? Picking the right structure for your situation is key if you want your company to last. The company structure effects how and when you get paid, how and when taxes are paid, how much money you can stash away for retirement, and much more.</p>

<p>Talk to an accountant when deciding on a company structure. An accountant will look at your current financial situation, your short and long plans, and help you decide what company structure best suits your situation. And like your business plan, your company structure might change over time. It might be best for your business to start out as a sole proprietorship, then when revenues hit a certain amount change to an S-Corp. Or maybe your company should be a C-Corp on day one. Your accountant can help you decide what is best for you.</p>

<p>I made the mistake of setting up the company structure for White Peak Software without talking with an accountant. White Peak Software is an S-Corp, and I made that choice without consulting anyone else. Turns out I might have been better off setting up White Peak Software as a C-Corp, but even after all these years I still haven’t converted my company.</p>

<p>While being an S-Corp would not have been my accountant’s first choice for my business, it has worked out fine. Still, I wish I had gotten advice on the best company structure for my business when I first got started.</p>

<p>Speaking of my accountant…</p>

<h1 id="hire-an-accountant">Hire an Accountant</h1>

<p>You need an accountant, a really good one! A really good accountant is the virtual CFO of your company. Your accountant should do more than just file your taxes for you. You accountant should provide you with advice and direction on managing cash flow, handling and paying off debt, and all other financial areas of your business (and personal life).</p>

<p>The one thing that sticks in my mind after reading Jared Sinclair’s post about <a href="http://blog.jaredsinclair.com/post/93118460565/a-candid-look-at-unreads-first-year">Unread’s first year</a> is that 40% of his first years net revenue went towards self-employment taxes. I don’t know Jared’s particular situation or the type of company structure he was operating under, but I believe a really good accountant could have brought the amount he paid in taxes down sufficiently, maybe even down to 0%.</p>

<p>For the first three years I spent working full time for White Peak Software, the company took huge losses. Now this didn’t mean revenue wasn’t coming in - revenue was certainly coming in. It just meant company expenses were greater than the income…on paper. “On paper” is key here.</p>

<p>When I started my company I had a bedroom dedicated as my company office. White Peak Software paid me rent for the space, and this counted as a company expense. Did I actually have more money because my company was paying me rent? No. But on paper the purpose of that money impacted how much, or how little, I paid in taxes.</p>

<p>As my accountant likes to say, “Tax evasion is illegal. Tax avoidance is not.” Because the company took a loss those first three years, I was able to avoid paying incoming tax.</p>

<p>Now I don’t know Jared’s particular situation, but from reading that one blog post I can’t help but wonder, had Jared had the right company structure in place and a really good accountant, could he have kept 100% of that net revenue. It’s possible and that would have given him a better chance at staying indie longer.</p>

<p>This is why it’s important to have a really good accountant. And the earlier you get your accountant involved in your business the better.</p>

<h1 id="always-seek-advice-from-others">Always Seek Advice From Others</h1>

<p>My accountant isn’t the only person who helps advise me on financial matters. I also have a financial advisor who helps oversee my money.</p>

<p>My financial advisor is responsible for managing my retirement plan and other investments, but he is also involved with what is going on with my business. He provides a kind of “check and balance” with financial decisions and suggestions my accountant will make. If, for example, my accountant suggests a strategy for saving money or paying off debt, I run the suggestion by my financial advisor to get his feedback. And I make sure my accountant and financial advisor talk at least one a year to make sure everyone is on the same page.</p>

<h1 id="a-tip-that-has-saved-my-ass-more-than-once">A Tip That Has Saved My Ass More Than Once</h1>

<p>And speaking of financial advice, one piece of advice that has saved White Peak Software on more than one occasion is having a business line of credit with my bank. My accountant suggested this years ago. I was against the idea because 1) at the time I was debt free and had no need for the line of credit, and 2) I saw it as an easy opportunity to potentially go into debt. But White Peak Software would not be in business today if not for this outstanding piece of advice.</p>

<p>During long dry spells when cash isn’t flowing, I have access to a large sum of money that will help me weather the storm. However, I should note that I must be very diligent to pay back the borrowed money as quickly as possible once cash is flowing again, and this is sometimes not an easy thing to do. So having a business line of credit may or may not be a good thing for you and your business.</p>

<h1 id="its-about-more-than-the-app">It’s About More Than the App</h1>

<p>Being an indie developer, nay a <strong>business owner</strong> is not for everyone. It takes a lot of hard work. It takes planning and requires not only strategies for making money but strategies on how to survive when the money isn’t coming in. For the software developer turned business owner, writing the app is the easiest part, but it’s about more than the app. To survive, you need to give the business side of your company just as much attention as you give your app. Your company’s survival depends on it.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:sbc">
      <p>A small business coach is someone who can help mentor you and help you take your company to the next level. It can be someone who does coaching for a living or even a friend who is wise in the ways of running a business. My coach happens to be a business savvy friend of mine. And yes, I paid him for his time during those three months of coaching, which I easily earned back using his advice. <a href="#fnref:sbc" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:consulting">
      <p>While making a living from my own products is the ultimate goal for my company, the reality is I still rely on consulting and contract programming to help supplement my income. However, as a business owner I can be very selective with who I work with and the types of projects I work on.  This allows me to say true to writing software that I’m proud of and that I can call my baby. <a href="#fnref:consulting" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salem The Bike City]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2011/08/15/salem-the-bike-city/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2011/08/15/salem-the-bike-city</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Salem Mass is often known as The Witch City, but it’s also trying hard to become a bike city. One example of this comes from today’s announcement about a <a href="http://www.salemnews.com/local/x850300025/Salem-to-join-major-cities-in-offering-bike-sharing-program">free bike sharing program</a> here in Salem. The city has also made improvements to off-road bike paths and recently completed the striping of on-street bike lanes. The problem, however, I have with biking in Salem is with the North Shore drivers.</p>

<p>I’ve lived and biked in four different cities (and surrounding metro areas): Memphis, St. Louis, New York, and Salem. And of the four I find Salem to be the least bike friendly. The problem isn’t the city and its attention to bicycling as an alternative form of transportation. The problem is with the annoying, and often times, clueless North Shore drivers in Salem. </p>

<p>Many of these drivers ignore the most basic of driving rules. Left hand turns from the right lane. Right hand turns from the left lane. Pulling out into cross traffic to stop traffic. And stopping the flow of traffic to let an oncoming car turn left. These are but a small example of the poor driving I witness almost daily in and around Salem.</p>

<p>When my wife and I moved to Salem, we thought the Boston area had the worse drivers around. As it turns out, the problem drivers seem to be restricted to the North Shore area only. Family and friends who come to visit are oftentimes shocked at what a North Shore driver will do.</p>

<p>So the randomness of poor driving by North Shore drivers makes Salem a bike unfriendly city. But it doesn’t stop there. Some of the drivers who don’t drive like complete idiots think the sidewalk is the place for bicycles. I’ve been yelled at many times from drivers to “get off the road” and “use the sidewalk”. </p>

<p>One particular time I was stuck in traffic on Essex Street. A clueless driver driving a van kept stopping. The driver was apparently lost. The street was narrow because of cars parked on the side, so I had to claim my place in the line of traffic. Now mind you, I was riding with traffic. In other words, I was keeping up with traffic and not slowing anyone down. We were only moving about 10 miles per hour, and that’s when we were moving. Oftentimes we were stopped. The van was making the traffic stop and go. As I said, the driver was lost or even possibly talking on the phone (another rant for another time).</p>

<p>A car squeezes up to me, and the woman driver, apparently nervous to have a bicyclist in front of her, started yelling at me. I told her she should be yelling at the driver of the van ahead of us because it was him causing the traffic problem. And I said it was perfectly legal for me to ride my bike in the lane as long as I obey traffic laws, which I was (and better than she was - she would pull into the oncoming lane just to yell at me). Of course, this woman had to make it her duty to continue harassing me every time the van stopped traffic. I finally had enough of the yelling woman and the crazy van driver, so I rode past the line of traffic and darted down a side street. </p>

<p>This is just one example of the many problems I’ve had with motorist in the witch city.</p>

<p>I hope Salem continues to promote bicycling in and around the city. I, for one, would like to see this city become more bike-friendly. But I think one part missing from Salem’s bike strategy is education. Area drivers need to be better educated about the rules of the road.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>