<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-30T15:44:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Years Ago Today]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/15/two-years-ago-today/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-15T09:46:04-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/15/two-years-ago-today</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We moved to Stowe two years ago today. It seems like we’ve been here a lot longer, but in a good way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video of Stowe, Vermont]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/video-of-stowe-vermont/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-18T22:22:58-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/video-of-stowe-vermont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Ashley came across another video of Vermont. This time it’s about Stowe, the town I live in. Enjoy.</p>

<p><div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9_Wk5j_4Uc4?color=white&theme=light"></iframe></figure></div></p>

<p>The video is from <a href="http://www.vtscapes.com">VermontScapes</a>. Go checkout the site if you want to see more beautiful photos of Vermont and the Stowe area.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Essence Of Vermont]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/essence-of-vermont/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-18T06:16:26-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/essence-of-vermont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s no surprise I love living in Vermont in part because it’s different from other places I have lived. And this video from Skyworks really captures parts of why I love it here.</p>

<p><div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UBwqn9BRWhA?color=white&theme=light"></iframe></figure></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do I Need Another Twitter Account]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-14T23:09:24-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier tonight I setup a new Twitter account that tweets a link each time I publish a new post here at thecave.com. The new Twitter account is <a href="https://twitter.com/thecave_com/">@thecave_com</a>. Of course now that this is setup, I’m wondering…Do I really need a separate Twitter account, or should I just tweet the links from my <a href="https://twitter.com/kiryt/">@kirbyt</a> account?</p>

<p>I guess I will keep the two separate accounts, and I’ll retweet via @kirbyt any links that I feel might be of greater interest, which is basically what I’ve always done. So if you want to know each time a new post is published, follow @thecave_com. Otherwise just keep doing what you’ve been doing.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[thecave On Twitter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-14T22:31:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Uli <a href="https://twitter.com/uliwitness/status/600656348272001024">asked</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Do you have a Twitter feed that lets me know when you post something new?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It only took me a month, but I finally have a Twitter account for thecave. Follow <a href="https://twitter.com/thecave_com/">@thecave_com</a> on Twitter if you want to know when I post something new to this blog. And as always you can subscribe to the <a href="http://www.thecave.com/feed.xml">RSS feed</a> if you prefer feed readers over Twitter.</p>

<h2 id="the-technical-how-to">The Technical How To</h2>

<p>There are a few different ways to automate the process of posting a link on Twitter when you publish a new blog post. <a href="http://twitterfeed.com">Twitter Feed</a> is one service I tried. It is fast and easy to setup, and it includes options such as including the title, description, or title and description in the tweet. Even though Twitter Feed is a cinch to setup, I decided to go with <a href="https://ifttt.com/">If This Then That (IFTTT)</a> instead.</p>

<p>Using IFTTT create a new recipe. Select <em>Feed</em> for the trigger and <em>Twitter</em> for the action. Be sure to connect your Twitter account to the IFTTT if you have not already done so. And that’s it. Next time you make a blog post, IFTTT will update your Twitter account with the title and link to the post.</p>

<p>And thanks <a href="https://twitter.com/uliwitness">@uliwitness</a> for suggesting I do this.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>