<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-25T08:11:43-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Love this picture]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/love-this-picture/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-25T08:08:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/love-this-picture</id>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I love this picture of Rowan and his cousin Sedona. Taken last weekend at Stowe Mountain Resort. <img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2813/32769104684_cec6f7e85b_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>
]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love this picture of Rowan and his cousin Sedona. Taken last weekend at Stowe Mountain Resort. <img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2813/32769104684_cec6f7e85b_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Micro blogging from thecave]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/micro-blogging-from-thecave/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-25T07:15:34-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2017/03/25/micro-blogging-from-thecave</id>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Testing, testing. 1, 2, 3…I moved my RSS feed for <a href="http://micro.blog">micro.blog</a> to <a href="https://www.thecave.com/">thecave.com</a> since I’m no longer actively working on my app, Cross Post.</p>
]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Testing, testing. 1, 2, 3…I moved my RSS feed for <a href="http://micro.blog">micro.blog</a> to <a href="https://www.thecave.com/">thecave.com</a> since I’m no longer actively working on my app, Cross Post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wow! Busy weekends ahead]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/30/wow-busy-weekends-ahead/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-30T20:34:29-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/30/wow-busy-weekends-ahead</id>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A friend emailed me asking if I’m around in two weekends. He wants to visit me in Stowe and do a little riding together. I haven’t seen this friend in years, and it will be great to catch up ago. The problem is, I discovered I’m busy every weekend through the end of March. Turns out, when you live in a ski town, lots of people want to come for a visit.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A friend emailed me asking if I’m around in two weekends. He wants to visit me in Stowe and do a little riding together. I haven’t seen this friend in years, and it will be great to catch up ago. The problem is, I discovered I’m busy every weekend through the end of March. Turns out, when you live in a ski town, lots of people want to come for a visit.</p>

<p>So if you want to visit me in Stowe, and you want to ride together, it’ll have to be during the weekday or a weekend towards the end of March beginning of April.</p>

<p>And in case you’re wondering, the skiing and riding in Stowe has been superb recently.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Siri, Text Evernote]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/20/hey-siri-text-evernote/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-20T06:52:48-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2017/01/20/hey-siri-text-evernote</id>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Do you use <a href="https://evernote.com">Evernote</a>? Ever wish you could quickly save a note to Evernote hands-free? I found a way.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you use <a href="https://evernote.com">Evernote</a>? Ever wish you could quickly save a note to Evernote hands-free? I found a way.</p>

<p>For nearly a year now, I’ve been using Evernote to store everything. Even the draft of this blog post was written using Evernote. As my dependency on Evernote grew, so did my need to quickly capture new ideas when I wasn’t near my computer. Sure, I can use my iPhone to save a note, but how do I save one when I can’t using my phone. What if I’m driving and an idea comes to mind that I want to capture. What then? Pull the car over just to use Evernote. Sorry, I’m obsessed with using Evernote, but not that obsessed.</p>

<p>Thankfully I found a way to record my ideas to Evernote that I can do it even while driving. All I do is say, “Hey Siri text Evernote…”</p>

<h1 id="how-it-works">How it works</h1>

<p><a href="https://ifttt.com/">IFTTT</a> is an online service that lets you connect one service to another. It’s watching for actions from one service, and when they happen, it triggers an action in the other service. For instance, if you post a picture to Instagram, then save it to Dropbox. IFTTT can do that for you. It’s even in their name. IFTTT is If This, Then That. If I post a picture to Instagram, then save it to Dropbox. If This, Then That.</p>

<p>IFTTT supports incoming SMS messages. IFTTT can also save a note Evernote. I created an applet — that’s what IFTTT calls the rules that connect services together — that combines these two services. The applet accepts an incoming SMS message, then saves the message to Evernote.</p>

<p>IFTTT provides the phone number for the SMS message, which I added to my contacts list. I named the contact Evernote. Now, whenever I need to save an idea to Evernote quickly, I just send a text message to my Evernote contact. Cool, eh? Wait, it gets even cooler.</p>

<h1 id="hey-siri-text-evernote">Hey Siri, Text Evernote</h1>

<p>iPhone and Apple Watch have a nifty feature where you can say, “Hey Siri” and have Siri do some task for you. I use this all this time for things like setting a timer. “Hey Siri, set a 5 minute timer.” BAM! Siri sets a 5-minute timer for me. But Siri can do more. She can send a text message. Heck, she’ll even type the message as you speak. So while I’m driving, I raise my wrist and say into my Apple Watch, “Hey Siri, text Evernote, write a blog post on how I save ideas to Evernote without using my hands.” My watch sends the message to my iPhone, which sends out the SMS to IFTTT, which saves the message to Evernote.</p>

<p>Pretty dang cool, eh?</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trying a little experiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2016/12/30/trying-a-little-experiment/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-30T18:01:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2016/12/30/trying-a-little-experiment</id>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I want an easy way to share certain posts to social media sites, such as Facebook and Twitter, at the time I publish the post. The more I can automate, the better. The problem is this site is a static HTML site generated by <a href="https://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> and hosted on <a href="https://pages.github.com">Github Pages</a>.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want an easy way to share certain posts to social media sites, such as Facebook and Twitter, at the time I publish the post. The more I can automate, the better. The problem is this site is a static HTML site generated by <a href="https://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> and hosted on <a href="https://pages.github.com">Github Pages</a>.</p>

<p>So how do I automatically share a post to Facebook or Twitter? That’s what I’m experimenting with right now, and this post is my test post.</p>

<h2 id="whats-going-on">What’s Going On</h2>

<p>For the techies reading this, here’s what I’m doing.</p>

<p>First, I updated my tags plugin to generate an RSS feed file for each tag. Next, I setup <a href="https://ifttt.com">IFTTT</a> to monitor the feed files for the tags “facebook” and “twitter”. When IFTTT detects a new feed file item (i.e., a new blog post), it will post the item to the appropriate social media site. If I want to share a post to Facebook, I simply tag it with “facebook”. And if I want to share the post on Twitter, I tag it with “twitter”.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/kirbyt/site-www-thecave-com">source code for this site</a> is available on <a href="https://github.com/kirbyt/site-www-thecave-com">Github</a> for those who want to look under the hood.</p>

<p>Now to start work on the hard part…writing more blog posts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>