<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: family | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/family/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-28T14:24:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family Influence]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/24/family-influence/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/24/family-influence</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over on ADN, Manton Reece <a href="https://alpha.app.net/manton/post/29056754">posted</a> a link to <a href="https://thedistance.com">The Distance</a>, a new online magazine about “long lasting businesses and the people behind them”. Manton’s post included this quote:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Starting a business is the easy part. Staying in business for a while is harder.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This got me thinking about <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">my own business</a>, which has been around for more than ten years. More importantly it got me thinking about the family influences in my life that unbeknownst to me, until recently, led to me working for myself. I have often shared the story about how the <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/27/woohoo-white-peak-software-is-10-years-old/">idea to start White Peak Software</a> came about, at a swim-up bar during my honeymoon, but I’ve never really talked about the family influences that helped lead me down the path of becoming a business owner. The reason for this is simple. It never occurred to me until recently.</p>

<p>My grandfather (my dad’s dad) was a successful business owner running his own lumber company for many years. My dad owned a general maintenance company. My aunt’s husband (my dad’s sister’s husband) opened <a href="http://www.jamesmiddletonjewelers.com">James Middleton Jewelers</a> back in 1955, and the store is still in business today run by my cousin Vickie.</p>

<p>Entrepreneurship was, and still is, common on my mom’s side of the family as well. My mom and her sisters opened and ran their own hair salon for a short period of time. My mom’s oldest sister’s husband ran his own accounting firm that is still in business today and still run by family members. My mom’s youngest sister, Beth and her husband Jay, owned Gary’s Ice Cream and Deli, the place of my very first “real” job, and later Mikey’s. My sister Renay’s husband has his own pressure washing company, and my grandmother, Dot, made and sold crafts.</p>

<p>I grew up surrounded by family members pursuing their own dreams and making their own destiny. Some were, and still are, successful in their business endeavors while others were not so lucky. But even the unlucky ones tried. They took the chance at running their own business. And all of this has had a huge impact on me even though I did not realized it until recently.</p>

<p>Thank you to all my family members who have influenced me directly and indirectly with their entrepreneur spirit. <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">White Peak Software</a> would not be here, and I would be living the life I live today if not for your influence.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still No Regrets]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/08/still-no-regrets/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/08/still-no-regrets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I pierced my ear when I was 16 or 17 years old. I did it myself on the way to school. I stopped by my mom’s place to pick up my little sister. While my mom was busy getting my sister ready, I grabbed two ice cubes from the frig, and I used them to numb my ear lobe. Then I took a piercing ear ring, the kind with a pointy end, and shoved it through my ear lobe. It made a pop sound as it pushed through the backside of my ear lobe. I felt nothing. It was easy peasy.</p>

<p>I don’t remember if it was later than day or the next when my dad found out. Needless to say, he was not happy. In fact he was very angry with me. As he shared his disappointment with me, he told me having my ear pierced was just a fad and that I would soon regret it. Well, 30 plus years later I’m still wearing earrings and I still have no regrets.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Long Day with the Kid]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/01/19/super-long-day-with-the-kid/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/01/19/super-long-day-with-the-kid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Melanie’s out of town enjoying some quality vacation time with one of her girlfriends leaving Rowan and me in Salem to enjoy some quality father son time. We made the most of it today, which has turned into a super long day. </p>

<p>Rowan woke me up at 4 AM looking for his blanket and Blue Doggie. Naturally, I couldn’t go back to sleep so I did some work starting at 4:30 AM. Rowan woke up at 8 AM, so I put the laptop away and started entertaining the kid. We had breakfast and played during the morning. At lunch time, we ate lunch while watching a Star Wars movie. Then we headed to the Boston Children’s Museum. We stayed until closing time, then headed to Rowan’s favorite restaurant, Acapulcos, for dinner. Then we had more play time, and had “movie night,” which was another Star Wars movie. Finally, the kid hit the sack at 10:30 PM and I jumped back on the laptop to do a bit of work.</p>

<p>Needless to say, it’s been a super long, and exhausting, day for both of us. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Christmas 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/12/25/christmas-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/12/25/christmas-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Christmas/Christmas-2012/27252258_tNP4bM"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Christmas/Christmas-2012/i-cxCnk8n/0/Th/IMG_0911-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> We spent Christmas in Salem this year. Mother Nature was kind and gave us a little snow this morning, but it melted by mid-afternoon. I repeated the tradition I started a few years back by smoking a turkey for dinner. It’s was delicious, but not has favor packed as it was 2 years ago. I blame it on the lack of thyme. The grocery store was all out when I went shopping. </p>

<p>Rowan got lots of toys. It’s hard to tell which ones are his favorite since he has played with them all. Melanie got a set of stemless wine glasses, which is something she has wanted for a long time. And they’re the perfect companion to the wine chiller she got last Christmas. I got a new solar powered keyboard for my Mac, which I’m using right now to type this postings. And Rowan made me a coffee cup, which will be perfect for my hot cocoa fix.</p>

<p>Overall, it’s been a good, low key Christmas, just the way we like it.</p>

<p>(Photos from our Christmas holiday are available <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Christmas/Christmas-2012/27252258_tNP4bM">here</a>.)</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>