<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: family | thecave | Ramblings from a crotchety old man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/family/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-05T02:07:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Long Day with the Kid]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/01/19/super-long-day-with-the-kid/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/01/19/super-long-day-with-the-kid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Melanie&#8217;s out of town enjoying some quality vacation time with one of her girlfriends leaving Rowan and me in Salem to enjoy some quality father son time. We made the most of it today, which has turned into a super long day.</p>

<p>Rowan woke me up at 4 AM looking for his blanket and Blue Doggie. Naturally, I couldn&#8217;t go back to sleep so I did some work starting at 4:30 AM. Rowan woke up at 8 AM, so I put the laptop away and started entertaining the kid. We had breakfast and played during the morning. At lunch time, we ate lunch while watching a Star Wars movie. Then we headed to the Boston Children&#8217;s Museum. We stayed until closing time, then headed to Rowan&#8217;s favorite restaurant, Acapulcos, for dinner. Then we had more play time, and had &#8220;movie night,&#8221; which was another Star Wars movie. Finally, the kid hit the sack at 10:30 PM and I jumped back on the laptop to do a bit of work.</p>

<p>Needless to say, it&#8217;s been a super long, and exhausting, day for both of us.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Christmas 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/12/25/christmas-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/12/25/christmas-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Christmas/Christmas-2012/27252258_tNP4bM'><img alt='' border='0' class='alignleft' src='http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Christmas/Christmas-2012/i-cxCnk8n/0/Th/IMG_0911-Th.jpg' /></a> We spent Christmas in Salem this year. Mother Nature was kind and gave us a little snow this morning, but it melted by mid-afternoon. I repeated the tradition I started a few years back by smoking a turkey for dinner. It&#8217;s was delicious, but not has favor packed as it was 2 years ago. I blame it on the lack of thyme. The grocery store was all out when I went shopping.</p>

<p>Rowan got lots of toys. It&#8217;s hard to tell which ones are his favorite since he has played with them all. Melanie got a set of stemless wine glasses, which is something she has wanted for a long time. And they&#8217;re the perfect companion to the wine chiller she got last Christmas. I got a new solar powered keyboard for my Mac, which I&#8217;m using right now to type this postings. And Rowan made me a coffee cup, which will be perfect for my hot cocoa fix.</p>

<p>Overall, it&#8217;s been a good, low key Christmas, just the way we like it.</p>

<p>(Photos from our Christmas holiday are available <a href='http://photos.thecave.com/Family/Christmas/Christmas-2012/27252258_tNP4bM'>here</a>.)</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>