<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: writing | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-07T13:46:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Minutes Of Writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/15-minutes-of-writing/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T13:19:09-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/15-minutes-of-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend, Greg Raiz, talks about <a href="http://www.raizlabs.com/graiz/2015/01/05/better-goals-via-better-systems/">using a system to achieve goals</a>. The particular goal he wants to achieve is writing more.</p>

<p>I’ve tried using a system similar to what Greg describes, but I fail each time I try. My system, or goal as I still often call it, has been to write an hour each day. Writing an hour day, often times more, was easy when I was writing my books, but I can’t seem to get into the routine now that I’m done with book writing (for now). I realized after reading Greg’s post that I’ve been doing it wrong. </p>

<p>Greg’s plan is to write about 100 words a day, or for about 15 minutes a day, which is about the amount of time he needs to write 100 words. And that sounds like a much more reasonable system than writing for an hour a day.</p>

<p>I wish I could write for at least an hour a day, but it’s just not in me to do that right now. Sure, if I were focused on writing a book then I would have no problem writing an hour a day. In fact, I would write more. But writing a book not my focus. Writing apps is my focus. And 15 minutes a day sounds like a perfect way for me to get back into writing.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>