<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: long trail | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/long trail/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-21T08:52:37-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working 80+ Hours Isn't The Answer]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-21T07:41:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A founder, or maybe the person is a manager type, asked on Quora, “<a href="http://www.quora.com/How-do-you-make-programmers-work-60-80-hours-per-week">How do you make programmers work 60-80 hours per week?</a>” While the question is a pathetic one, the answers that follow, especially the first one, are worth a read. And you should certainly read the answers if you happen to be one of those sad founders/manager types who wants their of programmers to work long hours. In short, if you are trying to force your programmers to work 60, 80 or more hours per week, then you are doing it wrong. </p>

<h2 id="personal-experience">Personal Experience</h2>

<p>I have first hand experience working 80+ hours per week. Heck, there were times I worked more than 100 hours in a single week at one particular startup. There were times when I would go days without going home, choosing instead to sleep in the office for an hour here and an hour there. And if I needed a change of clothes for an important meeting, I would go to the Banana Republic that was below my office to buy a change of clothes instead of going home.</p>

<p>The difference with this experience, however, was that I was never forced to put in those insane hours. No one ever asked me to work 80+ hours. I did it because I truly believed in what we were building. But I also knew what it took to be productive, and that’s why I often times made sure my team did not follow my lead. </p>

<p>I encouraged my team to work no more than 40 hours, and if I noticed someone reaching 50 hours I usually asked that person to take a break, go home, and enjoy life a bit. The work can wait. Sometimes the team member would take my suggestion and leave, other times they would not. But the choice was theirs. I never asked for more than 40 hours per week and in the end we created some amazing things in a short amount of time.</p>

<h2 id="get-to-the-point">Get To The Point</h2>

<p>So what’s my point here? My point is that you can’t force a programmer to work long hours. That person has to want to do it. There has to be a love or passion for what they are doing, otherwise it’s just work. And people max out, especially creative types, after about 32 to 40 hours of work in a single week.</p>

<h2 id="and-now">And Now</h2>

<p>I worked at a few startups putting in 60 or more hours per week, but those days are behind me. Those were fun times with lots of good memories, but I now find it’s more important to break up work with other interest. Today I’m a proponent of what I like to call underworking, or as I more often times jokingly call “being a slacker.”<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>Life’s too short to overwork yourself today in hopes you will have the time later in life for the fun things. Who knows what will happen in the future. You could be hit by a beer truck tomorrow and die. That’s why I believe you should make a point to spend more time <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing what you love</a> now. The work can wait. </p>

<h2 id="the-long-trail-and-me">The Long Trail And Me</h2>

<p>A couple of years back I did a talk on the topic of underworking at the first <a href="http://www.360intersect.com/">360intersect</a>. In it I talk about my time hiking the Long Trail and the effect it has had on me and the amount of time I spend working each week. Here’s the video for those interested in watching it and learning more about the benefits of working less.</p>

<p><div class="vimeo-video"><figure><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/65740037" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></figure></div></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Funny how working only 32 to 40 hours a week is thought to be slacking.  <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weighing In]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/21/weighing-in/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/21/weighing-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to weigh every item going with me on my end-to-end hike of the Long Trail. I’m unfortunately carrying about 5 pounds more than I was hoping, but I remind myself this is a month long hike, not a 3 to 5 day trip. I can do without some gear, such as the Solio charger, on shorter trips.</p>

<p>Here are the final weigh-in numbers:</p>

<ul>
<li>Base pack weight: 24.45 pounds</li>
<li>Fuel: 1.62 pounds</li>
<li>Food: 11.44 pounds</li>
<li>Water: 5.71 pounds</li>
</ul>

<p>Total pack weight: 43.22 pounds</p>

<p>For the more curious, I posted my <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ai_IwjXXrirWdEZrSWh6c3YtR0Q2SmtMaUZRSWQ5cWc#gid=0">gear list</a> and <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ai_IwjXXrirWdDVCYWozak50SV9DTzdMTGxSenpUbHc#gid=0">food list</a> on Google Docs.</p>

<p>What would I do differently if I could? Update some gear, specifically my backpack and sleeping bag. Updating these two items could shave off as much as 2 pounds from the base pack weight. </p>

<p>I could also go without the fitbit, Solio charger, iPhone, and cables, but I really want to track my steps, have a way to call someone if an emergency happens, and keep charged up while on the trail. Still, a little weight could be saved by leaving these items at home.</p>

<p>I could also leave the Long Trail Guide book behind, but it might prove useful while out on the trail.</p>

<p>Well, it is what it is, and a base pack weight of 24.45 isn’t too bad. It’s not great, but it will do. It is, after all, a month long hike.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pack Unpack Repeat]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/18/pack-unpack-repeat/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/18/pack-unpack-repeat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Random/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-Prep-2012/Packing-Practice/24840367_jkVX9C"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Random/Long-Trail-Thru-Hike-Prep-2012/Packing-Practice/i-9cwLz2t/0/Th/IMG0180-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> With only 5 days left before I start my hike, I spent the day packing and unpacking my backpack. To my surprise, every thing fit. But also to my surprise, the unofficial total weight is 45 pounds. This includes food and water. I was hoping my total weight would be 5 to 10 pounds less.</p>

<p>Not much I can do about it now other than to leave some gear behind. I’m planning to weigh each item on Monday, and will decide what absolutely needs to go and what can stay behind. I doubt, though, I will see much reduction of in weight. Some of my gear, such as my sleeping bag, are in desperate need of an upgrade.</p>

<p>My sleeping bag is 15 years year, and is much heavier than what I would buy today. But a new sleeping bag is not in my future anytime soon. With luck, and a change in our finical situation, I might be able to buy a lighter, better sleeping bag.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>