<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ios | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/ios/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-07T10:28:48-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boston Area Mac And iOS Dev Community Is Awesome]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/07/boston-area-mac-and-ios-dev-community-is-awesome/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-07T10:22:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/07/boston-area-mac-and-ios-dev-community-is-awesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past Wednesday I had a chance to attend <a href="http://www.nshappyhour.org">NSHappyHour</a>. It’s was my first time attending since moving to Vermont two years ago. I had a great time catching up with everyone, and I was reminded just how awesome the Mac and iOS developer community is in the Boston area. </p>

<p>I also was reminded how much I miss the community there, and since moving back isn’t an option for me - snowboard season starts in about 3 months for me - I need to make a point of visit the Boston area more.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building An App From Start To Finish]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-08T09:09:35-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amy Hoy wrote the first version of her book <a href="https://unicornfree.com/just-fucking-ship">Just Fucking Ship</a> in 24 hours, which is awesome. Along those same lines, <a href="https://twitter.com/_davidsmith">David Smith</a> built an app from start to finish in about 6 hours - also awesome, and he posted this video that shows the entire process.</p>

<p><div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rEkuRFO6xTw?color=white&theme=light"></iframe></figure></div></p>

<p>Both of these, the book and the app, are motivating me to do more faster. I just need to stop letting excuses and fear of not being perfect get in my way.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Views Created In Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/15/views-created-in-code/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-15T12:58:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/15/views-created-in-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year I posted an article that talks about why <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/04/i-stopped-using-nibs-thanks-to-auto-layout/">I stopped using Interface Builder</a> in favor of writing code to create views. There are some who disagree with me, and to them I say, “To each his own.” And there are some who agree with me, but choose not to publicize it. No matter. Every programmer has tricks that make them more productive, and creating views in code just happens to be one trick that works well for me. </p>

<p>What works for me doesn’t necessarily work for others. But I have to say, I had a brief “HA!” moment when I read this comment from Peter Steinberger’s post about <a href="http://petersteinberger.com/blog/2015/researching-researchkit/">researching Apple’s research kit</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>All views are created in code. Apple uses a Storyboard for the example catalog, but that’s it. Apple uses the standard pattern of overriding <code>viewDidLoad</code> to build UI in combination with Auto Layout and the visual format language, whenever possible.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Great minds think alike.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Though I don’t override <code>viewDidLoad</code> to create my views. I usually create a view class, and I add an instance of the class to the view controller’s view in <code>loadView</code>. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No WWDC Or SF Trip]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-14T09:20:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple announced the dates for this year’s WWDC, and once again a lottery is being used to decide who gets to buy a ticket. I have no interesting is attending WWDC other than to attend the labs since I do have questions I would love to ask an Apple engineer. But it’s not worth spending $1599 on a ticket just for that. </p>

<p>Likewise, I’m struggling to justify spending the money to stay in San Francisco the week of WWDC just to hang out with friends and drink beer. Certainly reconnecting with friends and making news ones is very enjoyable, but there are cheaper ways for me to do that. So I’ve decided I’m not going to SF for this year’s WWDC. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Watch Will Make iPhone 6 Plus Size Less Annoying]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-06T21:42:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things that annoys me most about the size of my iPhone 6 Plus is pulling it out of my pocket while at a bar or restaurant just to see why my phone buzzed. The majority of the time my phone buzzes because of an incoming text message. I have notifications turned off for almost all other apps, and I rarely. if ever, get phone calls these days, which is why I know the buzz is most likely a text message. And if I’m at the bar without my wife, then the person trying to reach me is most likely my wife. </p>

<p>So when the text message comes in, I have to pull out this big honkin’ device out of my pocket and light up the room just to see the message. I may reply, and if I do, it’s a short reply because, after all, I’m busy at the bar. Then I put the phone back into my pocket only to repeat all of this a few minutes later. </p>

<p>Receiving text messages doesn’t annoy me, but having to pull out and put away this big device every few minutes does annoy me. </p>

<p>It occurred to me that one of the possible reasons why Apple decided to release the larger iPhones was because they knew, thanks to the Apple Watch, that there would be no reason to pull out these larger devices from pockets and purses just to check notifications and send simple text messages and replies.</p>

<p>The Apple Watch will make the iPhone 6 Plus size less annoying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>