<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: social | thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/social/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-02T11:35:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boston Area Mac And iOS Dev Community Is Awesome]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/07/boston-area-mac-and-ios-dev-community-is-awesome/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-07T10:22:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/07/boston-area-mac-and-ios-dev-community-is-awesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past Wednesday I had a chance to attend <a href="http://www.nshappyhour.org">NSHappyHour</a>. It’s was my first time attending since moving to Vermont two years ago. I had a great time catching up with everyone, and I was reminded just how awesome the Mac and iOS developer community is in the Boston area.</p>

<p>I also was reminded how much I miss the community there, and since moving back isn’t an option for me - snowboard season starts in about 3 months for me - I need to make a point of visit the Boston area more.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fear]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/02/fear/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-02T06:48:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/02/fear</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I’ve been struggling to release new things out to the public, things such as blog posts, open source code, a new website and service I want to offer, even updates to some of my apps. What’s worse is that a number of these things are done and are just sitting on my computer. For instance, I’ve been using an updated version of Cross Post for nearly two months that isn’t available in the App Store.</p>

<p>So why haven’t I pulled the trigger on these things and released them to the public? Fear, that’s my answer.</p>

<p>I’m letting fear get the best me recently. I fear what people might say or think of the work I’m going. I fear that friends will start looking down on me. I fear that I will end up looking like an idiot. The funny part is I don’t have a fear of failing. You learn from failure. But for some odd reason I have developed a fear what others, especially friends, will think.</p>

<h2 id="out-of-character">Out of Character</h2>

<p>This fear of what others will think is completely out of character for me. For most of my life I’ve had a “I don’t give a fuck what other think” attitude (and that’s exactly how I’ve always put it). I was the high school weirdo with dyed hair and strange clothes. I was the nonconformist who would occasionally wear a polo shirt just to throw off my small circle of friends. In college I had a my racquetball racquet strung with bright hot pink strings, which led to some heated confrontations with others<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>. The point here is I didn’t care what others thought.</p>

<p>I remember an evening years ago when my dad refused to go out to dinner with me because of the way I was dressed. He said I embarrassed him. I argued that he was being ridiculous because 1) it wasn’t him that was dressed up like a Boy George reject and if anyone should be embarrassed it should be me (though I wasn’t), and 2) if I don’t care what people think about me, then why should he care. If anything people will feel sorry for him for having to sit with me at a restaurant. My argument didn’t change his mind and our dinner plans were canceled.</p>

<p>So if this fear is out of character for me, then where is it coming from?</p>

<h2 id="where-is-it-coming-from">Where Is It Coming From</h2>

<p>I know my fear is irrational when I think about it. But it’s still there and I can’t seem to shake it. Recently I’ve been putting a lot of thought into where this fear is coming from, and I think I might know.</p>

<p>I’ve been much more isolated since moving to Vermont. I don’t have the social circle of independent software developers and business owners around me like I did when I lived in New York City and the Boston area. Most of my social interactions these days involved talking about snowboarding and hiking, not on product releases, marketing, and growing a business.</p>

<p>Before moving to Vermont I attended a number of social gatherings where I could talk about and share my ideas. These groups were great and always provided excellent feedback. I always listened to what others had to say, but I didn’t always follow their advice. For example, I released a CSV editor for Windows years ago and made a good money from it for a number of years even though all my software dev friends said not to do it. Still, talking about the ideas with other on a regular bases always felt good, but I no longer have a local circle of friends and peers like I did before. And I think that is why I’ve developed this fear inside me.</p>

<p>Even though I didn’t care, for most of my life, what others thoughts, hearing what others had to say, both good or bad, always helped me. But in my recent isolation I rarely, if ever, get feedback from others. Hearing “you suck” motivated me to do better. Hearing “that’s awesome” in encouraged me to do more. But hearing nothing, no feedback at all, for long periods of time has caused this fear to grow inside of me.</p>

<h2 id="get-over-the-fear">Get Over The Fear</h2>

<p>I know my fears are irrational, but I can’t seem to shake them. So I’m trying a few new things in my attempts to get over the fear.</p>

<p>I’m trying to build a small community here in Stowe (though I think about giving up each month). A few folks do join me each month, but the group is not the same as the ones I participated in before coming to Vermont. Like the gatherings I attended before, this new group is made up of mostly software developers. But what is missing for me are the independents, the business owners, the solopreneur that were common in the circles I had when I lived in NYC and Boston.</p>

<p>I’m also participating in a bi-weekly mastermind group. This is going well, and in fact, it was on a recent mastermind call that I realized I’ve developed this irrational fear. My fear came up again last night in an email exchange with a friend who is doing a far better job of shipping than me. Talking about my fear with others as well as what I’m working on and my goals is starting to help me return to my old self, but I need to do more.</p>

<p>Another thing I’m interested in trying but I haven’t started yet is working with an accountability partner. The concept is simple. You and your partner help each other keep weekly commitments. Once a week you and your partner chat about the previous week’s accomplishments and the current week’s goals. When goals are not met, you analyze and talk through what happened. Having someone hold me accountable each week will help get me back into the habit of releasing things, which in turn will help me get over my fears.</p>

<p>One other thing I am doing in my attempts to shake the fear is to leave my quiet “cave” here in Stowe and get back into interacting in person with peers. To get things started, I agreed last week to speak at a small conference in October (more on this later). Just knowing I have this speaking event coming up should help reset my brain back to where it once was, or so I hope.</p>

<p>Are you having or had the similar fears? What sort of things are your doing to get over it? Fire off an email to me or send me a tweet and let me know.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>To this day I still don’t understand why people get so worked up over something so silly such as the string color of a racquetball racquet or the appearance of others. Just because it’s not something you would do, wear, or whatever doesn’t mean you need to hate on the other person. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do I Need Another Twitter Account]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-14T23:09:24-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier tonight I setup a new Twitter account that tweets a link each time I publish a new post here at thecave.com. The new Twitter account is <a href="https://twitter.com/thecave_com/">@thecave_com</a>. Of course now that this is setup, I’m wondering…Do I really need a separate Twitter account, or should I just tweet the links from my <a href="https://twitter.com/kiryt/">@kirbyt</a> account?</p>

<p>I guess I will keep the two separate accounts, and I’ll retweet via @kirbyt any links that I feel might be of greater interest, which is basically what I’ve always done. So if you want to know each time a new post is published, follow @thecave_com. Otherwise just keep doing what you’ve been doing.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[thecave On Twitter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-14T22:31:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Uli <a href="https://twitter.com/uliwitness/status/600656348272001024">asked</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Do you have a Twitter feed that lets me know when you post something new?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It only took me a month, but I finally have a Twitter account for thecave. Follow <a href="https://twitter.com/thecave_com/">@thecave_com</a> on Twitter if you want to know when I post something new to this blog. And as always you can subscribe to the <a href="http://www.thecave.com/feed.xml">RSS feed</a> if you prefer feed readers over Twitter.</p>

<h2 id="the-technical-how-to">The Technical How To</h2>

<p>There are a few different ways to automate the process of posting a link on Twitter when you publish a new blog post. <a href="http://twitterfeed.com">Twitter Feed</a> is one service I tried. It is fast and easy to setup, and it includes options such as including the title, description, or title and description in the tweet. Even though Twitter Feed is a cinch to setup, I decided to go with <a href="https://ifttt.com/">If This Then That (IFTTT)</a> instead.</p>

<p>Using IFTTT create a new recipe. Select <em>Feed</em> for the trigger and <em>Twitter</em> for the action. Be sure to connect your Twitter account to the IFTTT if you have not already done so. And that’s it. Next time you make a blog post, IFTTT will update your Twitter account with the title and link to the post.</p>

<p>And thanks <a href="https://twitter.com/uliwitness">@uliwitness</a> for suggesting I do this.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Après Code: A New Developer Meetup In Stowe Vt]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/05/apres-code-a-new-developer-meetup-in-stowe-vt/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-05T10:54:05-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/05/apres-code-a-new-developer-meetup-in-stowe-vt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started organizing developer related meetups in 2001 starting with a weekly happy hour for dev friends and co-workers. Over the years I ended up organizing different types of events, from monthly meetings that included speakers to parties and happy hours to annual snowboarding trips. I even started <a href="http://www.nshappyhour.org">NSHappyHour</a> for Mac and iOS developers, which is still going on each month in Salem, MA.</p>

<p>I realized as I prepared for my move to Stowe, VT, that I was burnt out organizing events and meetups. I stepped down as co-organizer of <a href="http://www.cocoaheadsboston.org">CocoaHeads Boston</a> a few months before my move, which gave me a chance to be just a regular attendee. That’s when I realized I was done organizing events for a while.</p>

<p>After moving to Vermont, I was asked by a few folks if I would start a <a href="http://cocoaheads.org">CocoaHeads</a> chapter in the Burlington area. I said no because I needed a break. The break I needed wasn’t just from being an organizer. I needed a break from attending developer focused gatherings and networking events too. And while it’s been a bit lonely not having local folks to talk shop with on a regular basis, I’ve enjoyed my break. But break time is over.</p>

<p>It’s been nearly two years since I was last responsible for a meetup, but that changes tonight with the first of many Après Code events.</p>

<p>I’ve been thinking about hosting a developer meetup in Stowe since I moved here, but I wasn’t initially sure there would be enough interest. However, in my short time here I’ve met other software developers living in the area. Some work for companies here in town while others work for shops in and around Burlington. And the number of developers in our small community is growing with companies like <a href="http://corp.inntopia.com/careers/">Inntopia hiring</a> more developers. Even though I knew there were developers living and working in the area, I wasn’t ready to commit to a monthly meetup just yet.</p>

<p>That changed two days before I left for Whistler. I was talking with a local dev friend, Maya Ropelip<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, about writing apps for iOS. During our chat I mentioned my idea for a local meetup. He got excited about the idea and thought the timing was right for hosting a software developer gathering in Stowe. He also agreed to be the co-host in case I need to skip a meetup. So that night I grabbed the domain name, setup a <a href="http://www.apres-code.com/">website</a>, and created a new group on <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Apres-Code/">meetup.com</a>.</p>

<p>Starting a new group just 48 hours before I leave the country for a week and a half wasn’t the smartest thing for me to do, but I did it anyways. And now that I’m back home, I’m scrambling to get the word out about tonight’s inaugural Après Code. So without further ado, I’m happy to officially announce <a href="http://www.apres-code.com/">Après Code</a>.</p>

<h1 id="what-is-aprs-code">What Is Après Code</h1>

<p>Après Code is an informal gathering of software developers in Stowe, Vermont. The gathering is a chance for those of us living in and around Stowe, or just visiting the area, to get together to talk about joys of producing software and writing code, seek help or assist others, and most importantly meet and get to know other fine folks in the our community. The group is open to professionals, hobbyists, and anyone with an interest in designing, programming and creating software, apps, and websites.</p>

<h2 id="when">When</h2>

<p>We meet the first Thursday of each month, starting tonight, at 6:30 pm and go until the last person leaves. We’re gathering at <a href="http://rimrocksmountaintavern.com/">Rimrock’s Tavern</a> though this could change in the future. But for now Rimrock’s is the place to be.</p>

<h2 id="more-information">More Information</h2>

<p>You can find more information about the group at the Après Code <a href="http://www.apres-code.com/">website</a>, and you can receive email reminders about future Après Code events by joining the Après Code <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Apres-Code/">meetup.com group</a>.</p>

<p>So if you happen to be in the area, whether you live in the Stowe area or are just visiting, stop by tonight to say hi.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I gotta get this guy on Twitter or some other social network. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>