<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: videos | thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/videos/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-05-02T12:29:17+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video of Stowe, Vermont]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/video-of-stowe-vermont/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-19T02:22:58+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/video-of-stowe-vermont</id>
    <tag>videos</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>My friend Ashley came across another video of Vermont. This time it’s about Stowe, the town I live in. Enjoy.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Ashley came across another video of Vermont. This time it’s about Stowe, the town I live in. Enjoy.</p>

<p><div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9_Wk5j_4Uc4?color=white&theme=light"></iframe></figure></div></p>

<p>The video is from <a href="http://www.vtscapes.com">VermontScapes</a>. Go checkout the site if you want to see more beautiful photos of Vermont and the Stowe area.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Essence Of Vermont]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/essence-of-vermont/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-18T10:16:26+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/18/essence-of-vermont</id>
    <tag>videos</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>It’s no surprise I love living in Vermont in part because it’s different from other places I have lived. And this video from Skyworks really captures parts of why I love it here.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s no surprise I love living in Vermont in part because it’s different from other places I have lived. And this video from Skyworks really captures parts of why I love it here.</p>

<p><div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UBwqn9BRWhA?color=white&theme=light"></iframe></figure></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building An App From Start To Finish]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-08T13:09:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/08/building-an-app-from-start-to-finish</id>
    <tag>videos</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Amy Hoy wrote the first version of her book <a href="https://unicornfree.com/just-fucking-ship">Just Fucking Ship</a> in 24 hours, which is awesome. Along those same lines, <a href="https://twitter.com/_davidsmith">David Smith</a> built an app from start to finish in about 6 hours - also awesome, and he posted this video that shows the entire process.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amy Hoy wrote the first version of her book <a href="https://unicornfree.com/just-fucking-ship">Just Fucking Ship</a> in 24 hours, which is awesome. Along those same lines, <a href="https://twitter.com/_davidsmith">David Smith</a> built an app from start to finish in about 6 hours - also awesome, and he posted this video that shows the entire process.</p>

<p><div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rEkuRFO6xTw?color=white&theme=light"></iframe></figure></div></p>

<p>Both of these, the book and the app, are motivating me to do more faster. I just need to stop letting excuses and fear of not being perfect get in my way.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snow River At Stowe]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-09T15:24:25+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe</id>
    <tag>videos</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>This looks like it was a lot of fun. Wish I had known about it when it happened last year.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This looks like it was a lot of fun. Wish I had known about it when it happened last year.</p>

<p><div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wfWUHKUt-Q0?color=white&theme=light"></iframe></figure></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working 80+ Hours Isn't The Answer]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-21T12:41:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/21/working-80-hours-isnt-the-answer</id>
    <tag>videos</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A founder, or maybe the person is a manager type, asked on Quora, “<a href="http://www.quora.com/How-do-you-make-programmers-work-60-80-hours-per-week">How do you make programmers work 60-80 hours per week?</a>” While the question is a pathetic one, the answers that follow, especially the first one, are worth a read. And you should certainly read the answers if you happen to be one of those sad founders/manager types who wants their of programmers to work long hours. In short, if you are trying to force your programmers to work 60, 80 or more hours per week, then you are doing it wrong.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A founder, or maybe the person is a manager type, asked on Quora, “<a href="http://www.quora.com/How-do-you-make-programmers-work-60-80-hours-per-week">How do you make programmers work 60-80 hours per week?</a>” While the question is a pathetic one, the answers that follow, especially the first one, are worth a read. And you should certainly read the answers if you happen to be one of those sad founders/manager types who wants their of programmers to work long hours. In short, if you are trying to force your programmers to work 60, 80 or more hours per week, then you are doing it wrong.</p>

<h2 id="personal-experience">Personal Experience</h2>

<p>I have first hand experience working 80+ hours per week. Heck, there were times I worked more than 100 hours in a single week at one particular startup. There were times when I would go days without going home, choosing instead to sleep in the office for an hour here and an hour there. And if I needed a change of clothes for an important meeting, I would go to the Banana Republic that was below my office to buy a change of clothes instead of going home.</p>

<p>The difference with this experience, however, was that I was never forced to put in those insane hours. No one ever asked me to work 80+ hours. I did it because I truly believed in what we were building. But I also knew what it took to be productive, and that’s why I often times made sure my team did not follow my lead.</p>

<p>I encouraged my team to work no more than 40 hours, and if I noticed someone reaching 50 hours I usually asked that person to take a break, go home, and enjoy life a bit. The work can wait. Sometimes the team member would take my suggestion and leave, other times they would not. But the choice was theirs. I never asked for more than 40 hours per week and in the end we created some amazing things in a short amount of time.</p>

<h2 id="get-to-the-point">Get To The Point</h2>

<p>So what’s my point here? My point is that you can’t force a programmer to work long hours. That person has to want to do it. There has to be a love or passion for what they are doing, otherwise it’s just work. And people max out, especially creative types, after about 32 to 40 hours of work in a single week.</p>

<h2 id="and-now">And Now</h2>

<p>I worked at a few startups putting in 60 or more hours per week, but those days are behind me. Those were fun times with lots of good memories, but I now find it’s more important to break up work with other interest. Today I’m a proponent of what I like to call underworking, or as I more often times jokingly call “being a slacker.”<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>Life’s too short to overwork yourself today in hopes you will have the time later in life for the fun things. Who knows what will happen in the future. You could be hit by a beer truck tomorrow and die. That’s why I believe you should make a point to spend more time <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing what you love</a> now. The work can wait.</p>

<h2 id="the-long-trail-and-me">The Long Trail And Me</h2>

<p>A couple of years back I did a talk on the topic of underworking at the first <a href="http://www.360intersect.com/">360intersect</a>. In it I talk about my time hiking the Long Trail and the effect it has had on me and the amount of time I spend working each week. Here’s the video for those interested in watching it and learning more about the benefits of working less.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<p><div class="vimeo-video"><figure><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/65740037" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></figure></div></p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Funny how working only 32 to 40 hours a week is thought to be slacking.&nbsp;<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>Sorry the first couple of minutes of the talk are missing. Someone forgot to push the record button.&nbsp;<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>