<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: social | thecave | Ramblings from a crotchety old man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/social/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-22T17:10:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Tradition Comes To A Close Tonight]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/22/a-tradition-comes-to-a-close-tonight/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/22/a-tradition-comes-to-a-close-tonight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On December 22, 2001, I was in Whistler with my friends Dave and Joe. We spent the day snowboarding, then that night we went to see the first Lord of the Rings movie. Little did I know that night would become a tradition of sorts for me.</p>

<p>On December 22, 2002, I repeated the previous year by snowboarding, though not at Whistler, during the day and went to see the second LOTR movie that night. And yep, I did it again December 22, 2003. My wife, who joined me for the second and third movies, was glad the trilogy was over. Snowboarding a full day then going to a long movie that evening made for a long day. But then The Hobbit came out so…</p>

<p>On December 22, 2012, the tradition resumed with a full day of snowboarding followed by watching first hobbit movie. And one year later, December 22, 2013, was another long day of snowboarding and hobbits. </p>

<p>And this brings us to today, December 22, 2014. I spent the day snowboarding and tonight I will go see The Hobbit: The Battle of the Five Armies. The tradition continues for one more day, but unless there are more hobbit movies hitting movie theaters in the future, this tradition comes to a close tonight.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Organizing Events]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/06/not-organizing-events/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/06/not-organizing-events</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I lived in NYC I organized and ran events for computer geeks like me. It was a lot of fun, and a great way to meet new people. Then I moved to Salem, Mass, a suburb of Boston, and again I organized and ran events in Salem and Boston. And again it was a lot of fun and a great way to meet new people.</p>

<p>I now live in Stowe, Vermont, and as of right now I have zero desire to organize and run events for like-minded computer nerds. After being so involved organizing meetups and such for over 10 years, it’s nice to take a break. That said, I sometimes wish someone had a tech-focused garthering in Stowe. I wonder how long before I end up organizing something.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross Posting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/03/14/cross-posting/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/03/14/cross-posting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to go back to cross posting between ADN, Twitter, and Facebook. I’m not as active as I once was on any one of these social networks, so I figured cross posting won’t cause too much noise in the streams of followers. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>