<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: social | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/social/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-10T11:55:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do I Need Another Twitter Account]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-14T23:09:24-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/do-i-need-another-twitter-account</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier tonight I setup a new Twitter account that tweets a link each time I publish a new post here at thecave.com. The new Twitter account is <a href="https://twitter.com/thecave_com/">@thecave_com</a>. Of course now that this is setup, I’m wondering…Do I really need a separate Twitter account, or should I just tweet the links from my <a href="https://twitter.com/kiryt/">@kirbyt</a> account?</p>

<p>I guess I will keep the two separate accounts, and I’ll retweet via @kirbyt any links that I feel might be of greater interest, which is basically what I’ve always done. So if you want to know each time a new post is published, follow @thecave_com. Otherwise just keep doing what you’ve been doing.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[thecave On Twitter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-14T22:31:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/14/thecave-on-twitter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend Uli <a href="https://twitter.com/uliwitness/status/600656348272001024">asked</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Do you have a Twitter feed that lets me know when you post something new?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It only took me a month, but I finally have a Twitter account for thecave. Follow <a href="https://twitter.com/thecave_com/">@thecave_com</a> on Twitter if you want to know when I post something new to this blog. And as always you can subscribe to the <a href="http://www.thecave.com/feed.xml">RSS feed</a> if you prefer feed readers over Twitter.</p>

<h2 id="the-technical-how-to">The Technical How To</h2>

<p>There are a few different ways to automate the process of posting a link on Twitter when you publish a new blog post. <a href="http://twitterfeed.com">Twitter Feed</a> is one service I tried. It is fast and easy to setup, and it includes options such as including the title, description, or title and description in the tweet. Even though Twitter Feed is a cinch to setup, I decided to go with <a href="https://ifttt.com/">If This Then That (IFTTT)</a> instead.</p>

<p>Using IFTTT create a new recipe. Select <em>Feed</em> for the trigger and <em>Twitter</em> for the action. Be sure to connect your Twitter account to the IFTTT if you have not already done so. And that’s it. Next time you make a blog post, IFTTT will update your Twitter account with the title and link to the post.</p>

<p>And thanks <a href="https://twitter.com/uliwitness">@uliwitness</a> for suggesting I do this.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eliminating Distractions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/18/eliminating-distractions/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-18T13:49:47-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/18/eliminating-distractions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dan Counsell wrote an excellent post about <a href="http://dancounsell.com/articles/removing-distractions">removing distractions</a>. In the post he talks about how he removed distractions by removing social media apps such as Twitter and Facebook from his iPhone. He’s done other things too such as reading a book instead of checking Twitter, and he started a “No Technology Day” on Saturdays, which is something I think I might start doing as well.</p>

<p>Over the last year I too have been eliminating distractions in my life by spending more of my time <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing what I love</a> and changing the way I use social networks. Changing the way I use social networks is one of the reasons I wrote my app <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/cross-post">Cross Post</a>. With Cross Post I can share pictures, thoughts, and comments on Facebook, Twitter, and App.net without the worry of being distracted by those sites. Cross Post sends updates to social media sites, but it does not read the time lines or streams from those sites. Cross Post is a tool for making, not reading, micro-blog posts, hence it’s ability to help eliminate distractions.</p>

<p>I did one other thing to help me eliminate distractions. I turned off notifications on all but the most important apps on my iPhone<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>. Unlike Dan I did not remove the social media apps from my phone. I still want to be able to reply to mentions via my iPhone, which is why I left the apps installed. And in the case of Facebook, it’s the easiest way for me to get news about my family via my sister down in Mississippi, so I still check Facebook once or twice a day. But I do not receive notifications from any of the social media apps on my phone.</p>

<p>So how can you start eliminating distractions in your life. I suggest starting with Dan’s new website, <a href="http://thegreatdisconnect.info">The Great Disconnect</a>. It contains articles, videos and information about how to remove distractions by living a less connected life. Check it out because we all can benefit from being a bit less connected these days.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Examples of app that are important to me and which I still have notifications turned on are ones for my bank and credit cards. I want to make sure I’m alerted if a fraudulent charge is ever made against one of my accounts. Slack is another app that I use with notifications turned on since I use this for work purposes. Beyond that, I have notifications turned off. Oh, and in case you were wondering, I let sites like Twitter notify me of mentions via email, and I only check email a few times a day. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Tradition Comes To A Close Tonight]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/22/a-tradition-comes-to-a-close-tonight/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/22/a-tradition-comes-to-a-close-tonight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On December 22, 2001, I was in Whistler with my friends Dave and Joe. We spent the day snowboarding, then that night we went to see the first Lord of the Rings movie. Little did I know that night would become a tradition of sorts for me.</p>

<p>On December 22, 2002, I repeated the previous year by snowboarding, though not at Whistler, during the day and went to see the second LOTR movie that night. And yep, I did it again December 22, 2003. My wife, who joined me for the second and third movies, was glad the trilogy was over. Snowboarding a full day then going to a long movie that evening made for a long day. But then The Hobbit came out so…</p>

<p>On December 22, 2012, the tradition resumed with a full day of snowboarding followed by watching first hobbit movie. And one year later, December 22, 2013, was another long day of snowboarding and hobbits.</p>

<p>And this brings us to today, December 22, 2014. I spent the day snowboarding and tonight I will go see The Hobbit: The Battle of the Five Armies. The tradition continues for one more day, but unless there are more hobbit movies hitting movie theaters in the future, this tradition comes to a close tonight.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Organizing Events]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/06/not-organizing-events/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/06/not-organizing-events</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I lived in NYC I organized and ran events for computer geeks like me. It was a lot of fun, and a great way to meet new people. Then I moved to Salem, Mass, a suburb of Boston, and again I organized and ran events in Salem and Boston. And again it was a lot of fun and a great way to meet new people.</p>

<p>I now live in Stowe, Vermont, and as of right now I have zero desire to organize and run events for like-minded computer nerds. After being so involved organizing meetups and such for over 10 years, it’s nice to take a break. That said, I sometimes wish someone had a tech-focused garthering in Stowe. I wonder how long before I end up organizing something.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>