<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: conference | thecave | Kirby Turner's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/conference/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-01-03T18:45:23+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Upcoming Share Extension Talk At 360idev-Min]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/07/my-upcoming-share-extension-talk-at-360idev-min/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-07T15:37:39+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/09/07/my-upcoming-share-extension-talk-at-360idev-min</id>
    <tag>conference</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I’m excited to be one of the speakers at the upcoming <a href="http://min.360idev.com">360idev-min</a> conference in Greenville, SC. In my talk I’ll share the things you need to know about when writing a share extension for your iOS app.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m excited to be one of the speakers at the upcoming <a href="http://min.360idev.com">360idev-min</a> conference in Greenville, SC. In my talk I’ll share the things you need to know about when writing a share extension for your iOS app.</p>

<p>If you plan to attend <a href="http://min.360idev.com">360idev-min</a>, then use the coupon code <strong>SpeakerFriend</strong> to save $100 when purchasing your ticket.</p>

<p>And let me know if you are attending so we can meet up in person.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No WWDC Or SF Trip]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-14T13:20:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/14/no-wwdc-or-sf-trip</id>
    <tag>conference</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Apple announced the dates for this year’s WWDC, and once again a lottery is being used to decide who gets to buy a ticket. I have no interesting is attending WWDC other than to attend the labs since I do have questions I would love to ask an Apple engineer. But it’s not worth spending $1599 on a ticket just for that.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple announced the dates for this year’s WWDC, and once again a lottery is being used to decide who gets to buy a ticket. I have no interesting is attending WWDC other than to attend the labs since I do have questions I would love to ask an Apple engineer. But it’s not worth spending $1599 on a ticket just for that.</p>

<p>Likewise, I’m struggling to justify spending the money to stay in San Francisco the week of WWDC just to hang out with friends and drink beer. Certainly reconnecting with friends and making news ones is very enjoyable, but there are cheaper ways for me to do that. So I’ve decided I’m not going to SF for this year’s WWDC.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone 6 Plus Is Too Big For Me, But I Bought It Anyways]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/10/13/iphone-6-plus-is-too-big-for-me-but-i-bought-it-anyways/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/10/13/iphone-6-plus-is-too-big-for-me-but-i-bought-it-anyways</id>
    <tag>conference</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks back I said I would be buying the <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/10/iphone-6-plus-pocket-test/">iPhone 6</a>, not the 6 Plus. The 6 Plus is simply too large for me. But I have since changed my mind.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks back I said I would be buying the <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/10/iphone-6-plus-pocket-test/">iPhone 6</a>, not the 6 Plus. The 6 Plus is simply too large for me. But I have since changed my mind.</p>

<p>There are a few reasons I changed my mind. First and foremost, I could not justify upgrading from the iPhone 5 to iPhone 6. It’s just a hardware upgrade, and I’m very happy with my iPhone 5. Sure, it would be nice having a device with TouchID but that’s not a must have feature for me. And a better camera would also be nice, but again it’s not totally necessary for me.</p>

<p>I actually started the process of ordering the iPhone 6 on two separate occasions this past week, and each time I stopped before completing the order. There simply weren’t any good reasons for me to upgrade my phone other than to keep the end date for my 2-year contract with Verizon in the month of October. But the same is not true for the iPhone 6 Plus.</p>

<h2 id="different-size-classes">Different Size Classes</h2>

<p>The iPhone 6 Plus has features not available on the 6, features that, as a developer, I need to support in the apps I write. And while I can use the iOS Simulator to test those features, I’m a firm believer that testing on an actual device is far better. Testing on a device gives you a real sense for how your app feels on that device, and that’s why I own a number of iOS devices. The Simulator is great for quick debugging and testings, but nothing beats playing with your app on an actual device.</p>

<p>The iPhone 6 Plus supports different size classes than the iPhone 6 and earlier iPhones. This means, for example, in landscape mode the iPhone 6 Plus can take advantage of displaying a split view controller, which is something the iPhone 6 does not. And again, while I can test this using the Simulator I won’t get a true feel for the differences without using an actual device. But this alone wasn’t the only reason I changed my mind on which device I should buy.</p>

<h2 id="the-pocket-test">The Pocket Test</h2>

<p>Over the weekend, while attending <a href="http://cingleton.com">Çingleton</a>, I did a number of pocket tests using various iPhone 6 Plus devices. Some had cases, others did not. What I found was that while I notice the iPhone 6 Plus in my pocket, it wasn’t as uncomfortable as I thought it would be. Does it feel as nice in my pocket as the iPhone 5 or even the 4s? Certainly not. And there will still be times when I’m annoyed at the size of the 6 Plus when carrying it in my pocket, such as when I’m snowboarding. In fact, I’ll likely have to carry the 6 Plus in my jacket pocket when snowboarding instead of my front pants pocket. And I’m not thrilled about carrying the larger device in a cargo pocket when I’m hiking as it will be banging against my leg as I walk.</p>

<p>But as I thought about it more I realized that I don’t keep my iPhone 5 in my pocket all that much. I work from home and the majority of the time my iPhone is sitting on my desk. I do put it in my pocket when I leave the house, but typically I’m at home more than not.</p>

<p>Still, after a weekend of various pocket tests I wasn’t completely sold on the iPhone 6 Plus. I certainly was leaning towards buying it, but I was still on the fence. That was until I learned about the zoom view.</p>

<h2 id="zoom-view">Zoom View</h2>

<p>With the zoom view an iPhone 6 Plus behaves like an iPhone 6. For instance, when the zoom view is enabled the home screen does not rotate when the iPhone 6 Plus is in landscape mode. In fact, it appears that the size classes used on the iPhone 6 Plus are the same as the iPhone 6 when using zoom mode. This means that the iPhone 6 Plus can be used to test the behavior of your app as if it were running on an iPhone 6. And that sealed the deal for me.</p>

<p>Using the iPhone 6 Plus to test my apps is like having two devices in one. I can test my apps to make sure the user experience is perfect for iPhone 6 Plus users and, thanks to the zoom view, iPhone 6 users. At this point the decision to buy an iPhone 6 Plus became a no brainer for me.</p>

<h2 id="not-a-developer">Not a Developer</h2>

<p>Would I buy an iPhone 6 Plus if I weren’t a developer? Nope, I would not. In fact I would not buy the iPhone 6 either, at least not right now. My iPhone 5 suits me well, and I would have no good reason to upgrade if I weren’t a developer.</p>

<h2 id="what-i-really-want">What I Really Want</h2>

<p>What I really want isn’t the iPhone 6 Plus, but what I want does not exists, at least not yet.</p>

<p>As a developer what I really want is an iPod touch Plus. If Apple were selling an iPod touch Plus that is the same as the iPhone 6 Plus minus the phone, then I would buy it in an instant. That way I could continue using my iPhone 5 as my primary phone device and the iPod touch Plus as a test device. And my son would be happy too because in his mind the iPod touch Plus would be his even though I would use it for testing purposes. But sadly there is no such thing as an iPod touch Plus right now.</p>

<h2 id="change-my-mind-again">Change My Mind Again</h2>

<p>So there you have it…the reasons I changed my mind.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Different size classes and UI behaviors.</li>
  <li>Not as uncomfortable in my pocket as I thought it would be.</li>
  <li>Able to test iPhone 6 and 6 Plus user experience from the same device.</li>
  <li>No iPod touch Plus.</li>
</ol>

<p>There’s actually one more reason that led to me changing my mind, Apple’s return policy. If after the first week of owning an iPhone 6 Plus I find that carrying it around in my pocket too annoying then I can return the device. I doubt I will return it especially after talking with many iPhone 6 Plus owners at Çingleton this past weekend, but still, there is always a chance I will change my mind again.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Software Industry Conference 2008]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2008/07/20/my-first-software-industry-conference-2008/"/>
    <updated>2008-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2008/07/20/my-first-software-industry-conference-2008</id>
    <tag>conference</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I attended my first <a href="http://www.sic.org/">Software Industry Conference</a> this year and overall it was a great experience.  I learned some good tips from the sessions I tended and from the people I met.  I got to meet a number of people who, like me, are indie developers and or run small software companies.  And I got to put faces on names of individuals from the <a href="http://www.asp-shareware.org/">ASP</a> newsgroups and <a href="http://discuss.joelonsoftware.com/?biz">BoS forum</a>. And of course I picked up a couple of new t-shirts too.  Now if vendors exhibiting at conferences like SIC would hand out jeans and boxers I could have a new wardrobe each year.<br /><br />The sessions covered a variety topics related to the business of selling software.  There were sessions on distribution channels, alternative revenue models such as subscriptions and rentals, marketing, web site designs, the impact of social networks and more.  I really liked the variety of topics covered.  However, one thing I did not like was the lack of depth in many of the sessions.<br /><br />Most of the sessions had multiple speakers providing different points of views on a topic.  For example, the session on distribution channels had 3 speakers.  The first speaker talked about breaking into the China marketplace.  The second speaker talked about OEM distribution, and the final speaker talked about distribution through publishers and retail channels.  With this particular topic the three speakers and the different points of view format worked well and was helpful and insightful.  But the multi-speaker approach did not work for all sessions.<br /><br />The session on web site analytics and metrics was one such session that I wish had been broken out into two separate sessions.  The first speaker talked about monitoring your competitors, and the second speaker talked about tools and options for understanding what is happening with your own web site.  What I would have liked to see was more in depth discussions and how tos on the two areas.  For example, the talk about the tools and options for understanding what is happening with your own web site was good but it could have been even better if the speaker had time to drill into a sample web log using a tool of choice and explain in detail how to look for and understand the meaning of the data and how to uncover and find trends within the data.<br /><br />It also felt as if each speaker was rushed to get through the information he or she wanted to share so that there would be enough time for the next speaker within the session.<br /><br />Despite the lack of depth in many of the session talks, the Q&amp;A; that typically followed was great.  In many cases the Q&amp;A; was more useful for me that the actual talk.  <br /><br />Another aspect of SIC that I really like is meeting a wide range of people who, like me, are producing and selling software products.  Not only was it fun to share war stories and talk shop, I also learned a lot from the more seasoned veterans.  For instance, Dan from <a href="http://www.topografix.com/">TopoGrafix</a> gave me some great feedback on my web site and suggested ways to improve my SEO with landing pages covering topics I had not thought of before.  Not only did I learn a thing or two from others, but the conversations I had with various individuals gave me the kick in the ass I needed to re-motivated and come up with fresh, new ideas for growing my company and taking it to the next level.<br /><br />So was the conference worth it?  Absolutely.  Granted my cost was low because the conference was held in the Boston metro area which is local for me and meant I didn’t not have to pay travel experiences (no airfare or hotel).  But I do plan to return next year and I will be staying in the hotel so I can have more fun at the party-like receptions held each evening.</p>
]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I attended my first <a href="http://www.sic.org/">Software Industry Conference</a> this year and overall it was a great experience.  I learned some good tips from the sessions I tended and from the people I met.  I got to meet a number of people who, like me, are indie developers and or run small software companies.  And I got to put faces on names of individuals from the <a href="http://www.asp-shareware.org/">ASP</a> newsgroups and <a href="http://discuss.joelonsoftware.com/?biz">BoS forum</a>. And of course I picked up a couple of new t-shirts too.  Now if vendors exhibiting at conferences like SIC would hand out jeans and boxers I could have a new wardrobe each year.<br /><br />The sessions covered a variety topics related to the business of selling software.  There were sessions on distribution channels, alternative revenue models such as subscriptions and rentals, marketing, web site designs, the impact of social networks and more.  I really liked the variety of topics covered.  However, one thing I did not like was the lack of depth in many of the sessions.<br /><br />Most of the sessions had multiple speakers providing different points of views on a topic.  For example, the session on distribution channels had 3 speakers.  The first speaker talked about breaking into the China marketplace.  The second speaker talked about OEM distribution, and the final speaker talked about distribution through publishers and retail channels.  With this particular topic the three speakers and the different points of view format worked well and was helpful and insightful.  But the multi-speaker approach did not work for all sessions.<br /><br />The session on web site analytics and metrics was one such session that I wish had been broken out into two separate sessions.  The first speaker talked about monitoring your competitors, and the second speaker talked about tools and options for understanding what is happening with your own web site.  What I would have liked to see was more in depth discussions and how tos on the two areas.  For example, the talk about the tools and options for understanding what is happening with your own web site was good but it could have been even better if the speaker had time to drill into a sample web log using a tool of choice and explain in detail how to look for and understand the meaning of the data and how to uncover and find trends within the data.<br /><br />It also felt as if each speaker was rushed to get through the information he or she wanted to share so that there would be enough time for the next speaker within the session.<br /><br />Despite the lack of depth in many of the session talks, the Q&amp;A; that typically followed was great.  In many cases the Q&amp;A; was more useful for me that the actual talk.  <br /><br />Another aspect of SIC that I really like is meeting a wide range of people who, like me, are producing and selling software products.  Not only was it fun to share war stories and talk shop, I also learned a lot from the more seasoned veterans.  For instance, Dan from <a href="http://www.topografix.com/">TopoGrafix</a> gave me some great feedback on my web site and suggested ways to improve my SEO with landing pages covering topics I had not thought of before.  Not only did I learn a thing or two from others, but the conversations I had with various individuals gave me the kick in the ass I needed to re-motivated and come up with fresh, new ideas for growing my company and taking it to the next level.<br /><br />So was the conference worth it?  Absolutely.  Granted my cost was low because the conference was held in the Boston metro area which is local for me and meant I didn’t not have to pay travel experiences (no airfare or hotel).  But I do plan to return next year and I will be staying in the hotel so I can have more fun at the party-like receptions held each evening.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CodeRage Day 1]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2007/03/12/coderage-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2007/03/12/coderage-day-1</id>
    <tag>conference</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://conferences.codegear.com/coderage07">CodeRage</a> Day 1 is over and overall I thought it was a great day.  Unfortunately Day 1 got off to a rough start.  Bandwidth issues caused video and audio outages throughout the morning but the problems were, for the most part, resolved later into the day.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://conferences.codegear.com/coderage07">CodeRage</a> Day 1 is over and overall I thought it was a great day.  Unfortunately Day 1 got off to a rough start.  Bandwidth issues caused video and audio outages throughout the morning but the problems were, for the most part, resolved later into the day.</p>

<p>The session that excited me the most was the <a href="http://video.codegear.com/coderage/ragingconference.exe/convert?track=&amp;page=allsessions.html#REFNO1270">New VCL for Delphi 2007</a>.  The new features centered around Vista look great and the timing couldn’t be more perfect since <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">White Peak Software</a> has plans to start supporting Vista in new applications very soon.</p>

<p>For those of you who missed today’s session, no worries.  <a href="http://www.codegear.com/">CodeGear</a> has plans to post the recorded sessions.  A few sessions are already posted <a href="http://torrent.codegear.com/coderage/">here</a> including the New VCL for Delphi 2007 session.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>