<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: programming | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-14T20:23:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Made Some Fixes To The Blog Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/28/made-some-fixes-to-the-blog-site/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-28T19:01:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/28/made-some-fixes-to-the-blog-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before doing some work today I decided to make some improvements to my blog site. I thought I would be playing with the site for only an hour or so, but instead it took most of the day. Typical when dealing with programming issues in an unfamiliar environment. </p>

<p>This site, as well as <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com">my company blog site</a>, uses <a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> to generate a static HTML version of the site that is in turned hosted on a server for your viewing pleasure. I noticed a while back that categories with embedded spaces, such as <em>cross post</em>, weren’t accessible from the categories list. The embedded space was being replaced with a dash. Also, the RSS feed was not including the time of the post, only the date. So I set out to fix these problems.</p>

<p>I started with the time problem first. I learned that Jekyll does not include the time of the post unless you include the <code>date</code> parameter in the front matter. Adding the parameter is easy enough to do, but I decided I wanted to make it even easier for me. So I created a Rakefile that has a <code>new_post</code> task. I could have used an existing Rakefile, maybe even the one from Octopress, but I decided it would be more fun to write my own. Turns out writing a Rakefile is pretty simple, and I had my <code>new_post</code> task working quickly. </p>

<p>The <code>new_post</code> task I wrote create a new markdown file for the post. The task also generates the YAML front matter for the post including the <code>date</code> parameter with the current local time. This solves my time problem in the RSS feed for new post. I thought about making a fix for older post, but I decided it wasn’t worth the effort.</p>

<p>Using the Rakefile to create a new post makes so much sense that I decided to add a <code>deploy</code> task the Rakefile. I’ve been using a shell script I wrote a few years ago to generate the Jekyll site then commit it to the <em>gh-pages</em> branch of the site’s git <a href="https://github.com/kirbyt/site-www-thecave-com">repo</a>. I thought it would be a fun exercise to re-implement this in the Rakefile. At the same time I decided to change how the files are committed to the branch. Instead of working from a single local git repo, I decided to clone the repo to a second <em>_deploy</em> directory, then copy the <em>_site</em> files to that directory. Turns out this was fairly simple to do as well. </p>

<p>With that work out of the way I turned my focus to the categories name problem. Turns out it was caused by a space replacement in the Jekyll plugin I use to generate the categories list. That was the easiest, fastest fix of the day.</p>

<p>With a smile on my face and feeling of success I decided to do one more thing. I decided to update my install of Jekyll. And this is when everything fell apart. The sense of success and feeling of being productive evaporated quickly. Long story short, turns out I had rvm and rbenv installed at the same time, and apparently having both installed at the same time causes problems when updating gems. Unfortunately it took me a long while to figure out what had happened. I didn’t realize rvm was installed, but once I did I uninstalled it. I did another update and made sure I had rbenv-gem-rehash installed. </p>

<p>All is well now. In fact, the only reason I’m writing this post is to make sure everything is working as expected. And now that I have a faster way to create new posts, I’m hoping to post here more frequently. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iPhone 6 Plus Is Too Big For Me, But I Bought It Anyways]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/10/13/iphone-6-plus-is-too-big-for-me-but-i-bought-it-anyways/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/10/13/iphone-6-plus-is-too-big-for-me-but-i-bought-it-anyways</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks back I said I would be buying the <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/10/iphone-6-plus-pocket-test/">iPhone 6</a>, not the 6 Plus. The 6 Plus is simply too large for me. But I have since changed my mind.</p>

<p>There are a few reasons I changed my mind. First and foremost, I could not justify upgrading from the iPhone 5 to iPhone 6. It’s just a hardware upgrade, and I’m very happy with my iPhone 5. Sure, it would be nice having a device with TouchID but that’s not a must have feature for me. And a better camera would also be nice, but again it’s not totally necessary for me.</p>

<p>I actually started the process of ordering the iPhone 6 on two separate occasions this past week, and each time I stopped before completing the order. There simply weren’t any good reasons for me to upgrade my phone other than to keep the end date for my 2-year contract with Verizon in the month of October. But the same is not true for the iPhone 6 Plus.</p>

<h2 id="different-size-classes">Different Size Classes</h2>

<p>The iPhone 6 Plus has features not available on the 6, features that, as a developer, I need to support in the apps I write. And while I can use the iOS Simulator to test those features, I’m a firm believer that testing on an actual device is far better. Testing on a device gives you a real sense for how your app feels on that device, and that’s why I own a number of iOS devices. The Simulator is great for quick debugging and testings, but nothing beats playing with your app on an actual device.</p>

<p>The iPhone 6 Plus supports different size classes than the iPhone 6 and earlier iPhones. This means, for example, in landscape mode the iPhone 6 Plus can take advantage of displaying a split view controller, which is something the iPhone 6 does not. And again, while I can test this using the Simulator I won’t get a true feel for the differences without using an actual device. But this alone wasn’t the only reason I changed my mind on which device I should buy.</p>

<h2 id="the-pocket-test">The Pocket Test</h2>

<p>Over the weekend, while attending <a href="http://cingleton.com">Çingleton</a>, I did a number of pocket tests using various iPhone 6 Plus devices. Some had cases, others did not. What I found was that while I notice the iPhone 6 Plus in my pocket, it wasn’t as uncomfortable as I thought it would be. Does it feel as nice in my pocket as the iPhone 5 or even the 4s? Certainly not. And there will still be times when I’m annoyed at the size of the 6 Plus when carrying it in my pocket, such as when I’m snowboarding. In fact, I’ll likely have to carry the 6 Plus in my jacket pocket when snowboarding instead of my front pants pocket. And I’m not thrilled about carrying the larger device in a cargo pocket when I’m hiking as it will be banging against my leg as I walk.</p>

<p>But as I thought about it more I realized that I don’t keep my iPhone 5 in my pocket all that much. I work from home and the majority of the time my iPhone is sitting on my desk. I do put it in my pocket when I leave the house, but typically I’m at home more than not.</p>

<p>Still, after a weekend of various pocket tests I wasn’t completely sold on the iPhone 6 Plus. I certainly was leaning towards buying it, but I was still on the fence. That was until I learned about the zoom view.</p>

<h2 id="zoom-view">Zoom View</h2>

<p>With the zoom view an iPhone 6 Plus behaves like an iPhone 6. For instance, when the zoom view is enabled the home screen does not rotate when the iPhone 6 Plus is in landscape mode. In fact, it appears that the size classes used on the iPhone 6 Plus are the same as the iPhone 6 when using zoom mode. This means that the iPhone 6 Plus can be used to test the behavior of your app as if it were running on an iPhone 6. And that sealed the deal for me.</p>

<p>Using the iPhone 6 Plus to test my apps is like having two devices in one. I can test my apps to make sure the user experience is perfect for iPhone 6 Plus users and, thanks to the zoom view, iPhone 6 users. At this point the decision to buy an iPhone 6 Plus became a no brainer for me.</p>

<h2 id="not-a-developer">Not a Developer</h2>

<p>Would I buy an iPhone 6 Plus if I weren’t a developer? Nope, I would not. In fact I would not buy the iPhone 6 either, at least not right now. My iPhone 5 suits me well, and I would have no good reason to upgrade if I weren’t a developer.</p>

<h2 id="what-i-really-want">What I Really Want</h2>

<p>What I really want isn’t the iPhone 6 Plus, but what I want does not exists, at least not yet.</p>

<p>As a developer what I really want is an iPod touch Plus. If Apple were selling an iPod touch Plus that is the same as the iPhone 6 Plus minus the phone, then I would buy it in an instant. That way I could continue using my iPhone 5 as my primary phone device and the iPod touch Plus as a test device. And my son would be happy too because in his mind the iPod touch Plus would be his even though I would use it for testing purposes. But sadly there is no such thing as an iPod touch Plus right now.</p>

<h2 id="change-my-mind-again">Change My Mind Again</h2>

<p>So there you have it…the reasons I changed my mind.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Different size classes and UI behaviors.</li>
  <li>Not as uncomfortable in my pocket as I thought it would be.</li>
  <li>Able to test iPhone 6 and 6 Plus user experience from the same device.</li>
  <li>No iPod touch Plus.</li>
</ol>

<p>There’s actually one more reason that led to me changing my mind, Apple’s return policy. If after the first week of owning an iPhone 6 Plus I find that carrying it around in my pocket too annoying then I can return the device. I doubt I will return it especially after talking with many iPhone 6 Plus owners at Çingleton this past weekend, but still, there is always a chance I will change my mind again.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microblogging, the Open Web, and Cross Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/10/09/microblogging-the-open-web-and-cross-post/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/10/09/microblogging-the-open-web-and-cross-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently Manton Reece has been talking a lot about <a href="http://www.manton.org/tag/microblogging">microblogging</a> in an open web world using <a href="http://www.manton.org/tag/rss">RSS</a>. He has touched on points that are important to me, specifically content ownership. Like many people I post regularly to App.net, Facebook, Twitter, and other social networks, but I’ve always had one big problem with these networks. My micro-posts do not appear on my web site, and if these networks were to disappear in the future, then my content disappears too.</p>

<h2 id="a-bit-of-history">A Bit of History</h2>

<p>I started thecave.com back in 1997. It was called “The Programmer’s Hideout” and I published various programming how-to articles for SQL Server, Delphi, and other tech that was interesting to me at the time. What I didn’t know at the time was that I was blogging. It wasn’t called blogging in 1997, but that’s exactly what I was doing. It wasn’t until March 2002 that thecave.com became what is typically known today as a blog site.</p>

<p>thecave.com has changed a lot under the hood. In the beginning I used a blogging engine that I wrote. I later switched to a hybrid engine using blogger.com as my editor. Blogger would upload an XML version of the post to my server that my blogging engine would consume and publish the website. As time went on I would used other blogging engines including Wordpress for thecave.com. Today thecave.com is a static HTML website generated by Jekyll. Despite all the changes under the hood, <a href="http://www.thecave.com/blog/archives/">every post</a> I have made to thecave.com since March 2002 is still available today<sup id="fnref:oldposts"><a href="#fn:oldposts" class="footnote">1</a></sup>. I own and control the content, and it is not going away.</p>

<p>This isn’t true for my Facebook or Twitter posts. They control the content, content that could disappear in the future. That is why Manton’s thoughts on microblogging in an open web environment has piqued my interest. I want to take back control of my content including my micro-posts, but how do I do this? As luck would have it, Manton suggested a possible solution for me that fits in nicely with Cross Post, the app I’m currently working, and his suggestion is changing the way I think of Cross Post<sup id="fnref:manton"><a href="#fn:manton" class="footnote">2</a></sup>.</p>

<h2 id="the-suggestion">The Suggestion</h2>

<p>Cross Post is designed to make it easy to share your status and photos across multiple social networks. In other words, Cross Post is a microblog app that lets you post to one or more social networks. Manton’s suggested to me that I add RSS support to Cross Post. It took a while for his suggestion to sink in, but when it did turn on I was like “Oh shit! I want that!”</p>

<p>Cross Post lets me post updates to App.net, Facebook, and Twitter so friends and family can read about me drinking beer, snowboarding, and doing other boring things. But more importantly it can be updated to give me the option to store my content in a location that I have complete control of. Cross Post then becomes an app for microblogging that not only publishes content to multiple networks, it stores your post in a place that you have complete control over and ownership of. And RSS is the perfect solution for this.</p>

<p>When I first heard Manton’s suggestion of adding RSS support to Cross Post, my thinking was that Cross Post would host the RSS feed on its own server. But this is not as simple as it sounds. This requires me to implement some type of user management system. Also since the Cross Post server would be hosting the content, I would have to implement features to allow a person to edit and remove posts. And then there is the hosting cost for hosting all the photos that a person can include with each post. But beyond that, you as the user of Cross Post would not have complete control over the content. It would be hosted on the Cross Post server, and if Cross Post were to ever disappear, then so would your content. In other words letting Cross Post host your content is no better than using App.net or Twitter. But I didn’t give up on the idea of using RSS in Cross Post.</p>

<p>Content ownership is what is important to me, and I knew there had to be a way to make this work. So my next thought was to have Cross Post support different blogging engines. Instead of just posting to social networks, Cross Post could upload your post to your web site directly. But that’s no easy task. What you are talking here is a microblogging version of <a href="http://www.red-sweater.com/marsedit/">MarsEdit</a>, which is not something I care to write. Besides, a microblogging MarsEdit wouldn’t help me get my post into thecave.com because only static HTML is hosted. What Cross Post needs to do is post the content somewhere available on the Internet, but it has to be a location that the person has complete control. That’s when it hit me. Dropbox.</p>

<h2 id="host-on-dropbox">Host on Dropbox</h2>

<p>Cross Post can post the content to your Dropbox (or similar service), and with syncing you will have a copy of your content for as long as you like. Even if Facebook or Twitter disappears, you would still have a copy of your post. And using RSS to store the content lets you do all sorts of things, from syndicating the post to other services to displaying the content in your own website to letting family and friends read you micro-post via an RSS reader.</p>

<h2 id="but-how">But How</h2>

<p>Here’s my current thinking of how it would work:</p>

<p>Using Cross Post, the person grants the app access to Dropbox (Google Drive, SFTP, whatever). When the person makes a post, Cross Post will append it to two feed files, full.rss and recent.rss. Full would contain all micro-posts ever made through the app. Recent would be the last n number of posts where “n” is set by the person (i.e., 5, 10, 20, etc). And if the post includes a photo, then the photo is uploaded to a subdirectory and the appropriate link is added to the entry in the feed file. If the person wishes to publish the feed to a service or let others consume the feed, then the Dropbox public link to the RSS feed file can be used.</p>

<p>The beauty of this approach is that the person has full control over the microblog content and that content is synced to their computer. Even if Cross Post disappears, the content does not. And for oddballs like me, I can integrated the microblog content into my static HTML site just by adding a plugin to Jekyll that consumes the RSS feed and generates a markdown file for each new post before generating the complete site. Heck, I can automate this to have my website updated in near-real time each time I make a new post via Cross Post.</p>

<p>So that’s my thinking, at a high level, for adding RSS support to Cross Post. This feature will not be in the first release of Cross Post. My first goal is to stabilize and ship the current version of the app. Once that happens I’ll focus on adding RSS support.</p>

<p>Whadda think? Is RSS support something that interest you? Let me know on App.net or Twitter.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:oldposts">
      <p>I still have the content from thecave.com pre-March 2002, but it’s not published on the Internet anymore. <a href="#fnref:oldposts" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:manton">
      <p>That Manton is a smart guy. <a href="#fnref:manton" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using xcodebuild To Export a .ipa From an Archive]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/16/using-xcodebuild-to-export-a-ipa-from-an-archive/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/16/using-xcodebuild-to-export-a-ipa-from-an-archive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Xcode 6 changes how you export a .ipa from an archive for adhoc distribution. It used to be that you could export the archive to a .ipa as long as you had the right provisioning profile and distribution certificate on your machine. Starting with Xcode 6 you need to be a team member of the particular Developer Program account and you need to have the rights to make a distribution build. This means you need to be a team agent. However, I work with a number of clients who don’t have the clue what Xcode is much less are willing to make distribution builds, so I need to way to make distribution builds within this new limitation from Xcode 6.</p>

<p>Making distribution builds hasn’t been a problem for me in the past. I ask the client to provide me<sup id="fnref:ask"><a href="#fn:ask" class="footnote">1</a></sup> with the necessary provisioning profile, distribution certificate, and public private key pair so I can make the distribution build for them. Then I use Xcode Organizer to export the archive to a .ipa that I can distribute.<sup id="fnref:host"><a href="#fn:host" class="footnote">2</a></sup> But it seems I can no longer export using Organizer without having the right team access, so I had to search out an alternative approach.</p>

<p>Turns out starting with Xcode 5, <em>xcodebuild</em> includes parameters for exporting from an archive. This is exactly what I need so I can continue making adhoc distribution builds for clients without being a team member or team agent under their Developer Program account.</p>

<p>So how do I do it?</p>

<h3 id="the-how-to">The How To</h3>

<p>My build script starts by performing a clean.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>xcodebuild clean -project $projectname.xcodeproj -configuration Release -alltargets</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Then the script builds and archives the app. I specify the archive path using the <em>-archivePath</em> parameter in the command line so the script will know where the archive file is located.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>xcodebuild archive -project $projectname.xcodeproj -scheme $schemename -archivePath $projectname.xcarchive</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Finally my script exports the archive into a .ipa file.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>xcodebuild -exportArchive -archivePath $projectname.xcarchive -exportPath $projectname -exportFormat ipa -exportProvisioningProfile “Provisioning Profile Name”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I let the provisioning profile imply the signing identity, but you can specify the signing identity using the <em>-exportSigningIdentity</em> parameter.</p>

<h3 id="the-gotcha">The Gotcha</h3>

<p>The one major gotcha that cost me a more than an hour of time was figuring out the parameter value for <em>-exportProvisioningProfile</em>. I initial thought it should be the file name to the provisioning profile. I tried it with and without the <em>.mobileprovision</em> file extension, but it did not work. I included a relative path as well as an absolute path to the provision profile. I tried using the UUID for the provision profile instead of the file name. I even I tried not including a path at all thinking it would look up the provision profile in the <em>~/Library/MobileDevice/Provisioning Profiles/</em> directory, but still no luck.</p>

<p>Turns out I needed to specify the name of the provisioning profile as defined in the file itself. This is the same name assigned to the profile in the provisioning portal. Once I figured this out I was able to export the .ipa from the archive using the my build script, and I don’t have to be a team agent under my client’s Developer Program account to make the distribution build.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:ask">
      <p>I usually assist my clients with this by guiding them through the steps, or I ask them to give me the account credentials with a temporary password so I can perform the necessary steps. Then I have the client reset the password. <a href="#fnref:ask" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:host">
      <p>I don’t export when I host the test app on <a href="http://hockeyapp.net/">HockeyApp</a>. It takes care of exporting the .ipa from the archive for you. I only export when the client requests that the test app be hosted on their own server.) <a href="#fnref:host" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reporting Errors in Cross Post Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/15/reporting-errors-in-cross-post-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/15/reporting-errors-in-cross-post-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I talked about <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/09/14/reporting-errors-in-cross-post/">options for reporting errors</a> (and statuses) from the server back to the Cross Post app. Later I came up with a third option, which I like the best…hosting the error reports on <a href="http://www.rackspace.com/cloud/files/">Cloud Files</a>.</p>

<p>The Cross Post server is scalable, which means I cannot rely on the server’s file system. Data on the file system for one server is not synced to the other servers, and it’s possible that the server reporting the error is not the same server as the one that caught the error.</p>

<p>The obvious solution is to use a database server, but using a database server is overkill for Cross Post. But as I thought about it more I realized I all I need is a scalable file system, and that’s exactly what cloud storage systems like <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/s3/">S3</a> and <a href="http://www.rackspace.com/cloud/files/">Cloud Files</a> do. They provide a scalable file storage system.</p>

<p>I came to this realization while thinking about how a CMS in a scalable environment might store uploaded files. Uploaded files would likely be stored on a scalable file storage system like S3. And that’s exactly what I need for reporting errors, a scalable file system. As I keep saying, a database is overkill for the current needs of Cross Post.</p>

<h2 id="cloud-files">Cloud Files</h2>

<p>So why Cloud Files instead of S3? Two reasons. 1) I already use Cloud Files as my CDN for my websites. And 2) the price. I don’t expect to have a lot of error reports, and once the error has been reported to the app the report is deleted, so I estimate my total storage cost will be pennies.</p>

<p>A GB of Cloud Files storage is only 10 cents a month, and bandwidth is only 12 cents per GB per month. The total space needed for my error reports will certainly be less than a GB each month, so my estimated cost is only 22 cents per month, well within an affordable range for a snowboard bum like me.</p>

<h2 id="the-how-tos">The How Tos</h2>

<p>So exactly how will this work? Cross Post sends a payload to the server. Once the server receives the payload the HTTP connection ends. The server then processes the payload posting the status update and photos to the selected social networks.</p>

<p>If an error occurs while posting to a social network, it is captured and stored in a JSON file. The file name is the unique id generated by the Cross Post app when packaging up the payload. The server will then take the JSON file and post it to Cloud Files. The next time the Cross Post app is launched, it will check Cloud Files to see if an error report exists. If it does, then the app will report the error to the user, and it will send a request to the Cross Post server telling it to delete the error report from Cloud Files<sup id="fnref:deletefile"><a href="#fn:deletefile" class="footnote">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>So what happens if an error occurred and the person never launches Cross Post ever again? For starters I’ll be sad, but with regards to the error report I can set an expiration date on the file, say 30 days. Cloud Files will take care of deleting the file when it expires. This means less work for my server and less code for me to write.</p>

<h2 id="not-just-for-errors">Not Just For Errors</h2>

<p>What I like about the approach is that it is not limited to reporting errors. I can use this approach to report any status back to the app, though at the moment the only status type I need to report is an error status. I subscribe to the “no news is good news” mindset meaning that once the server receives the payload, unless an error is reported, it’s safe to assume the post was sent to the different social networks without a problem.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:deletefile">
      <p>I let the Cross Post server delete the file from Cloud Files CDN so I don’t have to include the api key in the iOS app. <a href="#fnref:deletefile" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>