<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: stowe | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/stowe/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-03T21:27:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Temperature Inversion]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/temperature-inversion/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-17T11:24:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/temperature-inversion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seeing “temperature inversion” in the Stowe snow report this morning is music to my ears. It’s -20°F in town but a balmy 2°F at the summit. Time to ride. </p>

<p>Speaking of odd temperatures…Whistler Village is 50°F warmer than the Village of Stowe this morning. I’m starting to think our Whistler winter vacation next week will feel more like a spring break vacation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Local Retail Stores, Update Your Website]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-04T13:08:21-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/04/hey-local-retail-stores-update-your-website</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought a new Burton snowboard the other day. I ordered it online from a mom and pop shop in the Oregon. I wanted to buy locally here in Stowe but the price I paid was 10% cheaper than the price listed on the websites of local shops. Combined with the fact that I didn’t have to pay sales tax and shipping was free, I felt I was getting a great deal. Still, I would have preferred to support a local shop here in Vermont, but at least I supported a local shop in Oregon. </p>

<p>All good, right? Well…</p>

<p>My wife stopped by one of the local Stowe shops today to buy a pair of new skis. Turns out the shop has a sale going on…20% off all Burton boards! Turns out if I had bought my new board locally I would have saved more money than buying online. Plus I would have my board now instead of waiting until next week. </p>

<p>So why didn’t I buy locally given that the sale is going on? It’s because I didn’t know about the sale. Being the type of person I am, I check online before going into brick and mortar stores, and I checked the websites of the local Stowe shops before looking elsewhere. But the shop having the awesome sale did not advise the sale on their website. And because they didn’t advise the sale I ended up taking my business elsewhere.</p>

<p>What could this store have done to win my business? They could have shown the sale price on their website. And if they didn’t want to offer the sale price for online orders, then they could have advised the sale on the front page of their website. Something as simple as “20% Off All Snowboards” for in-store purchases only would have brought me into the store two days ago. And since they have the snowboard I want in stock, it would have been an easy sell. I would have been in and out of the store in under 10 minutes, and they would have a few hundred more dollars in the cash register.</p>

<p>Still, I’m happy with my purchase. With my online purchase I was able to support a locally owned, small business…granted in Oregon instead of Vermont, but that’s still better than buying from a big corporate retail chain. And while I spent more money with my online order, it was only $32 more than I would have paid locally when you add sales tax. So I didn’t lose out too much. The Stowe shop, and the state of Vermont for that matter, lost out more than I did and all because the shop didn’t update their website.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/27/finally/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-27T13:54:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/27/finally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Northeast has been getting slammed with a major snow storm, but unfortunately Stowe, Vermont, is too far northwest to get the full force of the storm. I had hoped for a bit of new snow overnight, but it didn’t happen. So I waited before hitting the slopes this morning in hopes the edge of the storm would inch its way into the Stowe, but it didn’t happen. So Melanie and I hit the slopes anyways, braving the -26 degrees Fahrenheit wind chill. We got in two runs before deciding today would be a good day for a lunch date. So we left the hill, and headed for lunch in town. And then the snow finally came…guess I’ll be hitting the hill first thing tomorrow morning. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Despite A Rainy Start]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/28/despite-a-rainy-start/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/28/despite-a-rainy-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite a rainy start this morning, I was able to get in a few snowboard runs on the hill before crowd arrived. And I had great visibility top to bottom on the last two runs. I think that might be the first time this season I’ve had great visibility top to bottom.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still Enjoying the Snow]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/08/still-enjoying-the-snow/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/08/still-enjoying-the-snow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/sets/72157644571329602"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7347/14161061213_f44bfb7073_m.jpg" alt="Top of Nosedive" border="0" width="150" class="alignleft" /></a> I refuse to accept that winter is over. For instance, today I hiked up Mt. Mansfields to do a snowboard run on Nosedive. And based on the crowd, I wasn’t the only one who thought today was a good day for a hike.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/sets/72157644571329602">Here are some pictures</a> from today’s hike.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>