<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: work | thecave | Ramblings from a crotchety old man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-27T14:12:33-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Am Not The Android Expert You Seek]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/08/27/i-am-not-the-android-expert-you-seek/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/08/27/i-am-not-the-android-expert-you-seek</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I do not own an Android device. I have spent less than 2 hours in my entire life playing with an Android device. I’ve never written an app for Android. Heck, I’ve never written a single line of Java code in a shipping app. So, for the love of god, please stop asking me if I can look into problems related to Android and Android apps. I am the last person in the world you want to ask to help you with Android related problems.</p>

<p>Disclaimer: I have nothing against Android. It’s just not an area of interest to me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enjoy Less and Love More]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To some my life seems like a non-stop vacation. I’m a ski bum, a slacker, someone who rarely works. I’m always off on some adventure, snowboarding in the winter months, hiking and kayaking in the summer months. And from one point of view this is true. Over the last 12 months I have spent a great deal of my time snowboarding, hiking and kayaking. But I’ve also been focused on writing code and building apps.</p>

<p>Writing code and building software is a passion of mine. It’s the one thing I’m most passionate about. I’ve been writing code for more than 30 years, and I cannot image doing anything else with my life.</p>

<p>Over the last year I’ve been enjoying my passion more than ever. I’ve written more code in the last year than I did in the previous 3 years combined. I realized just this morning I have worked on and contributed to 22 different apps in the last 12 months, of which 15 are available in the App Store today. That’s a lot of time behind the keyboard.</p>

<p>Business is booming and life is good. So what changed? How is it I can live the ski bum, slacker life and still get a ton of work done? How is it I’m able to work on more apps today compared to a few years ago and still have time for adventure and family? The answer for me was to cut out those things from my life that I enjoy but do not love. (I already cut out those things I hate years ago.)</p>

<p>I stopped writing. I stopped organizing meet ups events. I stopped speaking at conferences. And while I haven’t completely stopped attending conferences and meet up events, I’ve cut way back. In the last 12 months I’ve attended one CocoaHeads event, one conference, and I socialized in San Francisco for only a 3 days during WWDC. This is a big change from just a few years ago when I was writing more words than code, attending and often times speaking at a conference every other month on average, and attending and organizing multiple social gatherings and meet ups each month.</p>

<p>I’ve also made changes to my daily routines. I don’t spend as much time reading news and following the latest happenings on social sites like App.net, Facebook and Twitter. I still make posts to these sites, but I limit the amount of time I spend reading what others have to say. And I’m not as active as I once was in chat rooms and irc. Cutting back on these distractions gives me more time each day to focus on things I love doing.</p>

<p>Some friends and family members have pointed out that I seem happier since moving to Stowe, and they are right. I am happier these days, but it’s not just because I moved to Stowe. It’s because I’m doing more of what I love, and I accomplished this by doing less of what I only enjoy.</p>

<p>By not doing the things I enjoy, I’ve been able to spend more time doing the things I love.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family Influence]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/24/family-influence/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/04/24/family-influence</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over on ADN, Manton Reece <a href="https://alpha.app.net/manton/post/29056754">posted</a> a link to <a href="https://thedistance.com">The Distance</a>, a new online magazine about “long lasting businesses and the people behind them”. Manton’s post included this quote:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Starting a business is the easy part. Staying in business for a while is harder.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This got me thinking about <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">my own business</a>, which has been around for more than ten years. More importantly it got me thinking about the family influences in my life that unbeknownst to me, until recently, led to me working for myself. I have often shared the story about how the <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2013/11/27/woohoo-white-peak-software-is-10-years-old/">idea to start White Peak Software</a> came about, at a swim-up bar during my honeymoon, but I’ve never really talked about the family influences that helped lead me down the path of becoming a business owner. The reason for this is simple. It never occurred to me until recently.</p>

<p>My grandfather (my dad’s dad) was a successful business owner running his own lumber company for many years. My dad owned a general maintenance company. My aunt’s husband (my dad’s sister’s husband) opened <a href="http://www.jamesmiddletonjewelers.com">James Middleton Jewelers</a> back in 1955, and the store is still in business today run by my cousin Vickie.</p>

<p>Entrepreneurship was, and still is, common on my mom’s side of the family as well. My mom and her sisters opened and ran their own hair salon for a short period of time. My mom’s oldest sister’s husband ran his own accounting firm that is still in business today and still run by family members. My mom’s youngest sister, Beth and her husband Jay, owned Gary’s Ice Cream and Deli, the place of my very first “real” job, and later Mikey’s. My sister Renay’s husband has his own pressure washing company, and my grandmother, Dot, made and sold crafts.</p>

<p>I grew up surrounded by family members pursuing their own dreams and making their own destiny. Some were, and still are, successful in their business endeavors while others were not so lucky. But even the unlucky ones tried. They took the chance at running their own business. And all of this has had a huge impact on me even though I did not realized it until recently.</p>

<p>Thank you to all my family members who have influenced me directly and indirectly with their entrepreneur spirit. <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">White Peak Software</a> would not be here, and I would be living the life I live today if not for your influence.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>