<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: work | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-18T12:16:09-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retiring My CSV Editor]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/18/retiring-my-csv-editor/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-18T11:23:09-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/18/retiring-my-csv-editor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I did something that I’ve been saying I will do for a long time. I retired my CSV editor, <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/">Killink</a>. </p>

<p>The first release of Killink CSV Editor was back on March 22, 2007, and over the years it has done well despite the fact that I haven’t been actively working on the app or marketing it. Killink had great potential, especially if I had followed the business advice from those smarter than me to focus on the enterprise, but I honestly lost interest in the editor after I started writing apps for Mac and iOS.</p>

<p>I did start work on a Mac version of Killink CSV Editor, and I have still have a semi-working version of it on my iPhone. But I struggled to create the user experience that I wanted on those two platforms. Given enough time I could have conquered the UX challenges, but I knew the market for the editor was small and spending the extra time to do what I wanted didn’t make good business sense. So the Mac and iOS versions never shipped.</p>

<p>I always found the customers of Killink CSV Editor fascinating. While we developer types view CSV as antiquated technology, these customers work with CSV files regularly. And most are business users from large, well known companies. We developer types often times forget that people around the world are using old technologies like CSV daily to do their job, and they too would like a better way to work with old tech like CSV files. Killink CSV Editor was a better way for many for a number of years.</p>

<p>It saddens me to retire Killink CSV Editor, but at the same time I feel like a burden has been lifted off my shoulders. The app is rock solid and support is minimum, but I have felt guilty for a long time about selling a software product that I know isn’t actively being worked on. And with the recent Windows 10 release, I finally decided now is the time to retire my CSV editor. </p>

<p>I’ve heard many good things about Windows 10. But if I keep selling Killink to Windows users I will have no choice but to install it some day. And honestly, I don’t want to do that. I have zero interest in Windows these days.</p>

<p>I do plan to continuing supporting licensed users of Killink CSV Editor, which I talk about over at the <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2015/08/18/killinks-retirement/">company blog site</a>. The support load is minimum, so providing ongoing support isn’t a concern for me. Killink is a native Win32 app built using Delphi. It’s rock solid and hasn’t had a serious issue that I couldn’t resolve in email in years. So I’m happy to continue answering questions about Killink and helping folks if they happen to run into a problem. That said, I’m not looking forward to the emails I’m going to receive when people try to buy a new license.</p>

<p>When I retired SMTP Diagnostics, another Windows app I sold for years, I received emails for nearly a year asking why it was no longer available and why I couldn’t make an exception this one time and sell a new license. Most of the time the people understood, but a few sent angry emails. I fully expect the same will happen with the retirement of Killink, and all I can say to those folks is sorry.</p>

<p>Retiring my CSV editor ends another chapter in my long software career. I’m a bit sad by this, but I’m also excited by no longer having the mental burden that came with having my editor sit untouched for such a long time while people were still buying licenses for it.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maintain Your iOS App With Peak App Care]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/11/maintain-your-ios-app-with-peak-app-care/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-11T07:05:42-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/11/maintain-your-ios-app-with-peak-app-care</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month I briefly mentioned <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/07/ive-been-doing-it-wrong/">my plan</a> to productize some of the services I offer through White Peak Software. The main idea is to take a consulting service that I already offer to my clients and turn it into a product that my clients and others will hopefully subscribe to thus creating a monthly recurring revenue stream for my company. My goal was to spend no more than 40 hours over the span of a few weeks setting up this new product. And now, after spending 38.75 hours over the last few weeks, I’m ready to share more details.</p>

<p>Today I’m happy to announce <a href="https://www.peakappcare.com">Peak App Care</a>. Peak App Care is a monthly subscription service for maintaining your iOS apps. What do I mean by that? Simply put, I monitor your app for crashes and fix them as quickly as possible. Not only that, I also perform small jobs such as bug fixes and enhancements to your app at your request, and I even manage the App Store for you, from updating screenshots to submitting new builds on your behalf.</p>

<p>What I have found is that many apps available today in the App Store are published by companies with zero iOS developers on staff. Those companies, instead, rely on freelancers and software shops to build their apps for them. The problem, however, is that often times there’s no plans to keep the app up to date after the initial release. </p>

<p>What happens when the app starts crashing or customers start reporting bugs? What happens when Apple releases a new version of iOS or a new device? </p>

<p>Often times these companies must scramble to find an iOS developer to help out. If they are lucky, the original developer is still available but chances are good the developer is currently working on something else and isn’t available for days, weeks, or even months. </p>

<p>With Peak App Care I become your in-house iOS developer responsible for the upkeep of your mobile app. I watch for crashes and fix them as they are reported. But I go beyond that. I will work with you to ensure your app remains up to date with the latest changes coming out of Cupertino. A good example of this is happening right now. </p>

<p>iOS 9 is in beta and every app publisher should be testing their app on this new iOS version. Not only that, the app should be updated to cleanly compile against the iOS 9 SDK. This means replacing deprecated code. But a company with no staffed iOS developer is often times unaware of the need to perform these types of tasks. Or they choose to ignore these tasks. After all, the app is running fine right now, so why wouldn’t it run fine when the new OS comes out. </p>

<p>Sometimes it’s okay to ignore changes coming from Apple, but sometimes the changes are too big to ignore. The iPhone 6 Plus is one example. Customers can quickly tell if an iPhone app doesn’t support the larger display found on the 6 Plus, and the only way to take full advantage of the larger display is to update the app. </p>

<p>This is one area where Peak App Care helps app publishers. Making changes to your app to support the latest iOS release or new device is covered with Peak App Care.</p>

<p>So that’s the new productize service I’m now offering. Check out the new <a href="https://www.peakappcare.com">web site</a>, and tell your friends, family members and anyone else who might be interested. Now let’s chat about how this concept came to be.</p>

<h2 id="giving-credit-where-credit-is-due">Giving Credit Where Credit is Due</h2>

<p>I wish I could take credit for coming up with a totally unique concept, but the truth is a maintenance plan for software isn’t anything new. And providing this type of service for mobile apps isn’t new either. In fact, I got the idea from Einar Vollset. </p>

<p>Einar talks about his app care service in <a href="http://www.freelancetransformation.com/blog/building-a-recurring-revenue-consulting-business-with-einar-vollset">this podcast interview</a> over at <a href="http://www.freelancetransformation.com">Freelance Transformations</a>. This interview blew me away. Here’s a person providing a service that is similar to what I provide, but he came up with a different way to market the service. Brilliant! </p>

<p>But Einar’s <a href="http://www.appaftercare.com">App Aftercare</a> isn’t unique either. There are many other examples of this in different spaces. <a href="http://wpcurve.com">WPCurve</a> provides a similar service for folks running a WordPress site. And I’ve heard of other examples too, companies that will help you maintain your Ruby on Rails app or your Django server. So the concept of app maintenance isn’t new, but I do give credit to Einar Vollset for inspiring me to create <a href="https://www.peakappcare.com">Peak App Care</a>. </p>

<h1 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h1>

<p>So what’s next now that the web site is up and running? Well, it’s time for me to roll up my sleeves and start the real work…marketing Peak App Care. </p>

<p>Like any product I need to market Peak App Care if it is to be a success. My first step is to let my existing clients know about this new offering, which I’ve already done. After that I need to start making others companies within my target audience aware of Peak App Care, and that is where things start to get tougher for me. Just posting a web site isn’t going to bring in customers. I must find ways to reach my target audience, and thankfully I have some ideas on how to make that happen.</p>

<p>As for my company reboot, I feel this is a good first step. I don’t know if Peak App Care will be a success or not. I’m hopeful it will be. But if I fail to bring on new subscribers over the next few months, at least I won’t feel like I have wasted a lot of my time or money. This is a big switch in thinking when I compare it to the months I’ve spent in the past working on other products that either failed or were never even released into the wild.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I've Been Doing It Wrong]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/07/ive-been-doing-it-wrong/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-07T07:22:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/07/ive-been-doing-it-wrong</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few years back I was making the majority of my income from the products I sold. My apps, my book, they were all doing well. But that changed in 2013. Things came crashing down, and I found myself wondering how I was going to pay the bills. </p>

<p>Luckily I have a marketable skill, so I decided to focus on consulting. This was my attempt to reboot my company. The idea was to do consulting work to raise cash, then when I had enough cash I would take time off to work on my business, which in my case meant building another app or two and improving on the ones I already had.</p>

<p>Unfortunately my attempts to reboot didn’t work. Sure, I released two new apps, but once they were out the door my focus returned to billable work. I wasn’t growing and nurturing the products I had. And I wasn’t taking advantage of the momentum I had built up through the end of 2012. I stopped working on my business (again), and things only got worst.</p>

<p>Today I barely make any money off of the products I have. My average monthly product revenue is around $800 per month now, which is better than nothing but certainly not enough to live on. And my attempts to relieve personal stress on the consulting side of has put me into a situation where my hourly bill rate is much lower than it was a few years back.</p>

<p>To get back on track, I started listening to podcasts and reading articles and books about bootstrapping and being an entrepreneur.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup> From reading posts by <a href="https://unicornfree.com">Amy Hoy</a> to watching videos from the <a href="http://appreneursummit.com">Appreneur Summit</a>, I’ve been consuming as much information as possible to figure out 1) how I got myself into this situation, and 2) how I’m going to get myself out of this situation. I’ve even started attending a mastermind group, which gives me an opportunity to talk through issues with my business and bounce around new ideas. But even after doing all this, I wasn’t feeling any better about my situation. In fact, I’ve been toying with the idea of giving up and taking a job elsewhere. But that changed two weeks ago.</p>

<p>Two weeks ago I woke up early one morning and thought, “I’ve been doing it wrong, and I know what I need to do to correct it.” It was as if all the information I consumed about making products and being an entrepreneur had finally mashed together in a way that made sense to my brain and the light bulb finally turned on.</p>

<p>My cycle of doing full-time consulting work followed by taking time off to work on an app or other product doesn’t work for me. That is now so obvious to me. But how do I get out of this cycle and start building up the momentum on the product side again. </p>

<p>The answer was right in front of my face. It’s a common theme in everything I was reading and listening to. And Justin Jackson says it best in his <a href="http://buildandlaunch.net">Build and Launch podcast</a>, “Start small, start now.” </p>

<p>I was using consulting work to save cash so I can take months off at a time to focus on building something. But what I built doesn’t make money. It’s not that the apps I’ve published suck. It’s that once they hit the App Store, my focus returns to consulting work. I’m not sticking with what I started. I’m not marketing the products I have. I’m not doing what I need to do to let more people know about them. </p>

<p>But at the same time I have a wife and a kid that I must provide for and rent and bills to pay. This is why I keep returning to consulting work.</p>

<p>So how do I break this cycle. It’s simple. I need to start small. </p>

<p>Instead of taking two to three months off to write a new app, I need to start creating small, even tiny, products that only take a short amount of time. Once the momentum is going and I have cash coming in from product sales, I can cut back on the consulting. </p>

<p>But what products can I create now, in a short amount of time, that will get the ball rolling. Here’s what I’m currently thinking:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Productize part of the services I offer.</strong> I’ll share more details on this soon, but in general the goal is to take a consulting service I already offer to my clients and turn it into a product that my clients, and hopefully others, will subscribe to. Now this might seem like a huge gamble. I mean after all, generating monthly recurring income is a tough nut to crack. But it’s a small gamble for me in that I will not spend more than 40 hours over the span of a few of weeks getting this setup. If no one subscribes, I’ve only lost a week’s worth of my time. But if just one company signs up, I’m that much closer to getting back on track.</li>
  <li><strong>Start publishing ebooks.</strong> While I don’t love writing I do enjoy it a lot, and frankly, I miss it. But writing a big book like <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">Learning iPad Programming</a> took too much out of me, so this time I want to do it differently. I want to keep it small. Again, I’ll share details later but the plan is to create highly focused, short ebooks on specific topics. </li>
  <li><strong>Video tutorials.</strong> This is something I’ve explored in the past, and it’s something I want to explore again. But this time I want to do it under my control.</li>
</ol>

<p>I don’t suspect any one of these ideas to make a ton of money, but that’s not the goal. The goal is to start small and start now so I can build momentum. And if any one of the products fail, then I’ve only lost, at most, a few weeks of my time. Besides, pursuing these small product ideas will not be a failure anyways even if they don’t earn a single cent. That’s because I will be learning a lot more about marketing and building a personal brand. And once the momentum does grows I can turn my attention back to my apps with new found knowledge on how to market and grow those apps.</p>

<p>Wish me luck, and stay tuned to see if I succeed or fail in the coming month.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I’m not a fan of calling myself an entrepreneur because I don’t think of myself as one entrepreneur. But I am a business owner, and I have been for nearly 12 years, so I guess that makes me an entrepreneur. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fear]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/02/fear/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-02T06:48:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/02/fear</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I’ve been struggling to release new things out to the public, things such as blog posts, open source code, a new website and service I want to offer, even updates to some of my apps. What’s worse is that a number of these things are done and are just sitting on my computer. For instance, I’ve been using an updated version of Cross Post for nearly two months that isn’t available in the App Store. </p>

<p>So why haven’t I pulled the trigger on these things and released them to the public? Fear, that’s my answer. </p>

<p>I’m letting fear get the best me recently. I fear what people might say or think of the work I’m going. I fear that friends will start looking down on me. I fear that I will end up looking like an idiot. The funny part is I don’t have a fear of failing. You learn from failure. But for some odd reason I have developed a fear what others, especially friends, will think. </p>

<h2 id="out-of-character">Out of Character</h2>

<p>This fear of what others will think is completely out of character for me. For most of my life I’ve had a “I don’t give a fuck what other think” attitude (and that’s exactly how I’ve always put it). I was the high school weirdo with dyed hair and strange clothes. I was the nonconformist who would occasionally wear a polo shirt just to throw off my small circle of friends. In college I had a my racquetball racquet strung with bright hot pink strings, which led to some heated confrontations with others<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>. The point here is I didn’t care what others thought.</p>

<p>I remember an evening years ago when my dad refused to go out to dinner with me because of the way I was dressed. He said I embarrassed him. I argued that he was being ridiculous because 1) it wasn’t him that was dressed up like a Boy George reject and if anyone should be embarrassed it should be me (though I wasn’t), and 2) if I don’t care what people think about me, then why should he care. If anything people will feel sorry for him for having to sit with me at a restaurant. My argument didn’t change his mind and our dinner plans were canceled.</p>

<p>So if this fear is out of character for me, then where is it coming from?</p>

<h2 id="where-is-it-coming-from">Where Is It Coming From</h2>

<p>I know my fear is irrational when I think about it. But it’s still there and I can’t seem to shake it. Recently I’ve been putting a lot of thought into where this fear is coming from, and I think I might know. </p>

<p>I’ve been much more isolated since moving to Vermont. I don’t have the social circle of independent software developers and business owners around me like I did when I lived in New York City and the Boston area. Most of my social interactions these days involved talking about snowboarding and hiking, not on product releases, marketing, and growing a business. </p>

<p>Before moving to Vermont I attended a number of social gatherings where I could talk about and share my ideas. These groups were great and always provided excellent feedback. I always listened to what others had to say, but I didn’t always follow their advice. For example, I released a CSV editor for Windows years ago and made a good money from it for a number of years even though all my software dev friends said not to do it. Still, talking about the ideas with other on a regular bases always felt good, but I no longer have a local circle of friends and peers like I did before. And I think that is why I’ve developed this fear inside me.</p>

<p>Even though I didn’t care, for most of my life, what others thoughts, hearing what others had to say, both good or bad, always helped me. But in my recent isolation I rarely, if ever, get feedback from others. Hearing “you suck” motivated me to do better. Hearing “that’s awesome” in encouraged me to do more. But hearing nothing, no feedback at all, for long periods of time has caused this fear to grow inside of me. </p>

<h2 id="get-over-the-fear">Get Over The Fear</h2>

<p>I know my fears are irrational, but I can’t seem to shake them. So I’m trying a few new things in my attempts to get over the fear. </p>

<p>I’m trying to build a small community here in Stowe (though I think about giving up each month). A few folks do join me each month, but the group is not the same as the ones I participated in before coming to Vermont. Like the gatherings I attended before, this new group is made up of mostly software developers. But what is missing for me are the independents, the business owners, the solopreneur that were common in the circles I had when I lived in NYC and Boston.</p>

<p>I’m also participating in a bi-weekly mastermind group. This is going well, and in fact, it was on a recent mastermind call that I realized I’ve developed this irrational fear. My fear came up again last night in an email exchange with a friend who is doing a far better job of shipping than me. Talking about my fear with others as well as what I’m working on and my goals is starting to help me return to my old self, but I need to do more.</p>

<p>Another thing I’m interested in trying but I haven’t started yet is working with an accountability partner. The concept is simple. You and your partner help each other keep weekly commitments. Once a week you and your partner chat about the previous week’s accomplishments and the current week’s goals. When goals are not met, you analyze and talk through what happened. Having someone hold me accountable each week will help get me back into the habit of releasing things, which in turn will help me get over my fears.</p>

<p>One other thing I am doing in my attempts to shake the fear is to leave my quiet “cave” here in Stowe and get back into interacting in person with peers. To get things started, I agreed last week to speak at a small conference in October (more on this later). Just knowing I have this speaking event coming up should help reset my brain back to where it once was, or so I hope.</p>

<p>Are you having or had the similar fears? What sort of things are your doing to get over it? Fire off an email to me or send me a tweet and let me know.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>To this day I still don’t understand why people get so worked up over something so silly such as the string color of a racquetball racquet or the appearance of others. Just because it’s not something you would do, wear, or whatever doesn’t mean you need to hate on the other person. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips To Being More Focused]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/22/tips-to-being-more-focused/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-22T11:51:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/06/22/tips-to-being-more-focused</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I tweeted the other day that “I have the problem of wanting to do too many things at once, which is distracting. It’s time for me to learn how to scale back and focus.”</p>

<p><img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/420/18776596119_d03e98a590_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>It’s true. Right now there are a number of things I’m working on and there are even more things that I want to work on. </p>

<p>Lately I’ve been bouncing back and forth between a number of projects, but I haven’t been very productive. I start work on a task but before I finish I let myself get distracted with another task. For instance, I’ll work on a client project and before I finish the task at hand I’ll jump to another task from another project. </p>

<p>I haven’t always worked this way, and I’m not sure why I now struggle to stay focused. It could be the changing of seasons. I had my daily routine dialed in during the winter months, but something has changed recently and it’s not just the seasons. </p>

<p>Maybe my struggle with focus is a sign of being burnt out, maybe it’s the type of projects I’m working on - I’m certainly less excited about certain projects while much more excited about others. Maybe it’s because the kid is out of school and my work day is broken up into smaller chunks than during school time. Or maybe it’s a combination of all of the above. All I know for sure is that I find it difficult to focus, so last week I set out to find new ways to get focused and stay focused<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>. And here’s what I came up with…</p>

<h2 id="dont-check-email-first-thing-in-the-morning">Don’t Check Email First Thing In The Morning</h2>

<p>I have stopped checking email first thing in the morning. This is probably one of the hardest habit for me to break, but I’ve come to realize that checking email first thing in the morning leads to the biggest distractions for me. So it is a must change habit for me. </p>

<p>On a typical day I start the morning excited about what I’m planning to do during the day only to have that excitement squashed because of emails. The emails will often times change my plans for the day. Emails, in other words, control my day when I should be controlling my day.</p>

<p>Instead of checking email at the start of the day I now check it later in the morning, usually just before I break for lunch. This gives me a chance to really focus on the work at hand and not let my day get off on the wrong foot.</p>

<p>I admit this hasn’t been the easiest change for me to make. I’ve become accustom to checking my email as soon as I wake up…often times while still in bed. But I recognize that checking email first thing each morning typically controls the rest of my day. It causes me to change the priorities I set the evening before, which in turn makes me feel like I didn’t spend nearly as much time on the most important tasks for the week. That’s why I’ve stopped checking email first thing each day and I have replaced that habit with the next tip.</p>

<h2 id="do-whats-most-important-first">Do What’s Most Important First</h2>

<p>Instead of checking email at the start of my day, I begin my work day by working on the task that is most important for the day. It could be bug fixes for a client’s app, work on a new landing page, writing a blog post, or adding a new feature to one of my apps. I decide the night before what is the most important thing to do and that’s the first task I work on the next morning.</p>

<p>I’ve been following this tip for only a few days, and so far I feel more productive. Plus I feel a greater sense of accomplishment at the end of the day because that task that was most important got the love it deserved.</p>

<p>I highly recommend get into the habit of starting your day by doing the most important task first. If you are writing a book, start your day by writing. If you are working on a client project, and have a upcoming deadline, start your day by working on the project. And remember to work on this important task before you check your email.</p>

<p>Those are the biggest changes I’ve made to my daily routine, and I’m seeing immediate results. But I decided to try a couple of more things to see if I can make more improvements to my focus and productivity.</p>

<h2 id="limit-meetings-to-tuesday-and-thursday">Limit Meetings to Tuesday and Thursday</h2>

<p>My next tip is to limit meetings with others to two specific days each week. For me those two days are Tuesday and Thursday. </p>

<p>The main benefit to doing this is to give me more control over the other days of the week. I can use those other days to focus on productive work without the disruption of meetings. Meetings are, after all, disruptive to a productive day. Nothing kills my productivity faster than having to stop what I’m working on to waste time in a meeting. And yes, most meetings are a waste of time. Even the ones that are not a complete waste of time do waste some time. That casual chit chat at the beginning of the meeting, for example, is unproductive time. So I’m limiting those periods of unproductive time to two days a week.</p>

<p>I get that this isn’t something everyone can do. Heck I’m not 100% sure I can make it happen for me. But if you work for yourself and/or have control over your schedule, then you should be able to make this happen. </p>

<p>Also if you are like me, you already have meetings on your calendar. I, for example, have a recurring client meeting every Monday and Thursday mornings, another client meeting on Monday afternoon, one on Wednesday morning, and just recently a client asked to do a daily stand-up meeting each morning<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote">2</a></sup>. This means there will be a transition period for me as I get my meetings re-scheduled for Tuesday and Thursday. But this is something I’m going to make happen come hell or high water.</p>

<h2 id="pomodoro-technique">Pomodoro Technique</h2>

<p>As if not checking email first thing each morning isn’t already a big change to my daily routine, I’ve decided to give the <a href="http://pomodorotechnique.com">Pomodoro Technique</a> a try.</p>

<p>The Pomodoro Technique is simple. You set a timer for 25 minutes and during that time you focus on a particular task. When the 25 minutes are up, you take a 5 minute break. Then you start another pomodoro, setting the timer for 25 minutes; focus, focus, focus; then take another 5 minute break. After four pomodoros you take a longer break (15 to 30 minutes).</p>

<p>I’ve heard about the Pomodoro Technique a number of times over the years. I felt the process was not for me, but since focus has become a recent problem for me I decided to give it a try. So far the small blocks of 25-minute work cycles is working well for me given the amount of distractions that can happen throughout the day especially when my wife and kid are home. With the Pomodoro Technique I focus for 25 minutes, then I can use the 5 minute break answer a question my wife might have or see the latest LEGO creation my son has built.</p>

<p>Time will tell if this technique will work for me long term. And I should mention I’m not following the Pomodoro Technique by the book either. There are times when I reach the end of my 25 minute work cycle and I don’t want to stop. So I don’t. I skip my 5 minute break, and I continue working using a new pomodoro. But I do force myself to take a break after the second pomodoro when I combine two of them.</p>

<h2 id="do-these-tips-really-work">Do These Tips Really Work</h2>

<p>So do these tips really work? It’s hard for me to say with absolutely certainty that they work. I’m seeing some positive results already, but only time will tell what works and doesn’t work for me long term. And obviously not every tip will work for every person. Heck, I’m not sure if all the tips will work for me. But these are the tips I’m trying right now, and after only a few days I’m seeing good results. </p>

<p>I’m getting more done faster, and that feeling of being overwhelmed that I got at the end of each day has been replaced with a greater sense of accomplishment and a feeling of being more productive. But the real test for me will be following these tips for a month and see what happens. Trying these tips for a month is the only way I will know what works and doesn’t work for me.</p>

<p>I’ll post an update on my progress in a few weeks. Meanwhile I encourage you to give one, some or all the tips a try to see what works for you. And let me know how it works out for you. </p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Yes, I see the irony in that my search for ways to become more focused distracted me from the work that I needed to do last week. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>I personally think daily stand up meetings, like most meetings, are a waste of time, and it’s certainly not a productive use of my time. A daily status email is far more productive in my opinion, and you have the report captured for historical purposes.  <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>