<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: watch | thecave | A Hideout for Programmers, Indie Devs, Solopreneurs]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/watch/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-02T11:39:40-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Argh! Thanks A Lot Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/10/argh-thanks-a-lot-apple/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-10T03:13:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/10/argh-thanks-a-lot-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I woke up at 2:45 am this morning to buy a new Apple Watch. I ordered the 42mm space gray with black sport band Apple Watch Sport, but I’m still annoyed. I got a delivery date of May 13 to May 27, and that annoys me because I was ready to order at 3 am.</p>

<p>I was at my computer trying to load store.apple.com at 3 am, but the site was down. I foolishly kept refreshing the web page for 6 minutes before deciding to try the Apple Store app on my iPhone. The app worked perfectly, and thanks to Apple Pay, the order process was fast. But it was too late to get the watch I wanted in the first set of shipments, and all because I wasted my time trying to use the damn website.</p>

<p>I know, “first world problems.” All I can say is I’m grumpy when I have to use an alarm clock to wake up, and I become more grumpy when my time is wasted because of a website outage after waking up so freakin’ early.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Watch Will Make iPhone 6 Plus Size Less Annoying]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-06T21:42:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things that annoys me most about the size of my iPhone 6 Plus is pulling it out of my pocket while at a bar or restaurant just to see why my phone buzzed. The majority of the time my phone buzzes because of an incoming text message. I have notifications turned off for almost all other apps, and I rarely. if ever, get phone calls these days, which is why I know the buzz is most likely a text message. And if I’m at the bar without my wife, then the person trying to reach me is most likely my wife.</p>

<p>So when the text message comes in, I have to pull out this big honkin’ device out of my pocket and light up the room just to see the message. I may reply, and if I do, it’s a short reply because, after all, I’m busy at the bar. Then I put the phone back into my pocket only to repeat all of this a few minutes later.</p>

<p>Receiving text messages doesn’t annoy me, but having to pull out and put away this big device every few minutes does annoy me.</p>

<p>It occurred to me that one of the possible reasons why Apple decided to release the larger iPhones was because they knew, thanks to the Apple Watch, that there would be no reason to pull out these larger devices from pockets and purses just to check notifications and send simple text messages and replies.</p>

<p>The Apple Watch will make the iPhone 6 Plus size less annoying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>