<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: microsoft | thecave | Kirby Turner's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/microsoft/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-09-07T00:38:30+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Microsoft's Acquisition of HockeyApp Saddens Me]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/12/why-microsoft-s-acquisition-of-hockeyapp-saddens-me/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/12/why-microsoft-s-acquisition-of-hockeyapp-saddens-me</id>
    <tag>microsoft</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>While catching up on the latest tech news last night, I came across a post that said Microsoft had acquired HockeyApp. My first thought was this is a joke. I immediately went to the HockeyApp blog site and, lo and behold, it is not a joke. Microsoft did acquire HockeyApp.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While catching up on the latest tech news last night, I came across a post that said Microsoft had acquired HockeyApp. My first thought was this is a joke. I immediately went to the HockeyApp blog site and, lo and behold, it is not a joke. Microsoft did acquire HockeyApp.</p>

<p>This news left me with mixed feelings. First, I’m happy for the folks at HockeyApp. I’ve been a long time user of HockeyApp, and I feel they have the best solution for beta app distribution and crash reporting. The acquisition is further proof that HockeyApp is an outstanding solution. Yet at the same time it saddens me that HockeyApp is now in the hands of Microsoft.</p>

<p>It’s no secret that I’m not a fan of Microsoft. That wasn’t always the case. I used to love the technology coming out of Redmond, so much so that I worked for nearly 4 years for a consulting company co-owned by Microsoft whose initial purpose was to promote and showcase Microsoft technologies in the enterprise. But around 2005 I started feeling like Microsoft technologies were heading in the wrong direction and, by this time I was working for myself, I stopped recommending Microsoft technologies to clients. I also began transitioning my skill set to other non-Microsoft technologies. By the end of 2008 I was done working in the Microsoft world, a decision that I don’t regret one bit.</p>

<p>In 2010 my dislike for Microsoft became a bit more personal when an accounting mistake caused during the merger of billing systems after a Microsoft acquisition resulted in a collection agency calling me on behalf of Microsoft. I talk in detail about what happened <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/04/26/i-paid-for-microsofts-mistake/">here</a> and <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/05/18/follow-up-on-my-fight-with-microsoft/">here</a>, and thanks to the first post being picked up on Hacker News the matter was eventually <a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/2010/06/14/score-one-for-the-little-guy-and-kudos-to-microsoft/">resolved</a>. Still, I was left with a stronger dislike of Microsoft.</p>

<p>The combination of my lacking faith in Microsoft technologies and poor customer service experiences<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup> drove me away from Microsoft world, and in 2010 I made conscious decision to stop giving my money to Microsoft unless there is absolutely no other option<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote">2</a></sup>. I’m fully aware that my decision to stop buying Microsoft products and services has zero impact on Microsoft. Also I don’t view Microsoft as an evil empire or a horrible company, and not everything about Microsoft sucks. Heck, they are doing some really neat things these days. But based on my past experiences, Microsoft is not a company I want to do business with today.</p>

<p>It boils downs to a personal preference, much like my preference to shop at Target instead of Wal-mart or to buy from a locally owned store before buying from a national store or online. And this is why Microsoft’s acquisition of HockeyApp saddens me. A product I love is now in the hands of a company I choose to not do business with, and this means I need to think long and hard about whether or not I will continue using HockeyApp when my subscription comes up for renewal in October.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>I know there are individuals at Microsoft who really care about and do provide outstanding customer service, and there are consumers and businesses out there that have had nothing but great experiences dealing with Microsoft. But my own personal experiences dealing with Microsoft have been less than ideal.&nbsp;<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>When writing my books my publisher required I submit my manuscripts in Word documents, so I ended up buying a copy of Microsoft Word. Also I do enjoying playing video games on my Xbox, so Microsoft does get a bit of my money from time to time. But in general I have stopped buying Microsoft products and services.&nbsp;<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PowerPoint 2007 and Outlook 2003 Don't Play Nice Together]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2007/04/16/powerpoint-2007-and-outlook-2003-dont-play-nice-together/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2007/04/16/powerpoint-2007-and-outlook-2003-dont-play-nice-together</id>
    <tag>microsoft</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I had a need to install PowerPoint 2007.  Typically I install something like this in a virtual machine to avoid problems with other applications but yesterday I was in a rush so I installed PowerPoint 2007 in my “production” VM.  The Office 2007 installation gave me the option to keep my Office 2003 applications and install only PowerPoint 2007.  “Groovy!” I thought.  Well, it turns out not to be so groovy.  <br /><br />After installing PowerPoint 2007 and doing what I needed to do, I launched Outlook 2003.  As Outlook 2003 was loading the Office 2007 installer popped up and attempted to install something.  I cancel the installer and Outlook 2003 finally loads.  I checked my mail, read a few messages, and clicked Reply to author a response to a new message.  Here’s where the problem started.<br /><br />I have Outlook configured to use Word as the editor for messages.  When I tried to reply to a message Outlook locked up.  Not only did the application lock up but the entire operating system locked up.  I had no choice but to power off.<br /><br />Rebooting didn’t help either.  Outlook 2003 did not properly load, and I had a new problem.  Microsoft’s automatic update was now maxing out the CPU.  To regain control over the machine I killed the automatic update process.<br /><br />After dealing with this mess I believe I found a work around.  After installing PowerPoint 2007 and before launch Outlook 2003, launch Word 2003.  If your experience is similar to mine you will notice Word 2003 loads without the XP theme.  After about 30 seconds Word 2003’s UI switches to the XP theme.  It is after this point that Outlook 2003 is once again able to use Word 2003 as its editor.<br /><br />I can’t guarantee this will work for you but it did work for me.  I’m now able to use Outlook 2003 once again.<br /><br />The only problem that remains is the automatic update for Windows.  It still maxes out the CPU and the process must be manually killed.  I can handle doing this until I have time to re-build a new “production” VM.<br /><br /><span style="color:red">Update</span>: I found <a href="http://www.thecave.com/archive/2007/05/24/wuauclt_svchost_and_100_cpu_usgage.aspx">this wordaround</a> to the maxed out CPU problem.</p>
]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I had a need to install PowerPoint 2007.  Typically I install something like this in a virtual machine to avoid problems with other applications but yesterday I was in a rush so I installed PowerPoint 2007 in my “production” VM.  The Office 2007 installation gave me the option to keep my Office 2003 applications and install only PowerPoint 2007.  “Groovy!” I thought.  Well, it turns out not to be so groovy.  <br /><br />After installing PowerPoint 2007 and doing what I needed to do, I launched Outlook 2003.  As Outlook 2003 was loading the Office 2007 installer popped up and attempted to install something.  I cancel the installer and Outlook 2003 finally loads.  I checked my mail, read a few messages, and clicked Reply to author a response to a new message.  Here’s where the problem started.<br /><br />I have Outlook configured to use Word as the editor for messages.  When I tried to reply to a message Outlook locked up.  Not only did the application lock up but the entire operating system locked up.  I had no choice but to power off.<br /><br />Rebooting didn’t help either.  Outlook 2003 did not properly load, and I had a new problem.  Microsoft’s automatic update was now maxing out the CPU.  To regain control over the machine I killed the automatic update process.<br /><br />After dealing with this mess I believe I found a work around.  After installing PowerPoint 2007 and before launch Outlook 2003, launch Word 2003.  If your experience is similar to mine you will notice Word 2003 loads without the XP theme.  After about 30 seconds Word 2003’s UI switches to the XP theme.  It is after this point that Outlook 2003 is once again able to use Word 2003 as its editor.<br /><br />I can’t guarantee this will work for you but it did work for me.  I’m now able to use Outlook 2003 once again.<br /><br />The only problem that remains is the automatic update for Windows.  It still maxes out the CPU and the process must be manually killed.  I can handle doing this until I have time to re-build a new “production” VM.<br /><br /><span style="color:red">Update</span>: I found <a href="http://www.thecave.com/archive/2007/05/24/wuauclt_svchost_and_100_cpu_usgage.aspx">this wordaround</a> to the maxed out CPU problem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Microsoft Re-designed the iPod Packaging?]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2006/04/27/what-is-microsoft-re-designed-the-ipod-packaging/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2006/04/27/what-is-microsoft-re-designed-the-ipod-packaging</id>
    <tag>microsoft</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>It might go a little something like this…<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EUXnJraKM3k&amp;search=microsoft%20packaging%20ipod">Microsoft’s Re-designed iPod Packing</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It might go a little something like this…<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EUXnJraKM3k&amp;search=microsoft%20packaging%20ipod">Microsoft’s Re-designed iPod Packing</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>