<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: nyc | thecave | Kirby Turner's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/nyc/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-08-05T01:23:55+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do you miss New York?]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2006/03/29/do-you-miss-new-york/"/>
    <updated>2006-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2006/03/29/do-you-miss-new-york</id>
    <tag>nyc</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A common question I get since moving to Salem is “Do you miss New York?”  I was thinking about that question this morning as I was standing on the 4-5-6 platform at Grand Central Station.  For those who don’t know, that’s in New York, and the answer is “No”.  I haven’t spent enough time in Salem or enough time away from New York to miss it yet.  It will probably hit me some time this summer but for now I haven’t missed the Big Apple.  Heck, Melanie is still based out of JFK and sees the city more than I do.  I wonder if she misses it yet.</p>
]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A common question I get since moving to Salem is “Do you miss New York?”  I was thinking about that question this morning as I was standing on the 4-5-6 platform at Grand Central Station.  For those who don’t know, that’s in New York, and the answer is “No”.  I haven’t spent enough time in Salem or enough time away from New York to miss it yet.  It will probably hit me some time this summer but for now I haven’t missed the Big Apple.  Heck, Melanie is still based out of JFK and sees the city more than I do.  I wonder if she misses it yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Surreal]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2006/01/26/its-surreal/"/>
    <updated>2006-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2006/01/26/its-surreal</id>
    <tag>nyc</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I have actually moved from New York City to <a href="http://www.salemweb.com/">Salem, Massachusetts</a>.  It’s still a bit surreal for us.  As we were driving out of the city yesterday, it didn’t feel like we were really leaving.  It felt more like we were making a quick trip and will be returning in a few days.  I think it will hit me in a few days that we’re not returning to the city to live.  Then again it might take longer for that to happen since I will be returning to New York next week for a meeting.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I have actually moved from New York City to <a href="http://www.salemweb.com/">Salem, Massachusetts</a>.  It’s still a bit surreal for us.  As we were driving out of the city yesterday, it didn’t feel like we were really leaving.  It felt more like we were making a quick trip and will be returning in a few days.  I think it will hit me in a few days that we’re not returning to the city to live.  Then again it might take longer for that to happen since I will be returning to New York next week for a meeting.</p>

<p>The move was the smoothest and easiest move I have ever made.  The movers from Oz Moving were outstanding.  I highly recommend using Oz.</p>

<p>The only problem that occurred yesterday was a flat tire in Connecticut.  The moving truck got a flat on I-95 which delayed their arrival into Salem.  But they did arrive.  We got everything unloaded, and now all that awaits us is the process of unpacking.</p>

<p>Update (September 13, 2012): Oz Moving’s web site is http://www.ozmoving.com/. There is no link here because they asked me to remove the link. Seems odd to me that they would make such a request, especially since I’m recommending them, but still, the link has been removed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Farewell New York, Hello Salem]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2006/01/24/farewell-new-york-hello-salem/"/>
    <updated>2006-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2006/01/24/farewell-new-york-hello-salem</id>
    <tag>nyc</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Today is our last full day in New York.  The movers arrive tomorrow at 8 AM.  We have almost everything packed.  We ran out of boxes last night so we couldn’t finish.  <br /><br />I’m not sure how soon we will have Internet access from the new home.  That’s one of my projects today…to schedule cable TV and Internet hook up.  So don’t expect a quick reply to emails and forum postings for the next few days.<br /><br />So how will we spend our final day in New York?  We have a few more things to pack, and the DVR/cable boxes need to be returned to Time Warner.  I’m meeting a good friend this afternoon for a quick happy hour drink followed by date night with my wife.  We are going to dinner at the place of our first date.  Unfortunately it won’t be a late night because the movers are coming early tomorrow but I’m sure it will still be a special time for us.<br /><br />I thought leaving New York was going to be hard, but as it turns out I’m ready to go.  The fact we spent our last weekend up in Vermont is probably a sign that we need to move.  We just don’t enjoy the city the way we use too, and there are so many other things we want out of life that are hard to obtain from here unless you have lots of money.  So it’s farewell to New York, hello Salem.</p>
]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is our last full day in New York.  The movers arrive tomorrow at 8 AM.  We have almost everything packed.  We ran out of boxes last night so we couldn’t finish.  <br /><br />I’m not sure how soon we will have Internet access from the new home.  That’s one of my projects today…to schedule cable TV and Internet hook up.  So don’t expect a quick reply to emails and forum postings for the next few days.<br /><br />So how will we spend our final day in New York?  We have a few more things to pack, and the DVR/cable boxes need to be returned to Time Warner.  I’m meeting a good friend this afternoon for a quick happy hour drink followed by date night with my wife.  We are going to dinner at the place of our first date.  Unfortunately it won’t be a late night because the movers are coming early tomorrow but I’m sure it will still be a special time for us.<br /><br />I thought leaving New York was going to be hard, but as it turns out I’m ready to go.  The fact we spent our last weekend up in Vermont is probably a sign that we need to move.  We just don’t enjoy the city the way we use too, and there are so many other things we want out of life that are hard to obtain from here unless you have lots of money.  So it’s farewell to New York, hello Salem.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>