<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tech | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-11T10:08:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boston Area Mac And iOS Dev Community Is Awesome]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/07/boston-area-mac-and-ios-dev-community-is-awesome/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-07T10:22:16-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/07/boston-area-mac-and-ios-dev-community-is-awesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past Wednesday I had a chance to attend <a href="http://www.nshappyhour.org">NSHappyHour</a>. It’s was my first time attending since moving to Vermont two years ago. I had a great time catching up with everyone, and I was reminded just how awesome the Mac and iOS developer community is in the Boston area. </p>

<p>I also was reminded how much I miss the community there, and since moving back isn’t an option for me - snowboard season starts in about 3 months for me - I need to make a point of visit the Boston area more.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redirect Jekyll Site To HTTPS On OpenShift]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/14/redirect-jekyll-site-to-https-on-openshift/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-14T14:17:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/14/redirect-jekyll-site-to-https-on-openshift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m preparing to roll out a new <a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> website, but unlike with my other Jekyll sites, I want each web page served up on <code>https</code>, not <code>http</code>. This means telling the server to redirect <code>http</code> request to <code>https</code>. </p>

<p>Hosting this new site on <a href="https://pages.github.com">Github Pages</a> isn’t option because Github Pages doesn’t support using a custom SSL certificate for your custom domain name. So I decided to see what it would take to host a Jekyll site on <a href="https://www.openshift.com">OpenShift</a>. </p>

<p>I was thrilled to learn that OpenShift has a <a href="https://hub.openshift.com/quickstarts/41-jekyll">quick start cartridge for installing Jekyll</a> on a new gear. With a click of a button I was able to deploy my new server instance with a boiler plate Jekyll site. I replaced the boiler plate site with the one I’ve been working on, and BAM! My site was up and running. The only step remaining was to force the web server to serve up the pages using <code>https</code>.</p>

<p>Turns out this is simple to do with OpenShift and Jekyll. First, I went over to namecheap.com and purchased a <a href="https://www.namecheap.com/security/ssl-certificates/rapidssl/rapidssl.aspx">RapidSSL certificate</a> with domain validation. Next, I followed the instructions from OpenShift to <a href="https://developers.openshift.com/en/managing-domains-ssl.html#_generating_a_csr_certificate_signing_request">generate my certificate signing request</a>. Using my newly generated CSR I activated my RapidSSL certificate over at namecheap, then I followed the instructions on OpenShift to <a href="https://developers.openshift.com/en/managing-domains-ssl.html#using-a-custom-ssl-certificate">add the certificate to my server instance</a>.</p>

<p>Up to this point everything was easy peasy, and all I had left to do was figure out how to redirect the Jekyll site from <code>http</code> to <code>https</code>. Turns out this isn’t difficult either.</p>

<p>The Jekyll website is actually just a static website hosted by Apache 2 running on an OpenShift gear. To force the redirect all I needed to do was add a <em>.htaccess</em> file to the root of my Jekyll site source code (note: the site source code is in the <em>source/</em> directory when using OpenShift) and put this rewrite rule in the file:</p>

<pre><code>RewriteEngine on  
RewriteCond %{HTTP:X-Forwarded-Proto} !https  
RewriteRule .* https://%{HTTP_HOST}%{REQUEST_URI} [R,L]  
</code></pre>

<p>After I added the <em>.htaccess</em> file with the rewrite rule, I pushed my changes to the remote git repository running on my OpenShift gear. This launched Jekyll which re-built my static website, this time with each web page being served with <code>https</code> instead of <code>http</code>.</p>

<p>Including the <em>.htaccess</em> file works great when deploying the Jekyll site to OpenShift, but approach isn’t unique to OpenShift. This should work for most Jekyll site hosted with Apache 2. And if for some reason Jekyll isn’t including the <em>.htaccess</em> file when it builds the site, add <code>include: [".htaccess"]</code> to your <em>_config.yaml</em> file.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Watch Will Make iPhone 6 Plus Size Less Annoying]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-06T21:42:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/06/apple-watch-will-make-iphone-6-plus-size-less-annoying</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the things that annoys me most about the size of my iPhone 6 Plus is pulling it out of my pocket while at a bar or restaurant just to see why my phone buzzed. The majority of the time my phone buzzes because of an incoming text message. I have notifications turned off for almost all other apps, and I rarely. if ever, get phone calls these days, which is why I know the buzz is most likely a text message. And if I’m at the bar without my wife, then the person trying to reach me is most likely my wife. </p>

<p>So when the text message comes in, I have to pull out this big honkin’ device out of my pocket and light up the room just to see the message. I may reply, and if I do, it’s a short reply because, after all, I’m busy at the bar. Then I put the phone back into my pocket only to repeat all of this a few minutes later. </p>

<p>Receiving text messages doesn’t annoy me, but having to pull out and put away this big device every few minutes does annoy me. </p>

<p>It occurred to me that one of the possible reasons why Apple decided to release the larger iPhones was because they knew, thanks to the Apple Watch, that there would be no reason to pull out these larger devices from pockets and purses just to check notifications and send simple text messages and replies.</p>

<p>The Apple Watch will make the iPhone 6 Plus size less annoying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Affordable Cloud Storage With Amazon Cloud Drive]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/27/affordable-cloud-storage-with-amazon-cloud-drive/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-27T06:52:45-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/27/affordable-cloud-storage-with-amazon-cloud-drive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday Amazon announced new <a href="https://www.amazon.com/clouddrive/pricing">pricing plans</a> for their cloud storage offering named <a href="https://www.amazon.com/clouddrive/home">Cloud Drive</a>. You can store unlimited number of photos for $11.99 per year, or you can store unlimited number of files for $59.99. The later is a no-brainer for me as I have been looking for an affordable cloud storage solution like this.</p>

<p>Currently I use a number of different services for cloud storage. I use <a href="https://db.tt/Y2NovyiG">Dropbox</a> to sync files between computers and devices. The files I keep on Dropbox are ones I need immediate access to. In other words, these are the files I need to have on my laptop while also having access from other computers and devices such as my iPhone. </p>

<p>I use <a href="https://secure.backblaze.com/r/00ytw8">Backblaze</a> to backup all the files on my laptop to the cloud. It’s my lifeline should something unexpected happen to my laptop. For photos I use <a href="https://secure.smugmug.com/signup?Coupon=8ZK2smzZYAS1I">SmugMug</a>, but more recently I’ve been using <a href="http://www.flickr.com">Flickr</a> more than SmugMug. And I use Rackspace Cloud File for my CDN. That’s content delivery network for my non-geeky friends reading this.</p>

<p>The problem with these different cloud storage providers is that I still had no easy way to upload and store files that I don’t need frequent access to. I don’t like to throw away data, but I also don’t need documents I wrote back in 2003 wasting space on my laptop. Dropbox has a way to not sync selected folders, but I don’t trust it. Plus, it’s not as straight forward as uploading and storing selected files.</p>

<p>Rackspace Cloud File works well for archiving my old data, but it can become costly if I have multi-terabytes of data to store. Same is true for Amazon S3, which I considered using in the past. In fact, when Amazon announced S3 Glacier I thought I had found the perfect cloud storage solution for me, but it’s not easy to use.</p>

<p>Flickr and SmugMug are great for storing photos and videos, and they both make it easy to upload new ones. Heck, Flickr will even automatically upload new photos taken on my iPhone for me. It doesn’t get much easier than that. But these two only support photos and videos, and I have other file types I want to store in the cloud.</p>

<p>So when I first heard about Amazon’s new pricing for Cloud Drive I thought, “Finally, an affordable cloud storage solution that fixes my needs for archiving old data.” At $60 per year for unlimited storage, I would be a fool not to try it out. But I don’t even need to spend the $60 right now. Amazon is offering a 3-month free trial.</p>

<p>Cloud Drive has desktop software for your Mac (and I’m guessing Windows too) to upload files, but I’m not a fan of the desktop software. It doesn’t let me pick where I want to store the files I’m uploading, and I like to use a very specific directory structure for my files. </p>

<p>While the Cloud Drive desktop software doesn’t suite my needs, the Cloud Drive web interface does. I can organize my storage area to my liking, create new folders and upload files to specific folders within the file system. And that’s just what I’ve been doing…uploading and organizing files - a few gigs so far to test out the service.</p>

<p>I do, however, have one complaint about Cloud Drive. The Cloud Drive app for iOS only shows photos and videos. I want access to all the files stored on my Cloud Drive. Hopefully Amazon will change this soon, or maybe it’s an opportunity for me to write a new app. There is, after all, an API for Cloud Drive.</p>

<p>Amazon Cloud Drive is the solution I’ve been looking for to archive my old data to the cloud. I’ll continue using external hard drives, Dropbox, Backblaze and such for backups, but my days with SmugMugs might be numbered. Still, I’m excited to finally have an affordable cloud storage solution for my old data.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New kirbyturner.com Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/new-kirbyturnercom-site/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-15T16:20:35-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/15/new-kirbyturnercom-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have owned the vanity domain name <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">kirbyturner.com</a> for a long time, but I didn’t anything with it after buying it. That changed back when I was writing <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com">Learning iPad Programming</a>. My publisher asked that I setup a website that talks about me, so I finally put kirbyturner.com to use. Unfortunately I never liked the look of the site. I used a bland template to create the website quickly. The site was ugly, but it served its purpose. Then Justin Williams created a new “professional web site” for <a href="http://www.justinw.me">himself</a>.</p>

<p>My first thought after seeing Justin’s new site was, “Wow! That looks really nice.” My second thought was, “Man my site sucks donkey balls.” So I spent the last couple of days working on a new look for <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">kirbyturner.com</a>. I just finished the site, and I can say with 100% certainty that the new site looks much, much better than my <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/16288802435/">old site</a>. Thanks for the inspiration, Justin.</p>

<p>Take a look at the new and improved <a href="http://www.kirbyturner.com">kirbyturner.com</a>, and let me know what you think.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>