<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: writing | thecave | Kirby Turner's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/tag/writing/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-10-26T18:22:19+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blogging The Little Things]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/07/blogging-the-little-things/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-07T14:11:57+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/08/07/blogging-the-little-things</id>
    <tag>writing</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I read a post from Shubham Jain, by way of <a href="http://shapeof.com/archives/2015/7/coffee_coder_-_blog_little_things.html">Gus Mueller</a>, about <a href="http://coffeecoder.net/blog/blog-little-things/">blogging the little things</a>. In the post, Shubham says:</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read a post from Shubham Jain, by way of <a href="http://shapeof.com/archives/2015/7/coffee_coder_-_blog_little_things.html">Gus Mueller</a>, about <a href="http://coffeecoder.net/blog/blog-little-things/">blogging the little things</a>. In the post, Shubham says:</p>

<div class="highlighter-rouge"><pre class="highlight"><code>There are lots of things that can be blogged about and yet, we are stuck in the dilemma of, – "Is it worth something to write?". The fear of being insignificant aka "Nobody will read it" syndrome, inhibits us from writing that simple thing that might have helped many people.
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>I recently talked about my <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/07/02/fear/">fears</a> and I mentioned some of the things I’m trying to do to help overcome those fears. And blogging more about the little things seems like another way for me to overcome some of the fears I’ve been having.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where I Blog These Days]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-19T13:40:11+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/19/where-i-blog-these-days</id>
    <tag>writing</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I’ve recently, and “recently” as in the last couple of years, cut back on the number of blog sites I have. I’m down to three sites now, and that seems manageable. The sites are:</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve recently, and “recently” as in the last couple of years, cut back on the number of blog sites I have. I’m down to three sites now, and that seems manageable. The sites are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/">thecave.com</a><br />
  That’s this site. It’s my personal blog, and it’s where I post most often. I talk about everything from what’s going on with me personally to snowboarding to programming. The site is broken down into categories, and I have plans to publish an RSS feed for each category so readers can filter out topics they might consider noise.</li>
  <li><a href="http://blog.whitepeaksoftware.com/">blog.whitepeaksoftware.com</a><br />
  This is my company blog site. The focus of this site is to talk about the company and the products I sell. Granted I’m doing a horrible job at keeping up with the posts. That’s probably one of the many reasons my stuff doesn’t sell as well as it did a few years back.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.rowanturner.net/">rowanturner.net</a><br />
  Yep, my son has his own website. But he has no interest in making posts here, so I do it for him. I usually post pictures and videos of Rowan and his friends off having fun. My mom might be the only person reading this site regularly, but that’s fine. I’ll keep posting because I like looking back on past articles and reliving fun moments with my kid.</li>
</ul>

<p>These sites each have RSS feeds, so you don’t have to remember to visit. And some day I’ll do a better job of mentioning when new posts are available on the various social networks for those who don’t want to subscribe to the feeds.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reliving The Past]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/reliving-the-past/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-17T06:38:50+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/02/17/reliving-the-past</id>
    <tag>writing</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I just spent the last two hours looking through past posts here at thecave. I was writing a lot for the four or five years, and some of those old posts are actually good. But more importantly reading through those old posts gave me a chance to relive my past.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just spent the last two hours looking through past posts here at thecave. I was writing a lot for the four or five years, and some of those old posts are actually good. But more importantly reading through those old posts gave me a chance to relive my past.</p>

<p>This makes me realize I need to post here more even if the post is short like this one. All too often I’ll post something short to Twitter or Facebook, but I need to start posting it here too. It will be great to re-read my old posts five years from now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Plans For A Third Edition]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/08/no-plans-for-a-third-edition/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-08T13:18:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/08/no-plans-for-a-third-edition</id>
    <tag>writing</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A number of people have recently asked if there will be a third edition of <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/">Learning iPad Programming</a>. The short answer is no, there are no plans. There are many reasons why I decided to not update the book, but a few key reasons stand out more than others.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A number of people have recently asked if there will be a third edition of <a href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/">Learning iPad Programming</a>. The short answer is no, there are no plans. There are many reasons why I decided to not update the book, but a few key reasons stand out more than others.</p>

<h2 id="i-enjoy-writing-but-i-dont-love-it">I Enjoy Writing, But I Don’t Love It</h2>

<p>Writing a tech book was on my bucket list for many years, and writing has long been an interest of mine. But writing a book like Learning iPad Programming takes a lot of time. The first two editions of the book consumed most of my time and life for nearly two and a half years, and this left me feeling stressed and depressed. That’s when I came to the conclusion that my time is better spent <a href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/06/20/enjoy-less-and-love-more/">doing things I love</a> and cutting back on doing things that I only enjoy.</p>

<p>If I had all the time in the world, then I certainly would consider updating the book each year or two. But my time is limited, and writing apps, snowboarding, spending time with my family, and going on outdoor adventures are all things I love doing. And those things leave me with little extra time to do things I only enjoy.</p>

<h2 id="no-financial-motivation">No Financial Motivation</h2>

<p>My <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">company</a> was booming just before I started work on the first edition of Learning iPad Programming. I saw a steady increase in product revenue year after year for five straight years, and I was becoming less dependent on consulting and contract work. In other words, I was on track for making a living selling my own products. In fact, that’s partly why I agreed to write a book in the first place. In my mind the book was another product in my expanding line of diversified products. But it turns out writing a book is hard. And writing the first edition was probably one of the hardest things I’ve ever done.</p>

<p>I had never written a book before, so I ended up spending a lot of time learning how to write a book. I also tried a number of different systems to get me into the habit of writing. All of this extra time spent on learning to write, how to get pass mental blocks, how to stay motivated, how to make daily progress, even the smallest bit, took my focus away from my company. And at one point I knew the only way I would finish the book was to devote 100% of my time to it, so that’s exactly what I did. I stopped working for a few months so I could work on the book full time.</p>

<p>All the time spent away from my company resulted in lost revenue as my product sales started a downward trend and I had zero time to offset the drop in product revenue with consulting. That meant I had to start living off of borrowed money. By the time the book was done I had well over $50K in credit card debt. And while sales of the book were great<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote">1</a></sup>, the royalty payments I received were not enough to pay down the debt, debt that I’m still working on paying off today.</p>

<h2 id="mistakes-and-mishandling">Mistakes and Mishandling</h2>

<p>The third and possibly the number one reason there are no plans for a third edition were the mistakes and mishandling of both editions of the book by the publisher. The publisher’s decision to release the second edition two weeks before WWDC 2013 was the final straw for me. Apple announced iOS 7 with its new look at that WWDC making the second edition obsolete only two weeks after hitting the bookstores.</p>

<p>There were other mistakes made throughout my time working with the publisher, from production problems to not completing planned projects. But it was the handling, or as I call it, the mishandling of the second edition that led to my decision to not continue updating the book.</p>

<p>If the book were self-published, then things might be different. But as it stands Learning iPad Programming is owned by the publisher, and everything other than the final manuscript is controlled by the publisher. I certainly have some say and can provide input, but I don’t really have any control once the manuscript is turned over to them. And given the past mistakes and mishandling of projects, I cannot see myself working with the same group for a third edition (my editor and her assistant excluded - they were outstanding to work with).</p>

<h1 id="there-you-have-it">There You Have It</h1>

<p>So there you have it, the main reasons there are no plans for a third edition of Learning iPad Programming. I admit it makes me rather sad when I think about it not doing new editions of the book. I poured my heart and soul into the first two editions, and I had high hopes that there would be many more editions for years to come. But at the end of the day it just not worth struggle, stress, and toll that the first two editions took on me, my family, and our financial wellbeing.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Of the millions of books available on Amazon, my book was in the top 1100 for a few months. This is an outstanding and rare achievement for a tech book, and one of my proudest moments during my career.&nbsp;<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Minutes Of Writing]]></title>
    
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/15-minutes-of-writing/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T18:19:09+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/01/07/15-minutes-of-writing</id>
    <tag>writing</tag>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>My friend, Greg Raiz, talks about <a href="http://www.raizlabs.com/graiz/2015/01/05/better-goals-via-better-systems/">using a system to achieve goals</a>. The particular goal he wants to achieve is writing more.</p>

]]></description>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend, Greg Raiz, talks about <a href="http://www.raizlabs.com/graiz/2015/01/05/better-goals-via-better-systems/">using a system to achieve goals</a>. The particular goal he wants to achieve is writing more.</p>

<p>I’ve tried using a system similar to what Greg describes, but I fail each time I try. My system, or goal as I still often call it, has been to write an hour each day. Writing an hour day, often times more, was easy when I was writing my books, but I can’t seem to get into the routine now that I’m done with book writing (for now). I realized after reading Greg’s post that I’ve been doing it wrong.</p>

<p>Greg’s plan is to write about 100 words a day, or for about 15 minutes a day, which is about the amount of time he needs to write 100 words. And that sounds like a much more reasonable system than writing for an hour a day.</p>

<p>I wish I could write for at least an hour a day, but it’s just not in me to do that right now. Sure, if I were focused on writing a book then I would have no problem writing an hour a day. In fact, I would write more. But writing a book not my focus. Writing apps is my focus. And 15 minutes a day sounds like a perfect way for me to get back into writing.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>