<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: snowboarding | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/snowboarding/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-01T16:08:42-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Despite A Rainy Start]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/28/despite-a-rainy-start/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/28/despite-a-rainy-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite a rainy start this morning, I was able to get in a few snowboard runs on the hill before crowd arrived. And I had great visibility top to bottom on the last two runs. I think that might be the first time this season I’ve had great visibility top to bottom.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Tradition Comes To A Close Tonight]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/22/a-tradition-comes-to-a-close-tonight/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/12/22/a-tradition-comes-to-a-close-tonight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On December 22, 2001, I was in Whistler with my friends Dave and Joe. We spent the day snowboarding, then that night we went to see the first Lord of the Rings movie. Little did I know that night would become a tradition of sorts for me.</p>

<p>On December 22, 2002, I repeated the previous year by snowboarding, though not at Whistler, during the day and went to see the second LOTR movie that night. And yep, I did it again December 22, 2003. My wife, who joined me for the second and third movies, was glad the trilogy was over. Snowboarding a full day then going to a long movie that evening made for a long day. But then The Hobbit came out so…</p>

<p>On December 22, 2012, the tradition resumed with a full day of snowboarding followed by watching first hobbit movie. And one year later, December 22, 2013, was another long day of snowboarding and hobbits. </p>

<p>And this brings us to today, December 22, 2014. I spent the day snowboarding and tonight I will go see The Hobbit: The Battle of the Five Armies. The tradition continues for one more day, but unless there are more hobbit movies hitting movie theaters in the future, this tradition comes to a close tonight.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still Enjoying the Snow]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/08/still-enjoying-the-snow/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/05/08/still-enjoying-the-snow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/sets/72157644571329602"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7347/14161061213_f44bfb7073_m.jpg" alt="Top of Nosedive" border="0" width="150" class="alignleft" /></a> I refuse to accept that winter is over. For instance, today I hiked up Mt. Mansfields to do a snowboard run on Nosedive. And based on the crowd, I wasn’t the only one who thought today was a good day for a hike.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kirbyturner/sets/72157644571329602">Here are some pictures</a> from today’s hike.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm Having a Bad Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/02/05/i-m-having-a-bad-day/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/02/05/i-m-having-a-bad-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m having a really bad day today. First, I had to rush to get Rowan to school. He was being his normal slow self, but thankfully we made it there before the bell rang. Then I get to the hill to ride the new snow when I realized I left my snowboard gear at home. So back home I go. But I had to drive behind a plow the entire way home turning a 15 minute drive into a 25 minute drive. And now I have to drive with the stream of traffic back up the hill. </p>

<p>Don’t you just hate days like today.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 25]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2014/01/17/day-25/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2014/01/17/day-25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks my 25th day snowboarding this season. While this might sound awesome, it’s fewer days than I was hoping to have by mid-January. I snowboarded 21 days up through Christmas. That means I have only snowboarded 4 days since Christmas, which is why I thought I would have more days by now.</p>

<p>There are a couple of reasons I’ve only gotten in 4 days over the last 3 weeks:</p>

<ol>
  <li>My season pass has blackout dated between December 26 and December 31. </li>
  <li>Warm temperatures and rain last week left the hill in less than ideal conditions, so I didn’t go out.</li>
</ol>

<p>Thankfully winter has returned to Stowe, and I’ve been able to hit the slopes again. And with more snow in the forecast I’m hoping to see my day count increase more rapidly in the coming weeks.</p>

<p>Oh, and just to be clear my days on the hill are not full days like you would do when on vacation. I still have a <a href="http://www.whitepeaksoftware.com/">job</a> and I have to work. So when I go out for a day in Stowe it’s usually only for an hour and a half to two hours. I might do longer days when snowboarding with Rowan and Melanie, but in general my days on the slope are the equivalent to someone else going to the gym or running or doing some other form of regular exercise.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>