<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: snowboarding | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/snowboarding/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-14T21:03:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snow River At Stowe]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-09T11:24:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/05/09/snow-river-at-stowe</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This looks like it was a lot of fun. Wish I had known about it when it happened last year. </p>

<p><div class="youtube-video"><figure><iframe width="560" height="420" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wfWUHKUt-Q0?color=white&theme=light"></iframe></figure></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Should Feel Guilty But I Don't]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/13/i-should-feel-guilty-but-i-dont/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-13T20:15:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/04/13/i-should-feel-guilty-but-i-dont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played hooky from work afternoon. I should feel guilty but I don’t. </p>

<p>I picked up Rowan from school this afternoon, and we headed to the mountain. Unfortunately I forgot his skis boots, so we had to stop by the house. Then as we tried to get on the lift I realized I left our passes in our jackets. The temperature was in the 60, so we weren’t wearing our jackets. They were still at the house. The afternoon was off to a bad start, but our luck changed. </p>

<p>We were able to get two runs in before the lifts closed thanks to the nice lifties that let us through without our passes. Also we ran into some friends in our first run, including a class mate of Rowan’s. After the lifts shut down for the day we hung out in the parking lot for a bit of après ski with friends. Then we headed to Rimrocks where we ran into more friends. </p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8776/16952950809_f0103c0255_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>It was a great father son afternoon with wonderful friends, and when I’m 85 years old I’ll remember how much fun Rowan and I had today. I won’t remember the work I should have done today, and that’s why I don’t feel guilty about how I spent my time this afternoon.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8722/16951598160_95cb6df7cc_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Driver X]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/09/driver-x/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-09T16:11:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/09/driver-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I received my new pair of Burton Driver X snowboard boots this afternoon. Damn, these puppies are stiff, but that’s a good thing. I can’t wait to hit the hill with them in the morning. It’s going to be a whole new riding experience after wearing boots that I probably should’ve replaced a couple of seasons ago.</p>

<p><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7634/16766864701_a383cbd8cc_z.jpg" alt="" /></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Feel Guilty But]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/09/i-feel-guilty-but/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-09T11:21:39-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/09/i-feel-guilty-but</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our local hill received a surprised 6-7 inches of new snow overnight. I feel a little guilty for not letting Rowan skip the first half of school this morning so he could ride the fresh powder, but at the time, he didn’t ask to skip school so he’s loss.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Snow Was Better In 2003]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/05/the-snow-was-better-in-2003/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-05T10:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2015/03/05/the-snow-was-better-in-2003</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During our stay in Whistler last week, I kept saying to my wife I thought the snow conditions, which weren’t the best, were about the same as the conditions we experienced in February 2003. Turns out I was wrong.</p>

<p>The conditions in 2003 were much better. The snow was soft, and we did a lot of riding in the bowls. The base might not have been as deep in 2003, but it was certainly better. The hard pack and icy conditions this year limited where we could ride. Really, the only thing that was the same between the two seasons was the lack of new snow.</p>

<p>So how did I finally remember that the snow conditions were better when I was thinking they were the same? I re-read my postings from WASTED II trip, which was held in February 2003. Here are my postings from that trip:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/01/day-0-the-commute-begins/">Day 0</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/02/day-1-the-arrival/">Day 1</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/03/day-2-a-hundred-and-ten-percent/">Day 2</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/04/day-3-birthday-fondue/">Day 3</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/05/wasted-ii-day-4-bowl-of-sweetness/">Day 4</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/06/wasted-ii-day-5-park-fun/">Day 5</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/07/wasted-ii-day-6-return-to-blackcomb/">Day 6</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/08/wasted-ii-day-7-the-brotherhood/">Day 7</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/09/wasted-ii-day-8-beer-xbox-and-more-beer/">Day 8</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/13/wasted-ii-day-9-10-11-and-12-catch-up/">Day 9, 10, 11 and 12</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/16/wasted-ii-final-days-no-snow-but-still-a-great-time/">Final Days</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.thecave.com/2003/02/16/wasted-ii-im-so-glad-we-had-this-time-together/">Conclusion</a></li>
</ul>

<p>On a related note, a long time local told me that the conditions this years are the worst he has seen since 1986.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>