<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rowan | thecave | Ramblings From A Crotchety Old Man]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/category/rowan/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thecave.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-21T23:25:45-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thecave.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rowan on the Balance Board]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/11/rowan-on-the-balance-board/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/11/11/rowan-on-the-balance-board</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/blog/2013-11-11rowan-balanceboard.gif"><img src="/images/blog/2013-11-11rowan-balanceboard.gif" alt="Rowan on the balance board" border="0" width="150" class="alignleft" /></a> I wanted to play with a GIF animator, so I used a few photos I took yesterday of Rowan playing on the balance board. That kid is going to be so much better than me at just about everything.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations to the Kid]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/20/congrats-to-the-kid/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2013/06/20/congrats-to-the-kid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Rowan/Pre-school-Graduation/30095717_rX5mHW"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Rowan/Pre-school-Graduation/i-mVqV5r9/0/Th/IMG_1350%20-%20Version%202-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a> A big congratulations to Rowan, aka the kid, for graduating from pre-school. He’s been at Run-a-Muck for three and a half years. Seems strange that he’s done - though officially his last day is tomorrow. I’m very proud of the kid.</p>

<p>Here are the <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Rowan/Pre-school-Graduation/30095717_rX5mHW">graduation pictures</a> for your viewing pleasure.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yankee Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/06/yankee-game/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/08/06/yankee-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Sports/Yankees-Game-Day-August-5-2012/24592870_NjzbJg"><img src="http://photos.thecave.com/Sports/Yankees-Game-Day-August-5-2012/i-gpjw7zB/0/Th/IMG0137-Th.jpg" alt="" border="0" class="alignleft" /></a>
Rowan has gone to at least one Yankee game a year at Yankee Stadium since he was born in March 2008. The only year he missed was 2009 when the new stadium opened. And yes, he attended a game - though he slept through most of it - at the old Yankee Stadium.</p>

<p>This year we watched the Yankees win over the Seattle Mariners. Rowan enjoyed the game, but not as much as past years. He thought the game was too long, and he was ready to leave by the seventh inning. But like a real trooper, he stayed and let Melanie and I enjoy the rest of the day.</p>

<p>The only bad part of the day was the return trip home. Bad storms were moving in throughout New York City all the way up to Boston. This caused a number of flights from LGA to Boston to cancel. Lucky for us, Melanie met another passenger who was non-reving and had rented a car. She offer to let us hitch a ride up to Boston, and we of course accepted her offer. We got home later than planned, but thanks to Jane we got home.</p>

<p>More pictures from our game at Yankee Stadium are <a href="http://photos.thecave.com/Sports/Yankees-Game-Day-August-5-2012/24592870_NjzbJg">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sleeping In]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thecave.com/2012/07/20/sleeping-in/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thecave.com/2012/07/20/sleeping-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Rowan has recently been sleeping later into the mornings. This is great because Melanie and I both prefer sleeping in as well. I remember when Rowan first started sleeping through the night. He would wake up at 5:30 in the morning to start his day. I used to say, if only he would sleep until 6 am. And of course he did start sleeping until 6 am over time. When that happened, I starter saying, if only he would sleep until 6:30 am. As he slept later, I continued saying to myself, sleep until 7 am. Then it was 7:30 am. Then 8 am.</p>

<p>He is now consistently sleeping until sometime between 8 and 9 am each morning, and I’m loving it. But as the saying goes, all good things must come to an end. Lucky for me that end doesn’t come for another year when the kid start kindergarten. Until that time, I’m going to enjoy the extra sleep.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>